<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="166"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[WEAVES        1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[2    WEAVES]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[St St. Joseph
                                                   Joseph
                                                 .






                      Our Heavenly Patron








                                                                                          WEAVES        3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Declaration


        Magazine of St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous), Irinjalakuda statement about ownership and
        other particulars about,  “The Sibyl” 2022. Form IV (see rule 8).













                                 Dr. Sr. Asha Therese CHF
                                 Publisher












                              Ms. Geetha Jacob                 Ms. Melvy Xavier
                              Staff Editor                           Student Editor


















                                 Ms. Veena Sany               Ms. Rejo T.J
                                Advertisement Convener      Committee Member













                                                  Jeswin Jose Vithayathil
                                                  Associate Editor(Graphics)


        I, Dr. Sr. Asha Therese, declare that the above particulars are true to the best of my knowledge.
                                                                                               sd/-
                                                                                   Dr. Sr. Asha Therese


           4    WEAVES]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[O  ur M  ott  o
                                                  Our Motto
                                             LIGHT   LIFE   LOVE


                                                  Our Vision
                                                  O  ur V ision
                       WOMEN EMPOWERED AND LIBERATED THROUGH
                             KNOWLEDGE FOR A BRAVE NEW WORLD
                                            OF IDEAL FAMILIES.


                                                          ission
                                                    ur M
                                                 O
                                                 Our Mission
                    CREATING AN EDUCATIONAL ENVIRONMENT FOR THE
        TOTAL  DEVELOPMENT  OF  YOUNG  WOMEN  IN  THIS  GLOBALIZED
        E-WORLD THROUGH VALUE BASED HOLISTIC INSTRUCTION ACROSS A
                                 WIDE RANGE OF DISCIPLINES AND
                            MAINSTREAMING A GENDER PERSPECTIVE






                                                                                          WEAVES        5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[SAINT
                                 SAINT


                       MARIAM THRESIA
                                   MARIAM THRESIA


                                                              Patroness of Families
                                                              Patroness of Families
                                  Foundress, Holy Family Congregation
                                  Foundress, Holy Family Congregation





           6    WEAVES]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[V
                                    enerable
                            Venerable

                      Fr. JOSEPH
                                 Fr    . JOSEPH


                                           VITHA                Y   A    THIL
                       VITHAYATHIL



                                                Co-Founder
                                                Co-Founder
                                                Holy Family Congregation
                                                Holy Family Congregation

                                                                                          WEAVES        7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Patron
                                                       Mar Pauly Kannookadan




                                                       Bishop
                                                       Diocese of Irinjalakuda


































                                 Fr. Nevin Attokaran

                                     College Chaplain and

                                                   Chancellor
                                  Diocese of  Irinjalakuda
















           8    WEAVES]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[Rev. Sr. Dr. Annie Kuriakose CHF












                                     Superior General
                       Holy Family Congregation
























                                                      Rev.Sr. Elsy Kokkat CHF



                                                      Provincial Superior
                                                      CHF Pavanatma Province






                                                      Manager
                                                      St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous)
                                                      Irinjalakuda












                                                                                          WEAVES        9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Your Life was a Blessing!
                                           Your Memory a Treasure!
































                                          Rev. Sr. Mary Loretta CHF
                                               Former Principal




                                           The Sparkle You Spread

                                                  Around is to
                                              Stay Here Forever!

































                                                  Mr. K.P John




           10   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Loved Beyond Words!
                                          Missed Beyond Measure!

































                                              Ms. Baby J Alappatt
                                  Former Head, Department of Zoology






                                           Forever in Our Hearts!




































                                                   Laya David
                                               B.Com (Final Year)


                                                                                          WEAVES       11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Dr. Sr. Asha Therese, Principal from 2020 - 2022
                                 An embodiment of serenity and goodwill.











































                                       Dr. Sr. Elaiza, The New  Principal
                         A visionary leader who skilfully plans for total efficiency.





           12   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[PRINCIPAL’S



                                                                                 MESSAGE






















                                                                                     “The    function    of
                                                                                     education is to teach one
                                                                                    to think intensively and to
                                                                                    think critically. Intelligence
                                                                                   plus  character;  that  is  the
                                                                                  goal of true education”.
                                                                                 -Martin Luther King, Jr.

                                                                              St.  Joseph’s  College  is  proud  to
                                                                            have been able to give our students
                                                                         an outlet to showcase their creative
                                                                       capabilities in the form of the college
                                                                   magazine “ Weaves ”. The magazine is a vessel
                                                               intended for students to inculcate creativity, critical
                                                         and divergent thinking all while trying to impart the values
                                         of life. The excellent work put in by this year’s magazine team, comprising of
                                         both students and staff members, has resulted in an exemplary outcome. The
                                         end result has gone above and beyond its expectations and I am confident it
                                         is a true reflection of the capabilities of our students while being a great read
                                         at the same time.
                                         The past few years laid a great challenge for all educational institutions when
                                         they had to face the new normal of a post covid world. But even through such
                                         uncertainties, St. Joseph’s stood strong. We were able to bravely navigate
                                         through these  challenging  times without  compromising on the  quality of
                                         education provided to our students. While we celebrate this achievement, we
                                         also intended to move ahead with the spirit that, there is always more that
                                         can be done, more that can be achieved and more that can be accomplished.
                                         We march ahead with the mission to spread “Light, Life and Love” to all corners
                                         of the world through our students. We strive to become the top choice of any
                                         student who wishes to pursue collegiate education and in turn mould our
                                         students to become strong pillars of their respective communities and active
                                         contributors to the economic, social and cultural welfare of the society and
                                         the country at large.
                                         May God help us in this effort. I wish all the students a grand success in their
                                         career and prosperity in their future life.









                                                                                          WEAVES       13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[EDITORIAL BOARD


























                                 Hajra P. Y                             Nasrin N. S
                          Indulge in the simple pleasures of      I\nhnt\mfw Icp¯pff s\bv¯nÃ.
                          life, for the heart may not realize how   tNÀ¯p  \nÀ¯ent\mfw  lrZyamb
                          deeply it is stuck in the rat race. It starts   kzÀ¤hpanÃ. Häs¸Sensâ iq\yXbpw
                          with dullness, every day feeling heavy,   CÃmbvabpsS  Ibv]pw  A\p`hn¨h-
                          almost like it has been lived before.   sc¡qSn, kvt\l¯nsâ CgIfmÂ Â
                          Then slowly eating out the light of the   X¶ntebv¡Sp¸n¡p¶  hnimeXbpsS
                          body.                                   t]cmWv  a\pjyXzw.  AsX, Fsâbpw
                          Romanticize life to suck out all the    \n§fpsSbpw PohnX¯nsâ [À½w s\
                          marrow that drains the heart.           bv¯p Xs¶bmWv; AIe§sf tXm
                                                                  ¸n¡p¶ s\bv¯v!
                                   WEAVES                                  WEAVES

















               Lakshmi O. S                    Nazeen Fathima                     Anakha Kannan
                                                                               ” The greater the difficulty. The more
                                              Somewhere around the paths of    glory in surmounting it. Skillful pilots
          CXv Hcp ]pXnb bm{XbmWv. tXm         love, stories are stuck, smudged,   gain their reputation from stroke and
          ÂhnIsf tXmÂ]n¨v ..... PohnXs¯       and stained. Despite the fact that   tempest.” - Epictetus
          tNÀ¯p]nSn¨v....  ]p©ncnsb Iq«p      the mundane existence of life    We would never learn anything if we
          ]nSn¨v...... apdnªp t]mb bm{XIÄ     provides you with unfinished and   were  never  pushed.  Doing  difficult
          XpScmw. hcq HmÀ½IÄ ]Xnbm³           undiscussed meters, we give you   things can make us want to give up, but
          Zqc§Ä k©cn¡mw.                      the embracement of solid life-   doing things can also make achieving
                                                                               our objectives feel better because we
                                                                               know we worked hard to get there.

                   WEAVES                             WEAVES                             WEAVES










           14   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[EDITOR’S  NOTE





           Welcome to The Sibyl 2022 edition, WEAVES. I am beyond thrilled and ecstatic to present to you this edition,
           on which we have been meticulously working for the past few months. In fact, by this point, I would have run a
           marathon around our campus trying to weave the wefts between the warps. A rather intriguing endeavour, to
           weave the fragments, silver splinters and the magic of life! Webs, patterns, and mazes of emotions, moments!
           As the year 2022 rolled around, everything appeared to be much better and brighter. In the COVID-19 battle,
           we, Josephites did not fail to put up a valiant fight and we have returned much more formidable than before.
           Every year, our college stands out on its own and is far from being just another academic year. In addition to
           the exceptional performance and the desire to explore every opportunity, our students always keep in mind to
           capture the essence of life, share their positive traits with others, and grow into strong, independent women
           who can run their own worlds and build their own empires. And perhaps most importantly, each student
           follows a unique individual path to reach their own points of success. It would take a thousand more pages
           for each of her tales and to express all of this in our magazine, not to mention our remarkable faculty and
           their accomplishments, and our non-teaching staff who have been taking care of our college and its environs
           like their own home. However, our team has made every effort to weave many of these pleasant memories,
           thoughts, and lovely souls into our magazine entitled WEAVES. Like a mother affectionately braiding her
           child’s hair, a spider scrupulously spinning its web or a weaver bird tenderly building its nest, the very core
           of our existence here has been woven into The Sibyl 2022. Sibyl is a mythical prophetess who is thought to
           foretell the future. I hope every woman of St. Joseph’s college becomes the future itself and each step she
           takes towards it be chronicled in the upcoming issues.                        MELVY XAVIER
                                                                                         STUDENT EDITOR



                                                                                          WEAVES       15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Million years yore she began
                                                   To weave the colours of life



                                                   Silhouettes and shapes she wove
                                                   Brooding lone in a grove


                                                   Silver and grey and gold

                                                   Now gleamed then vanished


                                                   Never she gave up the chase
                                                   To trap the tricky ones in her case



                                                   Waved the glassy magic wand
                                                   Warped the single fuzzy strand



                                                   Shapes... Shades...
                                                   Steeps... Slopes...


                                                   Smiles... Sighs...

                                                   Gains... Pains..


                                                   Colours... Hopes...
                                                   Visions... Dreams...



                                                   Resistance... Resilience...


                                                   Towards times unborn...



                                                   WEAVES

















           16   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[W










                                                                                    E










                                                                                    A











                                                                                    V










                                                                                    E










                                                                                    S





















                                                                                          WEAVES       17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[CONTENTS















                        Annual Report        20                           Different Generations,
                                                              66          Different Thoughts




                           A Sage Saga       48
                                                              67          Soul  Knot





                        Hangout Spots        50               68          A´yao bm{X





            Graceful Metamorphosis           53               69          Cage






                      To the Gulmohar        62               70          N«¡qSpIÄ¡v Hcp AdpXn





                             Exhaustion      63               71          Ammama


                                                              72

                             Euthanasia      64                           आओ धरती को बचाएं



                                            65                73
              Iq«nse InfnbpsS hyY



                                                              74          Nn{Xw hnNn{Xw





















           18   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[75
                    {]WbaÀ½c§Ä
                                                             85          {`m´³




                     Queer Book Recs        76
                                                             86          ^mÌv ^pUv



                                            78
                                        माँ                  87          IS¸mSv




                                            79               112
                                     िकसान                               PohtemIs¯ alm_en



 N«¡qSpIÄ¡v Hcp AdpXn                                        114         Team Josephites
                      Pzen¡p¶ HmÀ½          80                           The Invinvcibles




                    \ndª a\Ênsâ             80              121          SJC Playlist
                          \nizmkw……




                          To Not be Ok      82             163           HmÀ½IfpsS eb\w






                       The Birth of Art     83




                   The Wicked House         84
                       Lost the  Home







                                                           Warps and Wefts





                                                                                          WEAVES       19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Annual Report 2021 - 22











        Distinguished dignitaries on the dais, His Excellency, Mar   of Zoology. Dr. Lisamma John, Associate Professor and
        Pauly Kannookadan, Bishop, Diocese of Irinjalakuda,   Head, Department of Hindi – a doyen of perseverance,
        Dr. M. Nasser, Pro-Vice Chancellor, University of   resourcefulness and meekness has demonstrated an
        Calicut,  Rev.  Mother.  Dr.  Annie  Kuriakose,  Superior   exemplary strength throughout her eventful career.
        General, Congregation of the Holy Family, Rev. Sr. Elsy   Ms. Joicy C. V, Office Attendant has blended generosity,
        Kokkatt, Manager and Provincial Superior (Pavanatma   stoicism and punctuality in her official life thus endearing
        Province, Irinjalakuda), Dr. Sr. Asha Therese, Principal,   herself intricately to the Josephite community. In a very
        St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous) Irinjalakuda, Smt.   special way, let me salute your invaluable services to the
        Sonia Giri, Municipal Chairperson, Irinjalakuda, Smt.   college.
        Feny Abin Vellanikkaran (Ward Councillor), Sri. Davis   Let me enlist this year’s activities of the Departments
        Ukken (President, PTWA), Dr. Lisamma John, Associate   and Committees briefly.
        Professor and Head, Department of Hindi, Mrs. Joycy
        C.V.,  (office  attendant),  Ms.  Anjaleena  Biju,  College   MILESTONES AT A GLANCE
        Union Chairperson, other dignitaries off the dais, invited
        guests,  former  principals,  retired  faculty  and  staff,   1) St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous) Irinjalakuda has
        members of the press and media, dear colleagues and   been recognized in the band ‘Performer’ as per ATAL
        my dear students,                                  Rankings.
        Warm greetings of 58th College Day!                2) The College has been elevated to the band of 100-
        As  we  sail  through  the  final  months  of  another   150 in NIRF Rankings.
        academic year, we realize that the recurring waves of   3) India Today National Survey identified St. Joseph’s
        the pandemic have given us a chance for reflection and   College as the 72nd Best College to offer B.Sc Courses.
        improvement. Pope Francis has exhorted the world to   4) Aneesha M, Anjali S and Seeya Metilda Baiju
        be faithful in crisis and live with contentment from day   of II BA English won the Gold, Silver and Bronze
        to day, without asking God what he really wants from   Medals respectively at the Asian Junior Power lifting
        us. He has hailed the noble profession of health workers   Championship held at Turkey. Aneesha M was crowned
        and has asked humanity to carry forward the mission   the Best Lifter, thus becoming the First Indian Player to
        of health care as we touch and heal the flesh of Christ   win the title.
        in our brethren. As the world grapples with the new   5) 60 National and International Webinars were
        variants  of  the  coronavirus  and  changing  protocols  of   conducted by various Departments and Committees.
        public health, education which is one of the anchors of   6) Ms. Linet Sebastian, Assistant Professor, Department
        civilization should derive fortitude from human values.  of English was awarded Ph.D.
        On the occasion of our 58th College Day, let me pay   7) Ms. Litty Chacko secured a Project Grant of Rs. 15
        grateful homage to   Rev. Sr. Mary Loretta CHF, Former   Lakhs for Manuscript Management and Conservation.
        Principal and Manager of St. Joseph’s College, nurturer   8) The Alumane Association sponsored 8 solar lights in
        of this institution in its nascent stages; Mr. K. P. John, the   the campus.
        pioneer who helmed the twenty-member committee of   9) The first virtual gathering of the Alumane was
        great visionaries who diligently laid the foundations of   conducted by Gulf Chapter, International Chapter and
        St. Joseph’s College and Ms. Baby J Alappatt, our retired   UAE Chapter in January.
        faculty and former head of the Department of Zoology   10)  A Synthetic track is sponsored by Federal Bank and
        who was a beacon of inspiration in the lives of hundreds   an Open Gym, soon to be launched.
        of students who imbibed knowledge from her guidance.  11)  The College has set up a state-of-the-art media lab
        The College community bids a fond adieu to three gems   with 50 computers.
        of the faculty and staff who embrace their retirement   12)  Outcome-based education implemented for Post
        this year. Our beloved Principal, Dr. Sr. Anis K. V, an   Graduate students.
        epitome  of  dedication,  benevolence  and  courage  has   13)  Dr. Binu T. V won the award for Best Programme
        led the institution over the last couple of years at the   Officer in the Calicut University; St. Joseph’s  College
        culmination of her elaborate service at the Department   was selected as Best NSS Unit.


           20   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[14)  Dr. Naijil George and Dr. Gigi Poulose secured   world book Lovers Day on 9th August 2021. Dr Sigma
        guideships.                                        G R, poet and Head, Dept. of English, VTMNSS College,
        15)  College Magazine ‘Niramaya’ released by       Dhanuvachapuram was the resource person. Three
        Honourable Minister of Higher Education, Dr. R. Bindu.  faculty projects and two student projects funded by the
        16)  Seed Money has been given by the management to   management were awarded this year to the department
        16 faculty and 58 students to motivate their research   of English. GLOWE-English for Empowerment is an
        aptitude.                                          innovative management-funded student initiative
        17)  4 faculty got research projects of Rs. 2 Lakhs,   of the department  that aims at empowering women
        sponsored by KSE and KLF, Irinjalakuda.            through English language. The principal investigator
        18)  782 students of the college won scholarships   of the project is Ms Divya Jobi, II M A student of the
        funded by State and Central Government worth   Rs.25   department. GLOWE stands for a Group of Linguistically
        Lakhs.                                             live and practically Oriented Women of right reasoning.
        19)  A new academic block was completed by utilizing   The major project initiatives are Language  Guide-to
        RUSA fund.                                         impart  language  guidance,  E4-a  specialized  training
                                                           to improve the four basic language skills, Ted Speak to
        DEPARTMENTS                                        provide training in public speaking skills, Me Magazine-
                                                           An E-Magazine for publishing students’ original works
                                                           and Web pals- a website to bring out the creative
        I. FACULTY OF ARTS                                 ideas of students. The official launch of the project was
                                                           held on 12th August 2021 on the virtual platform. Dr.
                                                           Radha  Muraleedharan,  former  Head,  Dept.  of  English,
        ENGLISH (AIDED)
                                                           launched the project. Dr. Sr. Asha, Principal, St Joseph’s
                                                           College, IJK delivered the benedictory address and Mr.
        The Post Graduate and Research Department of English   Ram C Menon, Director, Public Relations Council of
        celebrated  the Ruby  Jubilee  Year  of  its  inception.   India and Young Communicators’ Club Kerala Chapter
        To  celebrate  the  rich  legacy  of  four  decades,  the   felicitated.  Third  UG Botany and  Second  UG  English
        department  launched  a  year-long  celebration  under   students were given language training as part of this
        the title ‘Jubile De Rubis’. As part of observing World   project. Supervivientes, the II-year UG students’
        Environment Day, the Department of English hosted an   funded project focused on empowering women through
        online Intercollegiate Poetry Recitation competition on   entrepreneurship. There are mainly four activities
        the theme ‘Restituto Ecosystem’. observed the Reading   under  this  project-creating  brochures  and  certificates
        Week was observed in collaboration with the central   for online events, selling gooseberry juice, production of
        library of the college from 19th June 2021 to 24th June   cakes and cookies, and sales of arts and craft products.
        2021  by  conducting  ‘Reading  Reels’.  The  department    Legare- A Cultural Heritage Digitization Initiative is
        hosted two intercollegiate competitions, an online quiz   an  academic  extension  project  of  the  Research  and
        and an online book review competition. The second year   Post Graduate Department of English. The principal
        UG students organized  various online programmes as   investigators of the project are Ms. Linet Sebastian
        part of celebrating National Reading Day on June 19   and Ms Sameena Thomas, Assistant Professors of
        in honour of P N Panicker, the father of the Library and   the department of English. It aims at the research and
        Literacy  Movement  in  Kerala.  The  first  lecture  of  the   digital documentation of the local cultural inheritances
        Invited Lecture series planned as part of Jubile De Rubis   of  Irinjalakuda  to  help  in  the  preservation  of  cultural
        was held on 4th August on the topic ‘The Challenges of   memory, diversity and social integration of the region.
        Translating Literature’. The resource person of the day   The official launch of the project was held on 13th August
        was Dr. Vimla Menon, Retired faculty, department of   2021. The programme was inaugurated by the Principal
        English, St. Joseph’s College, Irinjalakuda. . - Tete – A   of the college, Dr. Sr. Asha. The chief guest and keynote
        _Tete series is an initiative under the Jubile De Rubis   speaker of the day was Dr. Sreevidhya V., Assistant
        programme  which  aims  to  bring  people  representing   Professor in History, Government College, Malappuram.
        different walks of life to have a direct interaction with   She spoke on the historical and cultural significance of
        the students. ‘Inspirit the She in You’, the first event in   Irinjalakuda. “Harnessing Online English Education
        this series, held on 5th August in online platform gave   to promote Social Skills and Inculcate Core Values of
        an opportunity for the students to interact with Smt.   Nationalism and Environmental Conservation among
        Echmukutty, writer  and activist. World Book Lovers   College Students” is a management funded faculty
        Day 2021 was observed with an array of competitions   project aimed at value addition through rethinking and
        and events to encourage the reading good literature.   re-inventing curriculum content at the undergraduate
        Two   online  intercollegiate  competitions,  Book  level. Ms.  Anju Susan George  and Ms. Anju  Antony,
        Mark Making on 12th August and Book Speak- An      Assistant Professors of the department of English are
        Intercollegiate Online Talkathon on 14th August, were   the  principal  investigators.  The  third  faculty  project
        organized. Invited Lecture Series-II- ‘The Rhapsodies of   titled “Impact of blended Learning in English Language
        Reading’- An invited lecture was organized to motivate   Acquisition:  A  Study  among  the  undergraduate
        and guide students to the art of reading as part of the
                                                           Students  of  Selected  Colleges  in  Thrissur  District”

                                                                                          WEAVES       21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[attempts to examine the impact of blended learning in   ‘Environment Day’ on June 5th 2021. A talk on ‘Kitchen
        English  language  acquisition  of  first-generation  higher   Gardening’ was arranged for the students and their
        education learners of online education. Ms. Deepa Roy,   mothers. Ms. Mini Shaji, Puthenpurackal, who has 20
        Assistant Professor of the department of English is the   years of experience in kitchen gardening was the resource
        principal investigator.                            person. A photography competition was arranged for
        Libertas 2021- The department organized three      the students. A virtual mode ‘Reading Day’ celebration
        intercollegiate  online  competitions-Epistles  of  was conducted by the department on 19th June 2021.
        Freedom, Freedom Slogan and Voices of Freedom- in   Students of the department celebrated International
        connection with 75th Independence Day Celebrations.   Yoga Day on 21 June 2021 by attending online session.
        Two endowment lectures  were organized this year   Departments of Economics of Sacred Heart College
        under  Jubile  De  Rubis.  The  first  lecture  of  the  series,   Chalakudy and St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous)
        ‘An Introduction to Psychoanalysis’ was held on   26th   Irinjalakuda jointly organized a Two-day International
        & 27th of October. Dr Kanakavinayakam G, Faculty of   Conference (Online) on “ECONOMICS OF HAPPINESS
        Law, SRM IST Chennai was the resource person. Second   AND WELFARE” on the 18th & 19th of June 2021. The
        lecture of the series, ‘An Introduction to Structuralism   resource persons were Dr. T.K. Mishra, Vice Principal
        with Special Reference to Roland Barthes: “Structuralist   & Associate Professor in Commerce of Ramanujan
        Activity”, was held on 26th November 2021. Dr C J   College, New Delhi, Dr. Subhashini Muthukrishnan,
        Davees, Professor (Retd), St Thomas College, Thrissur   Retired Professor of Economics, Bangalore, Vangie
        was the resource person. The annual intercollegiate quiz   M. Bogaty,  Business Consultant, USA, Dr. Jai Kishan
        competition, ‘Sr. Mary Franco Memorial Intercollegiate   Prasher of Zakir Hussain College (E), New Delhi and
        Literary Quiz- Sagesse Lit 2021’ conducted in honour   Dada Gunamuktananda International Professional
        of the former principal and head of the department of   in  Meditation,  Yoga,  Philosophy  and  Natural  Health-
        English, Rev Sr Mary Franco was held on 17th December   Sciences, Chile. The proceedings of the Conference
        2021. The quiz was inaugurated by the Vice Principal,   were  published  with  ISBN  number.  Yet  another
        Rev. Sr. Blessy, and Mr. Viswas Viswam, Assistant   Webinar on “Sailing Ahead with Economics: Career
        Professor in English, Govt. College, Madappally was   and Higher Education Opportunities for Economics
        the  quiz  master.  Certificate  Course  on  soft  Skills  for   Graduates” on 6th August 2021 was organized
        Successful  Career  and  Research  Methodology:  The   under the same collaboration. This was conducted
        department  offered  a  45  hours  certificate  course  on   through Zoom  meet. Dr. Chacko Jose P, Principal,  St.
        Soft Skills along with six other associating colleges in   Aloysius College, Elthuruth was the resource person.
        collaboration with Guru Angad Dev Teaching Learning   In connection with International Population Day,
        Centre, Pandit Madan Mohan Malviya National Mission   the Department of Economics conducted an online
        on Teachers and Teaching and the Ministry of Education,   awareness quiz on 11th July 2021. An intercollegiate
        Government of India from 18th October 2021 to 28th   online speech competition on the topic ‘Economics
        February 2022. The course was offered to the UG, PG   Reforms  in  India  after  Independence’  was  conducted
        students, Research Scholars and others interested. The   in connection with 75th Independence Day. Online
        course aimed at enabling students to communicate   Onam Celebration ‘Avaniyarangu’ was on 17 August
        with clarity and impact by improving their negotiation   2021.  Students  celebrated  ‘Teachers  Day’  and  Gandhi
        and presentation skills, problem solving skills as well as   Jayanti by creating a video in honor of Gandhiji with his
        to enhance their interview skills, teamwork, technical   quotes. An intercollegiate poster-making competition,
        skills and entrepreneurial skills.  Dr. Asha Thomas, Head,   ‘International Day for the Eradication of Poverty’, was
        Department of English was the course convenor and Dr.   organized by the department. In association with the
        Sujitha V S, Assistant Professor of the department was   Darsana Family Counselling Centre, the department
        the  course  coordinator.  A  30  hours  certificate  course   conducted an awareness class on ‘Domestic Violence
        on  Research  methodology  was  also  conducted  by  the   Act, 2015’ on 29th October 2021. Adv. Lina Joseph was
        department for the final year UG and PG students of the   the resource person. 88th birthday of Amartya Sen on
        department.  Dr Asha Thomas, Head of the Department   3 November 2021 was commemorated. Ms. Bavitha
        of English was the course Co-ordinator. National   M, II MA Economics student presented a paper on the
        Symposium on travel writing and theory titled “El Viaje:   contributions of Amartya Sen in the field of Economics.
        Discourses on Travel Writing and Theory” was conducted   Diwali  was  celebrated  on  5th  November  2021by
        on 28-01-2022. The webinar was inaugurated by Dr.   arranging Rangoli  competition. A Fresher’s Party was
        Sr Asha Therese, Principal, St Joseph’s College, IJK. Dr   organized on 16th November 2021, by II MA students.
        Dhishna Pannikot, Associate Professor, NIT, Karnataka   In connection with the international day for Elimination
        and V S. Sanoj, Journalist and Co-ordinating Producer,   of Violence against Women, a one-day Webinar was
        Asianet News Online were the resource persons.     organized on ‘Atrocities against Women and Laws to
                                                           Combat’ by Mary Jyothi Joseph, Assistant Professor,
        ECONOMICS                                          Government Law College Thrissur on November 25
                                                           2021 at 10.30 am.
        Department  of  Economics  commenced  its  activities   National Constitution Day was observed by the
        for  the  academic  year  2021-2022  by  celebrating   Department on 26th November, 2021. The pledge taking

           22   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[ceremony was conducted during the first hour of the day.   e-Quiz  Competition  ‘Hindi  Hai Hum’ on  10th  January
        A Webinar on ‘Human Rights and Law’, was conducted in   2022 which recorded 133 responses. In connection
        connection with Human Rights Day on 11th December   with the World Hindi Day celebration, the Department
        at 6.30 PM. Ms. Anjana Kannath, Advocate, High Court   of Hindi conducted a National Level Webinar on
        of Kerala was the resource person. In association   ‘Implementation of Rajbhasha in Banking Sector’ on
        with National Voters Day, Department conducted an   19th January 2022. Dr. Lisamma John published a Book
        elocution competition on the topic ‘Electoral Literacy   ‘Mamta Kaliya Ki Kahaniyon me Moolya Parivartan’,
        for Stronger Democracy’. ‘National Girl Child Day’ was   Jawahar Pustakalay, sadar bazar, Mathura-281001(UP).
        observed by creating a video that includes successful   Two new projects, one student project titled Ek Saath
        women  in  various  fields.  In  association  with  Republic   and Pandemics  in  Hindi Literature, a Faculty Project
        Day, ‘Best out of waste’ competition was conducted.   were initiated. The faculty members Dr. Lisamma John
        UGC NET/JRF Examination Orientation for the        and Ms. Nina M. M engaged in Social and Spiritual
        Postgraduate students of the academic year 2021-   activities of Chavara Family Forum, Santhi sadan, Mercy
        2022 was successfully completed.  Classes were taken   Trust Diocese of Irinjalakuda, Nammude Irinjalakuda
        by our Alumnae Mrs. Praseetha V. P (UG 2009-2012   etc. Dr. Lisamma John and Ms. Nina M.M, the Faculty of
        Batch), Ph.D. Scholar University of Calicut, M. D College   Hindi Department created their own Youtube channels
        Pazhanji and Mrs. Ninu Jacob (UG & PG 2014-2019    to share their passion for cooking, beauty and fashions.
        Batch) M.Ed student, Government college Thrissur.  The channels are ‘Rasoyee by lisa’ and ‘Nina Mulangil’s
                                                           world’ respectively and uploaded 300 videos within 2
        HINDI                                              years.

        Ms. Ashwati Biju, II B.Sc Botany was elected as the  HISTORY
        Association Secretary. On 5th June 2021 the department
        organized “Environment Day Celebrations’. All Students   Activities for the academic year 2021-22 of
        from various department planted saplings at their homes.   History Department began with the Environmental
        An Invited Talk on ‘Youth and Covid -19 Challenges Fear   day celebration on 5th June 2021. A webinar on
        and Facts’ was conducted on 1st July 2021, in connection   ‘Environment and History’ was conducted through the
        with National Doctor’s Day. The resource person was   google platform.  Mr. Rajan P.P, Assistant Professor,
        Dr. Arun Babu N.B., MBBS, MD, Assistant Professor at   Dept of History, Brennan College, Thalassery, was the
        Govt.  Medical  College,  Manjeri.  ‘Premchand  Jayanti   resource person. In connection with the World refugee
        Samaroh’ was celebrated from 31st July 2021 to 11   day,  an  inter-collegiate  essay  writing  competition  on
        August 2021 in connection with  Premchand Jayanthi.   ‘Refugees and future’ was conducted on 14/06/2021.
        Dr. Aruna Hiremath, Assistant  Professor and Head,   In connection with the World Blood Donor Day, the
        Department of Hindi, LVD College, Raichur, Karnataka,   department conducted Digital Logo competition on
        delivered the keynote address. National Level Story   14/06/2021. National Reading Day was celebrated
        Review Competition on the topic of ‘Premchand Ki   by conducting reading competition for students on
        Kafan Kahani’ was also held. Anu Asthana, M.A Hindi,   19/06/2021. The department celebrated International
        Indore Christian College, won the Frist Position, Surya   Yoga Day on  21/06/2021.  A Webinar  on ‘The Nature
        N.S and Gayathri B.S of Malabar Christian College,   of Pre British-India as Discovered by The Gandhian
        won the Second and third position respectively. As part   Historian Dharampal and Its Relevance for Us Today’
        of ‘Zehanat 2021’, Department conducted a National   was conducted on 30/06/2021 collaborating with
        Level e-Quiz with a record of 1252 responses. In   Probhodha  Trust.  Dr.  C.N.  Krishnan,  Professor  of
        connection with Hindi Day Celebration, the Department   Eminence and founder director-AU-KBC Research
        conducted  an Invited  Talk on ‘A Discourse  on Hindi   Centre Anna University, Chennai was the resource
        in the Perspective of South India’ on 14th September   person. The Hiroshima & Nagasaki day was observed by
        2021. Dr. K. M Jayakrishnan, Retired Associate     the department. The department conducted digital logo
        Professor, Christ College (Autonomous), Irinjalakuda,   competition on the topic World Peace on 06/08/2021.
        inaugurated and delivered a talk on this topic. ‘Saath’ in   To commemorate the Quit India day, the department
        National Level Poster Making Competition connection   conducted a Quiz competition on 09/08/2021. A
        with International Day for Older Person, students   National Webinar on ‘Mahatma Gandhi in contemporary
        conducted a programme on 1st October 2021. They    time’ was conducted on 15/08/2021 and 16/08/2021
        made a video, and talked about aging and caring of   collaborating with the Probhodha Trust.  Prof. Prabhat
        the old. The department organized ‘AAVAAZ 2021’ in   Patnaik, Renowned Economist & Political commentator
        connection with International Human Rights Day on   and the former professor at CESP JNU Delhi was the
        10th December 2021. Theme of this competition was   resource  person.  Indian  flag  making  competition  was
        Human Rights. Many Students from various College   arranged  to  mark  the  Independence  Day  celebrations
        actively participated in this competition. First Year Hindi   on 15/08/2021.
        students released the E-Manuscript named ‘Panah’ on   A National Webinar on ‘Approaches to History’ was
        22 December 2021.  In connection with the World Hindi   conducted on 16/09/2021. Dr. Anas Edoli, Assistant
        celebration, Department conducted a National Level   Professor, Dept of History, NAM college, Kallikkandy

                                                                                          WEAVES       23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[was the resource person. A National Webinar on ‘Gandhi   Basheer Remembrance Day was held on 7th July Monday
        & Women Liberation’ was conducted on 20/09/2021    at 11 am in collaboration with the Thudi Malayalavedhi.
        collaborating  with the  Probhodha Trust. Prof.  D. V. R.   Former MP and MLA Prof. Savithri Lakshmanan was
        Sai Gopal, Vice Chancellor, Cluster University, Kurnool,   the  chief  guest.  B.Voc  Malayalam  students  performed
        Andhra Pradesh, was the resource person. A National   a  video  presentation  on the  characters  of Basheer.
        Webinar on ‘Simplicity & Contemporary Context’     Department  of Malayalam organised a media seminar
        was conducted on 02/10/2021 in collaboration with   on 18th   July 2021. Reputed journalist Mr. Abhilash
        the Probhodha Trust. Prof. Rajendra Khimani, Vice-   Mohanan was the resource person. He spoke on ‘Vaartha
        Chancellor, Gujarat Vidyapith, Ahmedabad was the   Avatharanaththinte Charithravum Varththamanavum’.
        resource person. Kerala Piravi was celebrated on   Onam Celebration was held on 20th August 2021
        01/11/2021. A National Webinar on ‘Muhammed        in collaboration with the Tudi Malayalam Vedi. The
        Abdul Rahiman’ was conducted on 20/11/2021  in     students performed various art shows and organized an
        collaboration with the Probhodha Trust, Prof. M.N.   online ‘Pookalam’ competition. The webinar series on
        Karassery, writer and social thinker was the resource   ‘Folklore Study’ was jointly organized in association with
        person. Constitution day was observed on 26/11/2021   Kerala Folklore academy from 27th to 30th September
        and conducted speech competitions as part of the   2021. Kerala folklore Academy Secretary Mr. Keechery
        celebration. The Human Rights Day was celebrated on   Raghavan  inaugurated  the  event.  Dr. Pathmanabhan
        10/12/2021 and the department conducted placard    Kavumbayi presented webinar reports of the folklore
        making competition. A National Webinar on ‘Mahatma   academy.  Dr.  M.  G  Sasibhooshan,  Former  Director  of
        Gandhi & Vaikom Muhammed Basheer’ was conducted    Kerala  State  Literacy  Mission  Authority  presented  a
        on  18/12/2021  in  collaboration  with  the  Probhodha   paper entitled “Darusilpakalayile Nattuvazhakkangal”.
        Trust. Prof. K.P. Sankaran, Associate Professor (Rtd), St.   The third session of the folklore seminar was conducted
        Stephens College, Delhi was the resource person.   on 28th October 2021. Prof. George Menacherry, Chief
                                                           Editor, St. Thomas Christian Encyclopaedia of India,
        JOURNALISM AND                                     presented a paper entitled “Aanasukumarakalakalil.”
        MASS COMMUNICATION                                 The fourth session of the folklore seminar was
                                                           conducted on 29th October 2021. Mr. Kanippayyoor
                                                           Krishnan Namboothirippad, Vasthusasthrakulapathi,
        Journalism and Mass Communication students
        completed their internship in various media organizations   Vasthusasthravidyagurukulam,  Aranmula,  Kerala
        during the months of April and May 2021. The internship   Government, presented a paper entitled “Keraleeya
        was an opportunity for the students to gain first-hand   Vasthushilppakalayile  Nattuvazhakkangal”.  The  fifth
        knowledge on the media industry and also about the   session of the folklore seminar was conducted on
        challenges it poses. To celebrate the National Reading   30th October 2021.. Dr. Myna Umaiban, Assistant
        Day, a ‘Book Walk’ through Club House Discussion was   Professor, Department of Malayalam, MES College,
        organized on 19th June 2021. A film screening as well   Mambad, presented a paper entitled “Vishavaidyathile
        as film analysis on all genres of movies was conducted   Nattuvazhakkangal”.  Malayalam  Day  Debate  on
        in every week. In connection with the Social Media Day,   ‘Sthreedana Kkayaril Thoongiaadunna Penjeevithangal’
        the department organized an invited talk on ‘Social   was  organized  on  1st  November  2021  in  connection
        Media: The Future & Career’ on 30th June 2021. A ten-  with the Kerala Piravi celebrations. Kerala Piravi, the
        day Online Journ Workshop Series ‘ESFORZARSE 2021’   65th Birth Anniversary of Kerala was celebrated by the
        was conducted from 12th November 2021 to 25th      department on 01/11/2021 at 11 am.
        November 2021. It equipped the students with insights   ANGANA, Dr. R. Bindhu, Honourable Minister of Higher
        to be an expert in media approaches with the help of   Education and Social Justice, Thrissur, inaugurated
        experienced hands. The department of Journalism    the Vaidyaratnam Pharmacy’s women empowerment
        and Mass Communication broadcasts a multimedia     project ‘ANGANA’ at Thrissur district level, on
        news roundup named ‘SJC Chronicle’ every month on   20/12/2021 at 1 p.m. at St. Joseph’s College Auditorium.
        YouTube  through  the  official  channel  of  the  college.   Jyothish. S. Jayanthan welcomed the audience. Dr. Sr.
        This endeavor empowers the students to nurture their   Asha  Therese,  Principal  of the  college  presided  over
        basic journalistic skills. In connection with the National   the function. Mr. E. T. Neelakandan Moosath delivered
        Youth  Day,  the Department  of  Journalism  and  Mass   the keynote address. Municipal Chairperson Mrs. Sonia
        Communication organized ‘VOX POP 2K22 – Collection   Giri conveyed the greetings. Dr. Jency K. A., Assistant
        of Opinions’ on 13th January 2022.                 Professor, thanked Vaidyaratnam for the membership
                                                           project. Vaidyaratnam Senior Physician Dr. Radhika
                                                           Satheeshan  led  a  session  on  the  general  health  of
        MALAYALAM
                                                           women. 50 students were also given free consultation
                                                           in connection with launch of the project. Dr. R. Bindhu,
        As part of the reading day celebration, Department of   Minister of Higher Education and Social Justice released
        Malayalam conducted a talk on  “Oru Vayanakkarante   the book ‘Kavithayum Kalanubhoothiyum’ written by
        Aathmagathangal” by Mr. Rajendran Edathumkara,     Dr. K. A. Jency on 20/12/2021.The Preface of the book
        a prominent Malayalam novelist on 18th June 2021.
                                                           was written by Dr. Thomas Scariya. World Handwritten

           24   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[day celebration was conducted on 23rd January 2022.   Zone Inter University Championship held at SRM
                                                           University,  Chennai.  College  Volleyball  team  has  won
                                                           the Thrissur District Olympic Games 2022 Basketball
        PHYSICAL EDUCATION                                 competition held on 14-15 January 2022. Aleena Biju, II
                                                           B.Com represented Kerala team for the Junior national
        The  monumental  achievements  and  novel  initiatives   Voleyball championship held at West Bengal on 25-30
        elevated the department to greater heights. Dr. Stalin   December 2021. She was the captain of Kerala team.
        Raphel,  Head,  Dept.  of  Physical  Education  obtained   College Football  team won the Calicut University
        the license of Sports Psychology Consultancy from   Inter Zone Championship held at Center for Physical
        International Society of Sports Psychology (ISSP).  Dr.   Education, Calicut University on 12 to 14 December
        Stalin Raphel was elected as Honorary Secretary of   2021.  Our Seven players, Nidhiya Sreedharan, I MCJ,
        Thrissur District Olympic Association. Aneesha M of II   Vinitha Vijayan, I MCJ, Manju Baby, I MCJ, Reshma C,
        BA English won Gold Medal, Anjali S of II BA English won   I MCJ, Kavya K K,II MA Malayalam, Femina Raj, II MA
        Silver medal and Seeya Metilda Baiju of II BA English   Malayalam, Abhina P A, III BA History have represented
        won  Bronze  medal  in  the  Asian  Junior  Powerlifting   Kerala team in the National Senior championship held
        championship held at Turkey from 23rd to 30th      at Kerala. Eight Football players- Nidhiya Sreedharan,
        December 2021. Aneesha M has won the ‘Best Lifter’   I MCJ, Sivisha C, I MCJ, Vinitha Vijayan, I MCJ,  Kavya
        award  in  the  said  championship,  a  first  Indian  lifter   K K, II MA  Malayalam, Abhirami R, Aleena Mathew,
        who won this award. ‘Fit 4 Life’ project was launched to   Gadha T G, III BA History and Arathi V, I BA History
        create health and fitness culture among students as well   have represented Calicut University team in the South
        as staff members. National Sports Day was celebrated   Zone India Inter University championship held at Christ
        on 29 August 2021 by conducting an online motivation   University, Bangalore. Our fifteen players represented
        class by Ms. Sruthy M, International Volleyball player   Thrissur District team for the senior state Football
        and Alumna of the college. New online Yoga certificate   championship  and  won  the  state  championship  for
        course was inaugurated by Sri. K. R. Sambashivan,   the first time in the history, held at Ernakulam on 25-
        President, Thrissur District Sports Council.       29 November 2021.  College Badminton team  won
        College Basketball team won the Calicut University   the Calicut University Inter Zone Championship held
        Inter Zone Championship held at SNDP College,      at St. Joseph’s College, Devagiri on 4-5 December
        Perinthalmanna on 9 & 10th February 2021. Angela   2021. Varsha Venkitesh, III B.Com has won the
        Sunny,  II  MA  Economics  represented  Kerala  Senior   Calicut University Individual championship in the said
        Basketball team for the Senior South Zone National   competition. Varsha Venkitesh, III  B. Com and Amrutha
        Championship held at Chennai and won the second    P.S, III B.Com have represented Calicut University team
        place. Eight Basketball players - Angela Sunny, II MA   in the South Zone Inter University championship held at
        Economics, Aleena Seby, II MA Economics, Divya Sam, I   Andhra Pradesh.
        M.Sc Psychology, Aparna Sadashivan, I MA Economics,   College Boxing team  won the Calicut University
        Alna, II MCJ, Nandana K M, III B.Com, Ann Mariya Johny   Inter Zone Overall championship held at CPE, Calicut
        III BA Economics, Aiswarya P.K, III BA English and  have   University on 7/12/2021. Nissy Laisy, II MCJ, Anaswara
        represented Calicut University team for the South Zone   P.M, I BA History, Parvathi. P, I BA History, Nikhitha
        Inter University Championship held at Chennai. College   M Baby, II BA History, Deepa Toppo, I BA Economics,
        Basketball team has won the Thrissur District Olympic   Ananya K.N, II BA History, Arya Hellan Rose, II BA
        Games 2022 Basketball competition held on 12-13    English, won the Gold medal and Anagha N.S, I MCJ,
        January 2022. Aleena Antony, I BA Economics and Shilpa   Anandhashayana  M B  won the bronze  medal  in the
        P J, I BBA represented Kerala Junior Basketball team for   Calicut University inter zone championship. Nissy Laisy
        the National Championship held at Madhya Pradesh.   of II MCJ, Anaswara P.M, I BA History, Parvathi. P, I BA
        Aleena Antony was the Captain of Kerala team. Aleena   History,  Nikhitha  M  Baby,  II  BA  History  represented
        Antony, I BA Economics, Samiya T.S, I BSc Chemistry   Kerala team in the senior national championship held
        and Shilpa P J, I BBA represented Thrissur District   at Haryana on 21-27 October 2021. Nissy Laisy, II MCJ,
        Junior Basketball team for the State championship   Anaswara P.M, I BA History, Parvathi. P, I BA History,
        and won the  second place,  held at Kottayam.  Elna   Nikhitha  M  Baby,  II  BA  History  won the  gold  medal
        Fernandez, II BA Economics and Alna P A, II MCJ    and Deepa Toppo, II BA Economics won the bronze
        represented Ernakulam District Basketball team for   medal in the Senior state Boxing championship held
        the senior state championship and won the same held   at Thiruvananthapuram on 8-10 September 2021.
        at Thiruvananthapuram. College Volleyball team has   College Handball team won the third place in the Calicut
        won the second place in the Calicut University Inter   University Inter Zone Championship held at Providence
        Zone Championship held at St. Mary’s College, Sulthan   College, Calicut on 13-14 December 2021. Helna Jose,
        Bathery. Seven Volleyball  players- Anitta Thomas,  I   I B.Com has been selected to the Calicut University
        MCJ, Aiswarya V.S, II MSW, Arya C.V, I MCJ, Anusree H,   team. Our Handball team has won the second place in
        III BA English, Aleena Biju, II B.Com, Rosemary Titus, II   the Thrissur District Junior and senior championship
        BA Economics and Shilpa Shaji, II BA Economics have   held. This team also won the second place in the Thrissur
        represented Calicut University team for the South   District Olympic games Handball competition.

                                                                                          WEAVES       25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[College Power Lifters Aneesha M, II BA English won the   2021 by Ms. Premi T.C Faculty, Department of
        gold medal in the Senior state powerlifting championship   Psychology. Internship programmes were arranged for
        held  at  Tirur  on  December  2021  and  she  has  been   III BSW students at various institutions like Kottapuram
        awarded as the ‘Best Lifter’ of the championship.   Integrated Development Society, Kerala,  Mahila
        Aneesha M also won the gold medal Junior State     Samakhya Society Nilamboor, Malappuram, Kattapana
        Powerlifting Championship held on November 2021    Municipality, Idukki, Vincentian Service Society Centre
        and this championship also she become the ‘best lifter’.   of Rural Development (VSSCRD), Angamaly, Ernakulam.
        Aneesha M also won the gold medal in the Junior    Four BSW final year students worked as volunteers for
        Nationals Powerlifting Championship held at Rajasthan   Covid-19 duty at Irinjalakuda Municipality, Help Desk
        on 2-6 January 2022. Sona P T, III BA Economics won   from 21st  June to  10th July,  2021. On  26th June  20
        Gold medal, Navya Prasad, II BA History won the Silver   21 MSW students Ms. Sruthy S, Ms. Jayalakshmi A.J,
        medal, Anjali S, II BA English won the silver medal and   Ms. Ann Mary S and Ms. Mary Amrutha K.C arranged
        Ajeesha A, II BA English won the bronze medal in the   a State Level Seminar on “Atrocities against Women
        Senior state powerlifting championship held at Tirur   and Legal Rights’ in association with Attapady Adivasi
        on 11-12  December 2021.  Seeya  Metilda Baiju,  II BA   Development Initiatives (AADI) and KAPS (Kerala
        English won the gold medal and Anjali S, II BA English   Association of Professional Social Workers).
        won  the  silver  medal  in  the  Junior  State  Powerlifting   The  department  provided  certificate  course  on  ‘Life
        Championship held at Kozhikode on 1-3 November     Skills’ for BSW students from 23rd June to 1st July,
        2021. Anjali S, II BA English represented Kerala team   2021. The students have done exemplary work as
        in the Junior National Powerlifting Championship   part of the Lifesavers Project of General Hospital,
        held at Rajasthan on 2-6 January 2022. Alna P A, II   Irinjalakuda in May and June 2021 for being available
        MCJ and  Aiswarya P K,  III BA English  represented   round the clock to attend the calls of Covid-19 patients.
        Kerala senior team and won the third place in the 12th   Students monitored the patients and provided guidance
        Federation Cup Netball Championship held at Delhi on   as well as psychological support to them. As part of
        22-24 September 2021. Aiswarya P K, III BA English has   the observance of the international day against drug
        represented Thrissur district in the senior state Netball   abuse  and  illicit  trafficking,  an  intercollegiate  painting
        championship and won the first place held at Alappuzha   competition “AMELIORATE 2K21” was conducted with
        on 13-14 November 2021. Meritta Symon, I MCJ has   “War on Drugs” as the theme on 26th June 2021. On
        represented  Kerala  Senior Netball  team  in the  Senior   5th June 2021, II BSW students organized ‘Reinstate
        South Zone Championship and won the first place held   ecosystem’ via online mode. The students  prepared
        at Tamil Nadu. Navya Prasad, II BA History won the   video presentations to promote conservation of
        Silver medal, Anu James, I MCJ, Ajeesha and Ranjana P   nature. In the month of August, I Sem MSW  students
        H, II BA English and Deepa Toppo, II BA Economics won   were placed in different organizations like; Snehagiri
        the bronze medal in the Calicut University Inter Zone   Society (Mala), Child Line (Pullazhi), AURA (Amballur),
        Weight Lifting championship held at St. Mary’s College,   Government Old Age Home and Government Boys
        Thrissur on 20/12/2021. Lakshmipriya K K, II BSc   Home(Ramavarmapuram) and Cyrene Special School(
        Psychology has been selected to the Calicut University   Kodunga)  as part of their agency field work and placed
        Kabaddi team. Department hosted three Calicut      them  for  community  field  work  in  Kaipamangalam
        University Championships Basketball women, Volleyball   and Adatt Grama Panchayaths. “Enthuse – 2021, an
        women, and Football women. Thrissur District Olympic   induction programme for the freshers of BSW was
        Games 2022 Basketball competition was conducted    conducted on 07/10/2021-09/10/2021. The sessions
        by  the department.  The  College  has  hosted  Calicut   were handled by Ms.Sruthy S., Social Work Volunteer
        University Basketball coaching camp and State senior   on the role of social workers during the pandemic era,
        and junior women Basketball coaching camps.        Ms. Livi C.L., Faculty in Psychiatric Social Work, Govt.
        A special word of gratitude to the Kerala State Sports   Medical College, Thrissur, on the importance of social
        Council for their support and sincere thanks to our sports   workers in health, Sinson Paulose, Social Worker, VON
        Council coaches Mr. Sanjay Baliga, Volleyball Coach, Mr.   Canada, on Equality and Diversity of social work in
        P.C. Antony, Basketball Coach, Mr. Jinu Joseph, Football   National and international level and Ms.Jiny George,
        coach and Ms. Najmunisa, Football Coach for their   ICDS supervisor, Palakkad on opportunities of social
        committed efforts which has won many laurels to the   work in Government sector.
        college in the field of Volleyball, Basketball and Football.   An Induction Programme named ‘Inspire’ was held
        Other coaches, Mr. Biju Mohan and Mr. Sreejith, Shuttle   for 1st Semester MSW students from 26/10/2021 to
        Badminton Coaches, Mr. Dhanesh, Kabaddi Coach, Mr.   29/10/2021.  The  first  sessions  were  handled  by  Ms.
        Manoj, Boxing Coach, and Sarath, Handball Coach, have   Ambi Joseph, Specialist in Social Development and
        done a great job to make the college the best.     Psychotherapist on the Scope of social workers in
                                                           Community Development’, Mr. Tiju.C.Thomas, Associate
        SOCIAL WORK                                        co-coordinator of World Wide Fund for nature
                                                           (WWF), India on  Awareness on Social Work Practice
        The  department  organized training  on Statistical   in Nature Conservation and Tribal Development ,Mr.
        Package for Social Sciences (SPSS) on 12th January   Abraham C, District Coordinator of Kollam Child line,

           26   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[on Social Work Practice with Children’, Ms. Saneesh   of  Journey  and  Quest  in  Literature”  was  conducted.
        C.S, Doctoral Researcher at the German Centre for   Important  days  and  festivals  including  World
        Integrated Biodiversity Research on ‘Communities and   Environment  Day,  Reading  day,  Gandhi  Jayanthi  and
        Biodiversity, Mr.Diljohn.P, Psychiatric Social Worker   Navarathri were observed with various programmes.
        on the scope of ‘Social Worker in De addiction Centre’,
        Ms. Sanitha Arackal, Research Assistant in NIMHANS   II.  FACULTY OF SCIENCE
        Bangalore on  ‘Introduction to Psychiatric Social Work’,
        Sr.  Salin  CHF,  Family  Counselor  in Dharshana  Family
        Counseling  Centre  Irinjalakuda  on    ‘Importance  of    BIOTECHNOLOGY
        Counseling in Present Society’ and Dr. Sr. Jessin, HOD
        of Social Work Department on  ‘An Introduction to   The  departmental  activities  for  the  year  2021-2022
        Social Work Department’. MSW first year students have   commenced with celebration of National Reading day
        conducted a programme on “WASTE TO ART” as part of   on 19thJune 2021.An Intercollegiate Online Quiz
        Asadi ka Amrith Maholsav at Chalakudy Municipality on   Competition was conducted as part of World reading
        01/10/2021.                                        day.  An  online  survey  was  conducted  in  June  2021  to
        MSW students organized a “Blood Donation Camp” on   analyse the COVID-19 awareness among the public.
        31st October 2021 in collaboration with Amala hospital   In connection with World Heart Day celebration on
        at Kaiparambu Grama Panchayath and also organized an   29.09.2021, an Essay writing competition on the
        awareness  programme at  Kaiparambu Panchayath  on   topic:  “Lifestyle  and  Heart  diseases”,  poster  making
        the topic of “Menstruation and Hygiene” in collaboration   competition on Autobiography of Heart and, a small
        with Ollur Vaidyarathnam Ayurveda College. The session   write-up on “Listen to your Heart” were organized.
        was led by Associate professor Dr. Anju on 27th October   A webinar on Medical Coding was organized in
        2021. MSW first year students organized an awareness   collaboration with Al Salama, Institute of Medical Coding
        class at Panachery Panchayath on the topic of “Legal   on 9th October 2021 through google meet. A webinar
        Clinic” in collaboration with Kudumbasree Gender   on “Antivirals and Vaccine strategies against COVID-19”
        Resource Centre .The resource person was Advocate   by Dr. Mohanan Valiyaveetil, Senior Principal Scientist
        Mr.Sivaraman  working  under  Legal  Service  Authority   (F), Institute  of Advanced Virology, Trivandrum was
        on 16th October 2021. The department organized a   organized by the Department  in collaboration with
        debate on the topic on Adukkalayil Ninnu Arangathekku   Golden Jubilee Research Centre of our college on 16
        on 1st November 2021 as part of Kerala Piravi. 1st year   November 2021 on google platform. In connection with
        BSW students observed children`s day and diabetics   Constitution Day, a mobile quiz was organized on 26th
        day on 14th November 2021 in an online platform    November 2021. Students of MSc Botany from Carmel
        to promote diabetes care. The department launched   College, Mala visited the laboratory of the Dept. of
        a project named ‘SANJO CRAFTS’ for differently-    Biotechnology (SJC, IJK) on 29th November 2021.
        abled persons on 17th December  2021, inaugurated   Fresher’s day ‘Esperanza 2K22’ for the I DC was
        by India’s First Wheelchair Anchor on Television and   conducted on 7th January 2022. Dr. Naijil George was
        Motivational Speaker, Ms. Veena Venugopal. Twenty   appointed as Ph.D. guide in University of Calicut. Dr. Viji
        BSW students attended an internship programme of   Mary Varghese and Dr. Kavitha O have attended a six day
        15 days at KISMAT- Kerala Interstate Migrants Alliance   FDP program on ‘Strategies for Enhancing Mental Health
        for Transformation, District Help Desk, Thrissur. During   in Teachers and Students’ organized by Rajagiri College
        the days the students met 400 guest workers by way of   of Social Sciences. Dr. Viji M O published two books
        camp visits, home visits and site visits.          and a research article titled ‘A Comprehensive Review
        As  part  of  community  fieldwork  at  Mala  Panchayat,   Of The Pharmacological Attributes Of Chromolaena
        social work trainees conducted an awareness class   Odorata’in Dogo Rangsang Research Journal.  She
        based on “Women safety” and “Snehitha Project”     also presented paper on ‘A study on phytochemical
        for the  women of Mala Grama  Panchayat (ward  15)   composition, antimicrobial and antioxidant activities of
        through google meet. The resource person, Ms. Emy   Nerviliaaragoana Gaud., an endangered medicinal plant
        Rose (Community counselor) shared more information   at  the  International  Conference  ‘Recent  Advances  in
        about SNEHITHA and the social work trainee Seethal   Biosciences and Technology-21’.
        Rajeev discussed issues of violence against women. The
        department launched and successfully completed new   BOTANY
        certificate  courses  for  MSW  first  and  third  semester
        students on Media and social work and Corporate Social   PG Department of Botany took a great leap forward by
        Responsibility (CSR) during this academic year.
                                                           starting an Innovation Centre for Natural Resources
                                                           (ICNR) by launching products like plant shelves, paper,
        ENGLISH (SELF-FINANCING)                           and grow bags from exotic weed- Water Hyacinth,
                                                           terrariums in ceramic pots, stone arts and herbal
        The department organized A National Webinar on     cosmetics. The department  initiated the activities for
        “The Dalit Body and the Question of Agency through   the year by organizing a webinar on ‘From Amazon to
        Graphic Fiction”. A Webinar on “Miles to Go: Metaphors   Amazon.com-the story of WWW by Dr. C. Nagendra

                                                                                          WEAVES       27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Prabhu, Associate professor, S D College, Alappuzha in  COMPUTER SCIENCE
        connection with World Environment Day and another
        international webinar ‘Development of Vaccine for   Department of Computer Science and B.Voc Software
        Ehrlichiosis’ by Dr. Sunil Thomas on 19th  November.   Development organized a webinar on “Environment
        An MOU was signed with S D College, Alappuzha on   And  Women”    on 7th  June  2021  by  Prof.  Kusumam
        June 25 for the mutual exchange of expertise. An Online   Joseph, NAPM National Convenor, in connection
        Workshop on value addition of water hyacinth plants   with Environment Day. The Department observed
        was conducted  on 17th  August. As part  of Christmas   International Yoga Day on 21st June 2021. In association
        celebrations,  Homemade  Cake Fest  was  organized   with IQAC, the Department conducted “A Webinar on
        among students to cherish their baking skills. Financial   Kickstart your Career in Data Analysis Using Excel” for
        aid was provided for the needy people from the profit   the students of our own college on 28th July 2021. The
        of herbal cosmetics products. The department also   resource Person was Jomon Joseph, CEO, The Strategist,
        organized  Four-day  Internship  programme  for  the   Cochin. Eid Mubarak was celebrated as the festival
        students sponsored by FECER. Sale of plant shelves and   of joy, sharing and gratitude. In association with IPSR
        earthen pots were arranged as part of green practices.  solutions ltd., the Department conducted a national level
                                                           online hackathon “CODEFEST 2K21” for the UG & PG
        CHEMISTRY                                          students of institutes across the country on 14th August
                                                           2021. The association of Department of Computer
        The activities for the year 2021-22 commenced with   Science and B.Voc Software Development,“ACER” was
        the celebration of World Environment Day on 5th June   inaugurated on 31st August, 2021 by Dr. D. Sreekanth,
        2021. Photography competition, cloth bag making, and   Senior  Knowledge  Officer,  ICT  Academy  of  Kerala.  A
        a clean and green programme were the special events   bridge session, “School to College and the Gateway to
        conducted to mark the day. The Chemistry Association   a Career” was conducted by Senthil Kumar Madhavan,
        was virtually Inaugurated by Dr. Reni Joseph, Professor,   Senior training Consultant & International Career
        St. Louis Community College, United States on 11-12-  Coach on 1st October, 2021. The department observed
        2021, followed by an international webinar. Nine of our   Gandhi Jayanthi and International Day of Non-Violence
        UG students secured A+ and eight PG students secured   on 2nd October, 2021. A one-day workshop on “Cloud
        O Grade in the  last academic  year. The department   Technologies & the Role of Cloud in Data Science” was
        organized  an  awareness  programme  for  the  local   conducted on 2nd October 2021 by Mahesh D, Data
        community on Eradication of Plastic Bag Usage from   Scientist, Menerva Software, Cochin. The Department
        our Surroundings on 3-07-2021, the International   organized an Induction Programme -”LEADING EDGE
        Plastic Bag Free Day. The awareness lecture was given   2021” for the first PG and UG batch by Dr. K. Satheesh
        by   Ms. Parvathi Arul Joshi, P.G. student, former State   Kumar, Associate Professor, Head, Department of
        Coordinator of the Indian Student Parliament,  and   Future Studies, University of Kerala. A Webinar session
        former Chairperson of the college. The Department   led by Dr. Zakkariya K. A, Director, DDUKK (Centre for
        commemorated Hiroshima and Nagasaki day on 6th     B. Voc, M. Voc and Research), CUSAT on “Scope and
        August 2021. Students lighted lamps as a tribute to the   Career opportunities of IT Sector and B. Voc Courses”
        victims of the atomic bombing and arranged Cartoon   was conducted on 5th December 2021. Ms. Anie Siva,
        and video making competitions. The department      Sub Inspector at Central Station, Kochi whose inspiring
        observed ‘Ozone Day’ on 16 September 2021 to spread   journey of life hit national headlines, delivered a
        awareness among students about the depletion of the   motivational talk. 166 participants from various colleges
        ozone layer. A digital poster-making competition on the   attended the program. World Computer Literacy Day
        theme: “Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam-The unique historic man”   was celebrated on 2nd December 2021. IT Quiz and
        was organized on Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam memorial day on   poster designing were conducted among the college
        27th July 2021. In connection with World Rivers Day,   students. Department of Computer Science and the
        Dept. of Chemistry (self-financing) organized an online   Innovation and Entrepreneurship Development Centre
        intercollegiate quiz competition on 26th September   (IEDC) organized HACKATHON 2K21 on 9th December
        2021. E-certificates were awarded to all the participants   2021 at MMT hall (Research Block).and IDEATHON
        who scored above 70%. “International day of Older   2K21 on 7th December to 9th December 2021.Students
        Persons” was observed on 1-10-2021 to predicate the   were actively participated in the event.
        need for access and meaningful participation in the
        digital world by elders. International Mole Day was  MATHEMATICS
        celebrated on 23rd October 2021. Late Dr. APJ Abdul
        Kalam, Former President of India, was commemorated   Postgraduate  and  Research   Department    of
        on  his birthday by  celebrating  World  Student’s  Day   Mathematics,  organized  a  two-day  ‘NET-JRF
        on 15th October, 2021. Online Handwriting, Diary   Orientation Programme in Mathematical Science’
        writing and Elocution competitions were held on this   on  21st  and  22nd  May  2021.    Department  organized
        day. MalayaliManka competition was conducted on 1st   Career orientation programme for Math Aspirants on
        November 2021 to mark Keralapiravi.                5th June 2021 and Career in Statistics on 27 January
                                                           2022. Mr. Vishnudas V, Mathematician, iTech Labs and

           28   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Dr.Rajesh G, Professor and Head, Dept of Statistics,   for  Renewable  Energy  Storage’  on 17th    September.
        CUSAT  were the resource persons of the programme   The resource person was Ms Sruthy Balakrishnan, PhD
        respectively. A collage-making competition based on the   Research Fellow at Curtin University, Australia. A two-
        theme “Graphic Representation of Covid data in Social   day Hands-on workshop on ‘AC-DC Inverter LED bulb
        Media and Newspapers” was organized for the students   assembly’ was organized on 20th and 21st September.
        on 29th June 2021, National Statistics Day. On 3rd July     A three-day Hands-on workshop on ‘Fabrication of
        the Department hosted a Webinar on ‘Administrative   Battery Eliminator with charger’ was conducted for
        Statistics’ led by Sri Shojan A. P., Deputy Director,   the students of the department on December 11, 13
        Department of Economics and Statistics, Thrissur. A   & 14. A one-day seminar was conducted on the topic
        webinar  led  by  Ms.  Sandra  Rebera,  a  Certified  Online   ‘The  Magnetosphere:  Earth’s  Invisible  Shield’  on  21st
        Tutor was organized on 30th July with the topic, on   December  2021.  The  resource  person  of  the  day  Dr.
        “Being an International Tutor - A Career Next to You”. The   Steffy Sara Varghese, Post-Doctoral Fellow at Central
        blessing of the new department premises was held on   University of Kerala, Kasaragod. The Physics Association
        8th September 2021. Mr. Anoop, Academic coordinator,   Day  Celebration;  ‘BIG  BANG  –  a  fission  that  emerges
        MATHLAB, Cochin led an online orientation workshop   from a fusion’ was organized on 22nd December. Toppers
        for JAM entrance for final year B. Sc. Students on 18th   of the previous UG & PG batches were congratulated
        September. The department hosted a webinar on “Ignite   on  the  day.  Hand  assembled  Inverter  LED  bulbs  were
        Yourself” which was delivered by Rev. Fr. Jobi Menoth,   distributed to the local community. Other days of
        Assistant  Professor, Department  of Psychology,  St.   relevance  like  World  environment  day,  Independence
        James Medical Academy to mark Gandhi Jayanthi. A   Day, and birthdays of renowned personalities were
        National Level Intercollegiate PowerPoint Presentation   celebrated with the conduct of poster competitions,
        Competition with “Mathematical discoveries that    photography competitions, and short videos.
        changed the world” as the theme was conducted on the
        21st and 22nd of October. A Poster making competition   PSYCHOLOGY
        was conducted to observe Fibonacci Day on 23rd
        November. SIM club Activities for the year 2021-22 was   Department  of  psychology  organized  an  international
        inaugurated by Ms. Lilly T I, Associate Professor (Rtd.,   webinar on Emotional intelligence for positive mental
        Dpt.  of  Mathematics)  on 30th  November. Toppers  of   health on 1st October 2021 for the students of our
        the academic years 2020 and 2021 were honoured on   own college. Principal, Sr.Asha Therese, inaugurated
        this day. Student manuscript,  MATHZIANNA VOL. 13   the event in which the resource person was Mr. Matt
        by postgraduate students (2019-21 batch) was released   Perelstein, CEO EQ4 peace Worldwide Inc, USA. Mental
        by Principal, Dr. Sr. Asha Therese in the programme. Dr.   health day was celebrated on 8th October 2021. Alumna
        N. Annamali from the Central University of Tamilnadu   of the department, Ms. Revathy Mohan delivered a talk
        delivered a Virtual talk using conference facility on   on  “Perseverance-  A  key  to success”.  The department
        the  topic  “Ring  Theory”.  As  per  MoU  signed  by  the   conducted various competitions like pookalam
        department with  Sahrdaya College of Advanced Studies,   competition, and digital poster-making competition as
        Kodakara, Faculty and student exchange programme   part of the world environment day celebration with the
        was  conducted  in  November.  Ms.  Sherin  Jose  T  from   theme ‘Reimagine, Recreate and restore.’
        St. Joseph’s College and Dr. Rani M. J. from Sahrdaya
        college handled the classes using Google classroom and   ZOOLOGY
        google meet. A chart-making competition was held in
        connection with National Mathematics Day on 22nd   Department  of Zoology  observed  World  Environment
        December. World Environment Day, International     Day  on  5th  June,  2021  by  conducting  awareness
        Yoga Day, Independence Day and Human Rights Day    programmes. Videos on the topic, ‘Environmental
        were celebrated online by creating short videos, online   Issues caused by Waste Disposal’ made by students
        post,ers and short movies. 13 students were placed in   and alumnae were uploaded to You-Tube and a ‘Virtual
        various MNCs like TCS, INFOSYS, WIPRO, HEXAWARE    Exhibition of Recycled Waste Materials’ was arranged.
        in  the  year  2021.  There  are  five  A+  grades  in  B.  Sc.   Reading Week was undertaken in which the UG and
        Mathematics and Three O grades in M. Sc. Mathematics   PG students selected and wrote an inspiring event,
        in the academic year 2020-21. Devika K A from II B.   from the life of a woman scientist they know about. An
        Sc. Mathematics has been selected for the prestigious   online meeting was convened on 18th July, 2021 to offer
        Online Foundation Course in Mathematics by MTTS    prayers  and  condolences  for  the  departed  soul  of  Ms.
        (Mathematics Training and Talent Search) which is a   Baby J. Alappat, former HOD and Associate Professor,
        Popular National level Mathematics undergraduate   Dept. of Zoology. Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam Memorial Day
        training programme in India.
                                                           was observed on 27th July 2021, by organizing a Video
                                                           making competition on ‘Quotes of APJ’ for UG and
        PHYSICS                                            PG  Zoology  students.  A  patriotic  song  competition
                                                           was organized for college students  in connection
        The Physics association activities commenced with an   with Independence Day 2021. An online Onam
        online  International  Webinar  on  ‘Thermal  Batteries   celebration ‘e-Onam’ was arranged on 18th August. The

                                                                                          WEAVES       29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Department organized online NET/JRF/GATE coaching   was organized in honour of the retiring Principal, Dr. Sr.
        on  28th  August  2021  by  qualified  Zoology  Alumnae.   Asha Therese, on 5th and 6th January, 2022. A webinar
        An  online  workshop  on  ‘Research  Methodology’  was   on  career  guidance  in  Medical  Coding  in  association
        organized on 16th & 17th September. with Dr. A. Biju   with Anton’s Medicode was organized on 29th January
        Kumar (Professor and Head, Dept. of Aquatic Biology   2021. On 30th January 2022, a Department Alumnae
        and Fisheries, University of Kerala) and Dr. Rajeev   meet was organized. As part of the international
        Raghavan (Assistant Professor, Kerala University of   webinar series, ‘Women In Life science’ – ‘WIL-2022’
        Fisheries and Ocean Studies) as resource persons. A   was organized on 1st February, 2022 in which Dr. Vrinda
        two-day online National workshop on ‘Fundamental   S. (Post-Doctoral Fellow - Brain Korea ’21, Republic
        Procedures in Microbiology’ was organized on 20th and   of Korea) interacted with the students. In connection
        21st September, 2021 ‘Basic Microbiology Techniques’   with World Wetlands Day, an Intercollegiate power
        and ‘Diagnostic Procedures for the Isolation of    point presentation competition was organized by the
        Pathogenic Bacteria from Fish and Shrimp’ were carried   Department on 2nd February, 2022 on the topic ‘Faunal
        out  by  Dr.  Manju  N.J.  (Assistant  Professor  in  Geology   Diversity in Wetlands of Kerala’.
        and Environmental Science, Christ College, IJK) and
        Dr. Sreedharan K. (Scientist, ICAR, CIFE, Mumbai)   COSTUME AND FASHION DESIGNING
        respectively. A three-day online international workshop
        on ‘Basics in Bioinformatics’ was organised from 25th   In  connection  with  National  Reading  Day,  the
        - 27th September, 2021. Dr, Gigi Poulose (Head, Dept.   department  conducted  an  inter-collegiate  Slogan
        of Zoology, St. Joseph’s college, IJK), Dr. Vrinda S. (Post-  making contest. Of the many entries from various
        Doctoral Fellow - Brain Korea ‘21, Incheon National   departments,  e-certificates  were  awarded  to  the  best
        University, Republic of Korea), Dr.  Ramya Ramankutty   five. The department organized its first National Webinar
        Nair (Technologist – Texas, USA) and Ms. Vinu Varghese   in connection with National Embroidery Day. The two
        (Assistant Professor, Dept. of Applied Biotechnology, St.   sessions were handled by Ms. Jyoti S Kordhanyamath,
        Mary’s College, Thrissur) handled the sessions.    Asst. Professor-Department of Fashion Design, AIGS,
        World Lung Day was observed by organizing an       Bangalore and Ms. Deepasri Prabhakar, Fashion
        international webinar on 25th September 2021 as Dr.   Designer, Founder- Mihira Inc. Bangalore. An Inter-
        Vimal Gangadharan, Pulmonologist and Program Leader,   collegiate Handloom Saree Draping Contest “Swadesi”
        Kauri Academy, New Zealand the principal speaker. A   was conducted in connection with National Handloom
        webinar on ‘Genesis of Dowry and Preventive Measures’   Day. An Inter-collegiate Virtual Malayalee Manka
        by Dr. Kavitha Balakrishnan (Co-ordinator, School of   Contest “Chandam” was organized to celebrate Onam.
        Legal Studies, Kannur University) was organized on 1st   The students of the department of Costume & Fashion
        October, 2021. An international webinar on ‘Trends   Designing presented a Virtual Fashion Show “Charkha”
        in Technologies in Bioscience’ was organized on 2nd   in connection with National Khadi Day. An Inter-
        October for which Dr. Valsamma Joseph (Professor,   Collegiate Designing Contest was arranged to mark
        National Centre for Aquatic Animal Health, CUSAT)   Diwali celebrations. An industrial visit was conducted
        and Dr. Sreelakshmi B. Nair (Quality Control Analyst,   by the department to “Thrissur Wovens”, Ashtamichira
        New Aroa Biosurgery Zealand) as the resource persons.   on 19-11-2021 as part of the curriculum. The industry
        National Wildlife Week – ‘Agria Zoi 2021’ was observed   with specialization in women’s innerwear follows a
        by the Department from 2nd – 8th October, 2021 by   line production system in which the sewing operators
        conducting various competitions for students. The final   sit in a line format for the construction which results
        year  students  participated  in  the  MANAV  Scientific   in better production. A Model Hunt was conducted by
        Reading and Comprehension Self-Assessment Module   the department on the college campus to find out the
        (funded by Dept. of Biotechnology, Ministry of Science   potential style setters and to form the college fashion
        & Technology, Govt. of India, and co-ordinated by IISER-  show team on the 22nd of December 2021. Around 20
        Pune, NCCS-Pune and Persistent Labs) for 15 days -   students participated of which 12 were selected on the
        27th September to 10th October 2021. Dr. Gigi Poulose   basis of their caliber.
        received the Certificate of Appreciation for coordinating
        the programme. On 10th November 2021, ii+OMICS     B.Voc MICROBIOLOGY AND
        Lab of the Department was inaugurated by Principal,
        Dr. Sr. Asha Therese. National Bird Watching Day, was   FORENSIC SCIENCE
        observed to mark the birth anniversary of Dr. Salim Ali,
        by organizing a drawing competition on the theme ‘A   Webinar series on “Bio instrumentation Frontiers 2021”
        Bird’ for UG students. As part of No Pesticide Use Week   was organized by the department. Dr. Sunil Kumar
        observance, an awareness programme on ‘Agroecology   P.N, scientist, NMR facility, IIRBS, MG University gave
        for Our Children’s Future’ was jointly organized by the   a lecture on the topic “NMR spectroscopy; Basics,
        department and Pesticide Action Network, India wherein   Instrumentation and Applications” on 03/07/2021.
        Mr. C. Jayakumar (Director, Pesticide Action Network   Dr. Jasim Basheer, junior researcher, Dept. of Cell
        (PAN), India) was the resource person. An exhibition,   biology Palacky University, Czech Republic lectured on
        as an academic outreach programme, ‘ZooVigour2K22’   “Techniques  in  advanced  fluorescence  Microscopy  for

           30   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[plant-microbe interactions” on 10/07/2021. The third   of Investing”. The CMA orientation programme for
        session of the webinar series held on 17/07/2021 was   faculty  and  students  was  conducted  on  July  28,  2021
        handled by Mr. Sanu Xavier, CEO, of the Innovation   by  Adv.  CMA.  Sankar  Panicker,  certified  professional
        Incubation  Centre,  MG  University  on  the  topic   in commercial arbitration. In connection with World
        “Spectroscopic analytical techniques”. Dr. Anu Gopinath   Nature Conservation Day, National Level Photography
        Assistant Professor in Chemical Oceanography Dept.   Competition  was  organized  on  July  28,  2021.  Inter
        of Aquatic Environment Management, KUFOS was       Collegiate  Cartoon Drawing Competition  was  held
        the resource person for the Topic “FTIR Principles   in connection with  Henry Fayol’s birth anniversary
        and Applications” on 24/07/2021. - Dr. Annie Y,    on  July  29,  2021.  A  National  Webinar  on  “Women
        Assistant Professor, Biochemistry School of Bioscience,   Empowerment through Financial Literacy” was
        MG University gave the presentation on the topic   organized on July 29, 2021. An International Webinar
        “Chromatography-based techniques” on 31/07/2021.   on the topic ‘Resilient Leadership in the Post Pandemic
        Dr. Aseem Wagle, Application Chemist, Toshwin      Era’ was held on 14th August. The department and
        Analytical Pvt. Ltd led the session on 07/08/2021on   Institute of Cost Accountants of India- Cochin Chapter
        the  topic  “GC-MS Understanding  the Technologies”.   signed MOU on 21st August entrusting the department
        Karkadakam and the heath awareness was conducted to   to act as a satellite centre for conducting CMA.
        instigate the habit of immunity boost among students on   A Career Guidance webinar was organized on 28th
        August 21, 2021. The department organized a Hands-  August 2021 in collaboration with “RISE” Right Initiative
        on workshop on ‘Rapid detection New Psychoactive   for Student Empowerment Pvt. Ltd.  The department
        Substances’ for the teaching staff on 3/11/2021. As   organized ‘Melting moments: Rendezous with a Baker’,
        part  of  the  Club  Activities,  Newsletter  Presentation   an interaction with women entrepreneur, for faculty
        was done by the students. Relevant news related to   and students on 30th September 2021. Inauguration of
        Microbiology and Forensic science for the months from   FDP on “Project Guidance: A Practical Approach”, jointly
        January to December was presented by the students in   organized by Commerce departments of St Joseph’s
        the department. Students presented Research papers   College Irinjalakuda and Nirmala College, Muvattupuzha
        on topics related to Microbiology and Forensic Science   was done by Dr. M.C. Dileepkumar, Former Vice-
        in the third week of every month.                  chancellor,  Sree  Sankaracharya  University  Kalady was
                                                           held on October 30, 2021. A motivational talk for faculty
        B.Voc MATHEMATICS AND                              and students was conducted on 8th December. Mrs.
        ARTIFICAL INTELLIGENCE                             Aswathi Dinil, TEDx speaker, psychologist, trainer, and,
                                                           life coach and Mrs. Vandhana Raghavan Vadakute UX
                                                           designer at Experion Technologies. Human Rights Day
        The  students  of  IInd  B.Voc  Mathematics  and  Artificial
        Intelligence conducted a quiz completion named “Feca”   was observed on December 10, 2021 by taking human
        on 7th May 2021. A webinar on “The importance      rights pledge by the students and faculty. An International
        of  Artificial  Intelligence”  was  organized  as  Ms   Webinar on Research  Article Writing and Publishing
        Krishnachalitha KC, MSc. B.Ed. as the speaker on 7th   was held on December 21 and the sessions were
        May 2021. A Talk on “Introduction to Deep Learning” was   handled by Dr. Justin Paul, Editor in chief, International
        organized by Ms. Tina (Asst. Professor, Dept. Computer   Journal of consumer studies and Dr. Shaheema Hameed,
        Science, St. Joseph’s college, IJK) on 30th November   Curriculum Developer at Aspire Academy for Sports
        2021. The students of IInd B.Voc Mathematics and   Excellence under the Aspire Zone Foundation in
        AI conducted a game corner named ‘Squid’ on 30th   Doha. ‘Santa’s Surprise’, an exhibition cum sale of the
        November 2021 in which games developed by students   products of Y we com, Young Women Entrepreneurs of
        were showcased.                                    Commerce, was organized on December 22, 2021. Ms.
                                                           Elizabeth Paul C has secured Young Researcher Award
                                                           from UIJIR Academic Research Foundation on May 30,
        III. FACULTY OF COMMERCE                           2021. Ms. Remya S has secured Research Excellence
                                                           Award from UIJIR Academic Research Foundation on
        COMMERCE (AIDED)                                   October 29, 2021. Ms. Amritha Thomas and Ms. Jitha
                                                           Thomas secured Best Paper Awards in the Doctoral
        The activities of the Research Department of Commerce   Conference organized by ICFAI University, Jharkhand.
        for the academic year 2021-2022 commenced with a
        National  Webinar  on  stock  markets  in  collaboration  BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION
        with Shine Projects, an online education company, on 2
        June 2021. An intercollegiate online quiz was conducted   On 1st of June , in connection with the Doctor’s Day
        in connection with World Environment Day on 5th June   Celebration  ,  the students  invited  Dr.Aishwarya
        2021. Reading day was celebrated on June 19, 2021, by   Thampi , MBBS for a live talk show via zoom meeting
        conducting online quiz, video presentation, and book   In connection with World Environment Day, a virtual
        reviews. In collaboration with BSE Investor Protection   role play and slogan speech were conducted by the
        Fund, a webinar was conducted on 21st June, on the   students. On June 19 , Reading Day was celebrated by
        topic “BSE Investor Awareness  Program - Principles   the students by performing a Role play for promoting

                                                                                          WEAVES       31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[interest in books and reading. An online competition   Drawing Competition” was held by the students of 3rd
        for poster making and essay writing in connection with   year, B.com(CA) on the occasion of “International Day
        the International Day against Drug abuse and illicit   for the Elimination of Violence against Women” on 25th
        trafficking was conducted on 26th June 2021. On 15th   November,  2021.  Theme  was  “Stop  Violence  Against
        August 2021 , the students designed a Rapid - Fire ( time   Women”.
        based ) Online Quiz for high school and college students.
        The competition was taken place at an International level   IV. RESEARCH
        where the registrations came from UAE, New Zealand ,
        Kuwait etc. Cash awards were distributed to the Top
        2 position holders.  On 5th September, the students  RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTRE
        organized a virtual teacher’s Day celebration via Google
        meet platform and gifts were awarded to them lateron.    A Webinar on ‘New Trends in Cancer Nanotheranostics’
        An  Idea  Generation  presentation  competition  was   was conducted on 27th November 2021. The resource
        conducted for college students on the topic The Right to   person was Dr. Kochurani K Johnson from Dept. of
        know - Building back better with access to information,   Material science and engineering,  University of New
        in connection with the World Development Information   South Wales, Sydney, Australia. Organized PROJECT
        Day 2021 on 21st October 2021. Attractive cash     LAUNCH@SJC  KSE  LIMITED,  on  18  September  2021
        rewards were given to the winners.                 which was conducted in association with the project
        In connection with Kerala Piravi, the department hosted   granted for establishment of Animal tissue culture
        a celebration on 1st November 2021 with cultural and   lab  at  research  centre.  An  amount  of  8  lakhs  as  first
        traditional programmes. The students were dressed up   installment was granted by KSE Limited, Irinjalakuda
        in their beautiful ethnic wears. On 21st November, the   for the purchase of inverted microscope in the Animal
        department conducted a Cartoon Making competition   tissue culture lab. KLF private Limited, Irinjalakuda
        in connection with the Women Entrepreneur’s Day    donated 2 lakhs for the faculty  who are engaged  in
        2021. A live workshop was conducted for the 3rd DC   the  scientific  and  industrial  research  field.  9  faculty
        students by Ms. Resmi , assistant professor at SSV   members are working in this field. Management of the
        College  on  the  research  methodology  and  project   college provided 10 lakhs as seed money to 30 students
        instructions. On 22nd of December , the Association   and 26 faculty. Under consultancy service, the centre
        Day  for  the  Department  of  Business  Administration   offers services such as guidance to student projects,
        was conducted in the morning .It was followed by the   water analysis, the selling of microbial cultures and
        Fresher’s Day celebration which was conducted in the   plantlets, and the application of instruments.
        3DC Classroom for all the First year students after the
        main college fresher’s day celebrations. The Christmas   CRMS - CENTRE FOR RESEARCH IN
        celebrations were conducted on 23rd of December with   MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES
        a wide range of cultural programs and fun filled games
        followed by Cake cutting celebration.
                                                           One day National webinar on ‘Basic tools in algebra
                                                           and analysis’ was conducted on 3rd February 2022. Dr
        COMMERCE & MANAGEMENT STUDIES                      M. N. Narayanan Namboothiri from CUSAT, Dr Krishna
        (SELF FINANCING)                                   Hanumanthu from CMI Chennai, Dr Viji M from St.
                                                           Thomas College(Autonomous), Thrissur were Resource
        An  orientation  programme  on CA  &  CMA  (India)   persons for the programme. Pravas K., Department of
        was organized on On 4th November 2021. The         Mathematics, KKTM Government College, Pullut joined
        resource person was Mr. Aju P.V., Practicing Chartered   as research supervisor in the research centre and RAC
        Accountant, Visiting Faculty of Auditing at ICAI,   was held for 4 new research scholars on 29/09/2021.
        Thrissur Chapter. The session that was conducted on   Department of Mathematics organized endowment
        the Zoom platform was informative and beneficial to the   lecture in honour of Dr. Mangalambal N. R. instituted by
        students. “ACCA, CMA (US)” orientation was conducted   the research scholars and the lecture was delivered by Dr.
        on 6th November 2021. Mr.Shone Babu,(Head          Aparna Lakshmanan S, Assistant Professor, Department
        of  Partnerships),International  Skill  Development  of Mathematics, Cochin University of Science and
        Corporation (ISDC), UK) was the resource person who   Technology on the topic ‘Topology generated by Graph’.
        enlightened the students regarding the importance      CRC - CENTRE FOR RESEARCH IN COMMERCE
        of ACCA, CMA (US). On 8th November 2021, the       The department produced 3 Ph.D.’s during this academic
        Department organized an “Online Collage Competition”   year. FDP on “Project Guidance: A Practical Approach,”
        held  by  the  students  of  3rd  year,  B.com(FA)  on  the   was jointly organized by the Commerce departments
        occasion of “World Literacy Day” . “Literacy teaching   of St Joseph’s College Irinjalakuda and Nirmala College,
        and  learning  in  the  Covid-19  Crisis  and  Beyond”  was   Muvattupuzha. International webinar on Research
        the theme adopted for the compettion. An “Online   Article Writing and Publishing on December 21. Ms.
        Photography Competition” held by the students of 3rd   Elizabeth Paul C has secured Young Researcher Award
        year, B.com(FB) on the occasion of “ International Day   and Ms. Remya S has secured Research Excellence
        of Older Persons ” was on October 1st, 2021. An “Online   Award from UIJIR Academic Research Foundation.
           32   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Best Paper Awards to Ms. Amritha and Ms. Jitha in   commanding  officer  of  7K  Girls  Bn,  Thrissur,  Kerala,
        Doctoral Conference. Ms Elizabeth Paul C, Ms. Remya,   as the guest speaker. On 1st December 2021 (World
        Ms. JithaThomas, Ms. Amritha and Ms. Sherline got   AIDS Day), cadets distributed  handmade brooches to
        Membership in REST Society for Research International.     the college community to spread awareness. The 7th
                                                           of December 2021 was observed as the Armed Force
        V. STUDENT WELFARE PROGRAMMES                      Flag Day to honor the martyrs and the men in uniform
                                                           who continue to safeguard the country’s honour. On
                                                           8th December 2021, the cadets paid homage to the
        NCC – NATIONAL CADET CORPS                         Chief of Defence Staff Gen Bipin Rawat and other 13
                                                           soldiers who were killed in the chopper crash. On 10th
        NCC has been  fully functional  in St. Joseph’s College   December, candles were lit in memory of all brave hearts
        (Autonomous) since its establishment on the campus.   the nation lost in the helicopter crash. UNICEF Day was
        The functioning of the unit on this campus has always   observed on December 11 which was commemorated
        given the institution sufficient cause for pride for it has   by preparing posters that  highlighted elimination of
        won many national and international honours, awards   hunger, violation of children’s rights, and discrimination
        and recognitions. The cadets were dispatched for the   against race, region, or religion. Vijay Diwas was
        legislative election duty From 5th - 7th of April and  were   observed to reminisce the service, valour, and sacrifices
        assigned the duty of Special Police Officers. Spreading   of the gallant men of the Indian Armed Forces’ victory
        awareness on the World Day for Safety and Health at   over Pakistan in the 1971 war. Cadets visited the Amar
        Work, the cadets prepared a video emphasizing the   Jawan on 16th December 2021 and paid homage to the
        precautions to be taken during the pandemic. On 10th   brave soldiers who have given their lives to the country.
        May 2021, the cadets celebrated the 41st birthday of   On 12th January, (National Youth Day) cadets prepared
        Subedar Major and Honorary Lieutenant Yogendra     a video to promote indigenous sports of our country.
        Singh Yadav PVC, the youngest recipient of the highest   The 74th Indian Army Day was celebrated with pride,
        Indian military honor, the Param Vir Chakra. As part of   zeal  and  passion  commemorating  the  sacrifices  and
        World  Environment  Day  on  5th  June  2021,  the  NCC   contributions made by the Indian Army. 26th January
        cadets posted a photo on social media of the group   2022, started with flag hoisting by principal Dr. Sr. Asha
        planting saplings. The cadets made a video on what   Therese  in  the  presence  of  Lt.  Litty  Chacko.  The  flag
        the UN Decade is, and how to support the ecosystem   hoisting was recorded via Google Meet so that all the
        to be a part of ‘Generation Restoration’. International   students and faculty of the college could attend it from
        Day of Yoga was celebrated by preparing a video on   their homes. The cadets also prepared a short video of
        the  importance of  “Surya  Namaskar. Commemorating   wishing everyone a Happy Republic Day in the various
        the Kargil Vijay Diwas, the cadets paid their tributes to   official languages of India and a Patriotic Dance. LCPL
        the Kargil heroes.Celebrating the 75th Independence   Aswathy P M and CDT Ardhra Babu set their mark as the
        Day on 15 August 2021, Azadi ka Amrit Mahotsav was   Covid-19 Youth volunteers assisting the health workers
        observed.  The  cadets  participated  in  ‘Rashtraaan’  and   at  Irinjalakuda  General  Hospital,  from  14  May  2021
        ‘Fit India Freedom Run 2.0’.  The 75th Independence   to 22 July 2021. They were awarded with Certificates
        Day on 15th August 2021, started with flag hoisting by   of Appreciation for their work. ENTHUSIA 2.0, an SSB
        principal Dr. Sr. Asha Therese in the presence of Lt. Litty   inspired intercollegiate competition was conducted
        Chacko, students and staff and the parade by the cadets   on 7th & 8th August 2021 by NCC (Army & Navy) of
        was worth mentioning. On National Sports Day, Indian   MES  Kalladi  College,  Mannarkkad  via  online  platform
        medal winners in Tokyo Olympics and Josephites who   . SUO Krishnapriya S, JUO Ann Mary Wilson, CQMS
        won medals in Calicut university championships were   Merin Sebastian, CPL Selin AJ and Cadet Ayana Joshy
        honoured.                                          represented the college, securing 8th  position among
        Teachers’ Day was celebrated on 5th September 2021   37+ colleges, with 524 points.
        through  a  video  to  honour  ANO  Lt.  Litty  Chacko  and
        presented a gift to her as a token of love and respect. As   NSS – NATIONAL SERVICE SCHEME
        a part of International Ozone Day on 16th September
        2021and International Day of Peace was observed on   A free Covid vaccination drive for students was conducted
        September 21, 2021. Indian Air Force Day was celebrated   in college by NSS units 50 &167 on 18.08.2021. NSS
        on 8th October 2021 by reminiscing its milestones   Volunteers distributed drinking water to the areas with
        through videos and posters. Posters were made to mark   water shortage in Irinjalakuda on 07.09.2021. Nearly
        Global Handwashing Day, on 15th October 2021. World   3000 cashew seedlings were distributed to all the
        Students Day was observed on 15th October 2021. As   students  and  faculty  of our  college,  and  to  the  public
        a part of the 73rd NCC day, on 26th November 2021,   on 13.10.2021. Cashew seedlings were obtained from
        “Run For Fun” was conducted to spread awareness    Kerala State Cashew Cultivation Development, as part
        among the youth to remain healthy and fit. A National   of the agency’s “New Cashew Garden Scheme”.  As part
        level interaction was conducted  on the topic  “How to   of Azadi ka Amrit Mahotsav, PAN INDIA AWARENESS
        develop leadership quality during school and college   and  OUTREACH  PROGRAMME  NSS  in  association
        time” with Col H Padmanabhan, Retd, the former     with St. Joseph’s college,  arranged an interactive

                                                                                          WEAVES       33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[session with the well-known playback singer Anoop   and Academic Counselling and Psycho Therapeutic
        Sankar on 17.10.2021. The seven-day special camp for   counselling for mental illness. Educational Guidance
        2021-22 was inaugurated by Smt. Sonia Giri, Municipal   and Stress relaxation Techniques are specially aimed
        chairperson,  Irinjalakuda  on  24.12.2021.  State  Level   at  the  student  community.  The  centre  undertook
        Inauguration of NSS Residential camps was conducted   pre-marital  counselling,  legal counseling  for  women
        in St. Joseph’s college, Irinjalakuda on 27.12.2021. Dr. R.   in divorce cases, and couple counselling throughout
        Bindu, Minister for Higher Education and Social Justice,   the year. The centre carried out sessions of individual
        Govt. of Kerala inaugurated the function.          counselling,  group  counselling,  behavior  modification
                                                           therapy, and alcoholic counselling. Board meetings and
        GRIEVANCE REDRESS CELL                             periodical gatherings of various associations like AA
                                                           group (Alcoholic Anonymous Group) and AIDS victims
        Grievance  boxes  were  installed  on  every  floor  and   and other needy people were arranged. AA group and
        complaints  dropped  in the  boxes  were  taken  into   HIV Victims Group Swandhanam meet regularly and
        account. Discussions were held in the committee and   the members are given support and counselling to
        proper decisions were taken to solve grievances raised   stop addiction, and abuse in order to lead a better and
        by students. Due to covid 19 pandemic most of the   normal life. Tele-counselling  for corona patients was
        classes were in online mode. Grievances regarding   done during the lockdown.  The centre also undertook
        the internet issues were solved with the help of class   post-covid counselling to provide mental support to the
        teachers of respective classes.                    needy ones. Kerala Catholic Youth Movement of the
                                                           diocese of Irinjalakuda conducted ‘Mithra’ Counselling
        ACADEMIC EXCELLENCE                                service  through  the  centre.  World  Environment  Day
                                                           on June 5th and World Social Work Day on 17th March
                                                           were observed with various programmes. International
        An  online  student  induction  programme  for  the  first-
        year students was conducted in online mode. The    Day for the Elimination of Violence Against Women was
        week-long programme started on 5th October 2021    observed on November 25th 2021.
        and the objective was to brief on the vision, mission
        and values of the institution. The programme helped to   LIBRARY
        make the students aware of the rules and regulations
        of the college and helped to acquaint them with the   “Athenaeum”, was organized in collaboration with the
        facilities and practices of the college. Activities of   Alumnae to celebrate the Reading week. In association
        various associations and clubs were introduced to them.       with the Speak English Club, “Reading Reels” was
        Mentors were assigned to a group of students. Tutorial/  organized. A National Webinar on “Digital Publishing
        Mentoring books for recording information about    Trends” was organized in collaboration with IQAC.
        students were given and tutors’ tips were distributed.
        A list of tutors and assigned mentees were made ready   VII. COMMITTEES
        for each department. SAT (subject aptitude tests) exams
        were conducted online. SAT mark lists were collected
        and filed. The committee supervised the preparation of  AICUF - ALL INDIA CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY
        the syllabus for the bridge course, maintenance of its   FEDERATION
        attendance records, and conduct of classes.
                                                           The AICUF commenced its activities for the academic
        VI. FACILITIES                                     year 2021-2022 with a prayer meeting for the faculty,
                                                           staff, and students through the online platform. A
                                                           special prayer session was arranged on the Feast of the
        DARSANA FAMILY COUNSELLING CENTRE                  Sacred Heart of Jesus and on the Feast of St. Mariam
                                                           Thresia.  Aleena C. A of II B. Com Computer Application
        Darsana stands as a beacon in the face of the darkness   was elected as the AICUF President.  With regard to
        in society and family. This centre aims at reducing   Pope Francis’ declaration of the year of St. Joseph,
        problems by strengthening family coping skills and   from 8 December 2020 to 8 December 2021, various
        effecting positive changes in attitude by providing timely   competitions like speech competition, poetry recitation,
        counselling and support.  The centre  functions with   and a few  other events were  conducted online.  St
        the  support  and  cooperation  from  the  management,   Joseph’s Meet was held on 4th December 2021 in which
        principal,  and  dedicated  service  of  three  counselors   participants were the ‘name-bearers’ of St. Joseph.
        and other staff members.  Counselling professionals at   Participants were presented with a small statue of St.
        the centre are Sr.Salin (MSW [Medical and Psychiatric   Joseph as a token of love.  The programme began with
        Social Work]), Mrs. Jiby Johny (MSW [Medical and   a prayer, followed by the message by Principal Dr. Sr.
        Psychiatric Social Work]) and Adv.Lina joseph (Legal   Asha Therese, and then a session by Fr. Jilson Payyapilli.
        Counsellor, LLB, MBA). The Centre focuses on key   The  winners  of the  online  competition  were  awarded
        areas including Personality development, Family    prizes on this day. Holy Masses were coordinated in


           34   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[the  college  chapel  on  the  first  Friday  of  every  month.   Centres during the pandemic. A National Webinar on
        The College Christmas celebration was organized by   ‘Gender Roles-Psychological and Legal aspects’ was
        the AICUF on 23rd December 2021. As part of the    on 14th and 17th August, 2021 by Mini Narayanan,
        celebration, competitions like crib making competition,   alumna, Dept. of English,1989-‘92 (Assistant Professor,
        star making competition, card making competition and   Amity Institute of Behavioral & Allied Sciences, Amity
        carol competition were conducted. On the day of the   University, Maharashtra) and Adv. Priya PK, alumna,
        celebration, College portico was decorated splendidly to   Dept  of  Commerce:1990-’93,  (Advocate,  Honourable
        spread Christmas cheer and joy. A flash mob and cultural   High Court of Kerala) respectively. The Association
        programmes were also conducted. Activities held during   organized ‘Guruvandanam’ – A tribute to Gurus
        the year were under the leadership of Dr. Sr. Neena   on 5th September 2021 to honour the teachers. In
        (AICUF Animator) and the team.                     collaboration  with  Research  Centre,  an  International
                                                           Webinar on ‘Cancer Nanotheranostics’ by Kochurani
        ALUMNAE ASSOCIATION                                K Johnson, Alumna, Dept. of Biotechnology 2006 -09,
                                                           Research Scholar, Scientia, University of New South
        The Alumnae Association of St Joseph’s College ‘St   Wales, Australia, was conducted on 27th November,
        Joseph’s College Alumnae’ (Reg No: TSR/TC/283/2018)   2021. A new life skill development programme named
        is registered as a Charitable Society under the    ‘Bloom- Being to becoming’, has been designed by Mrs
        Travancore  Cochin  Literary,  Scientific  and  Charitable   Santhi Rajagopal, alumna, Dept. of Economics,1972-’75,
        Societies Registration Act XII of 1995. The society works   for the students of the college. The expertise of a team
        under the chairmanship of Principal Dr. Anis K V and the   of eminent resource persons under the guidance of Mr.
        President Mrs. Mayalaxmi with support from Secretary   Gopinath Menon, a retired UN professional was made
        Mrs. Sumina MS and Treasurer Sr Finy PJ. Alumnae   available. The alumnae from the Department of History
        committee members assembled at frequent intervals   1986-‘89 held a reunion at the college campus on 19th
        on Google platform to plan and discuss the activities   December 2021.
        of the year 2021-22. Five alumnae executive meetings   The  first-ever  virtual  gathering  of  the  Gulf  chapter
        were organized.  ‘Oru Vattom Koodi’, a programme   was held on Google meet platform on 7th January
        to offer tribute to the late Jnanapeedham poet ONV   2022. The captain Ms. Tessy Varghese from Oman
        Kurup, was inaugurated by poet Rafeeq Ahmed on     coordinated the event. The first ever virtual gathering
        13thFebruary, 2021. A song on ONV named ‘Gananjali’   of the international chapter was held on 8th January
        was composed by the alumnae, and it was aired on print,   2022. The captains Dr. Mini Vithayathil and Ms. Roisy
        visual and social media. In connection with International   Sibi reunited the Josephite alumnae spread across the
        Women’s Day, 2021, on 8th March, the list of alumnae   world on a single screen. The first-ever virtual gathering
        with remarkable achievements in their careers was   of the UAE Chapter was held on the Zoom platform on
        announced through the various alumnae social media   15th January 2022. The captains, Ms. Rosily Jagadish
        groups. A drawing competition was held on the 9th of   and Ms. Anjali Venugopalan coordinated the event. Ms.
        May, 2021 in connection with international Mothers’   Sandhya Narayanan representing the 1992-‘95 batch
        Day, 2021 on the topic “Be the heroine of your life, not   handed  over  a  financial  contribution  of  INR  64,501  /-
        the  victim”.  A  National  workshop  on  ‘Gender  Inequity   towards the installation of the solar resources to Dr.
        in Kerala- The role of academicians and students’ by   Sr. Asha Therese on 15th January, 2022.   Dr. Kavitha
        Dr. Seema Bhaskaran (alumna, Dept. of English, 1989-  Balakrishnan, alumna, Department of Zoology 1992-95
        ’92, Mission Manager in the National Rural Livelihood   presented a self-created mural painting to the college
        Mission, MRD, Hyderabad ) was organized on 22nd May,   on 15th January 2022. The annual Global meet was
        2021. A webinar on ‘the importance of Career guidance   held on 26th January, 2022 in a hybrid style. Alumnae
        in the pandemic world’-by Dr Bindu Vijayakumar,    newsletter Domus Josfite, Volume No: 20 was released
        alumna, Dept of Mathematics: 1986-’89, visiting faculty   by Principal and was received by the Sahitya Academy
        at  Bharathiyar University, was  organized  on  the  31st   Award winner, Meenakshi  C.S., alumna,  1977-’79 pre-
        May, 2021.                                         degree batch. Ms. Reshma P A (Isha Farha Quraishy),
        A  photography  competition  named  ‘My  Green  Home’   alumna, Department of Botany 2006-09 was elected
        was conducted in connection with World Environment   the Best Alumna for her multi-faceted talents and
        Day, 2021. A webinar, ‘Athenaeum’ was organized to   various achievements. Alumnae achievers and authors
        observe the reading week, on25th June, 2021. Dr Khadija   were honoured during the programme. The retiring staff
        Mumtaz, Dr Atheena MN and Dr Roshni Swapna gave    members Dr. Sr. Asha Therese (Principal & Associate
        short talks on the occasion. ‘Glory 2.0’ was organized to   Professor),Dr. Lissamma John (Associate Professor &
        honour and appreciate the prestigious alumna       Head, the Department of Hindi) and Mrs. Joicy C (Office
        Dr. R Bindhu, Minister for Higher Education and    Attendant) were felicitated.
        Social Justice, Kerala on 31st July 2021. The Minister   HRDC - HUMAN RESOURCE DEVELOPMENT CELL
        also inaugurated the Gulf Chapter, UAE Chapter,    A  Seminar  on  Global  career  opportunities  and
        and International Chapter of the association on the   campus placements was conducted in collaboration
        occasion. Alumnae members raised a sum of Rupees   with EazyLink Academy, on 25th November, 2021.
        42000 to distribute Oximeters to the District Care   HRDC  organized  “Creating  a  Roadmap  for  Student

                                                                                          WEAVES       35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Entrepreneurship”  by  Mr.  Rahul  Manohar  O  in   online  condolence  meeting  in  prayerful  remembrance
        collaboration with IEDC on 2nd December 2021. A    of Rev. Sr. Mary Loretta CHF, former Principal, HOD,
        webinar on UK higher studies and job opportunities by   and Associate Professor  of Dept.  of Mathematics,
        Mr. Tomy Sebastian M S in association with T & T Global   and Mr. K.P. John, Founder member of our college was
        recruitment Ltd. was held on 5th December, 2021.   conducted on 11th September 2021. Staff Association
        The cell arranged a Seminar on banking orientation in   extended Christmas and New year greetings to
        association with Syllabox on 20th December 2021. A|   His  Excellency,  Bishop  Mar  Pauly  Kannookadan,
        webinar on German Language learning opportunities   Irinjalakuda Diocese, Dr. Sr. Annie Kuriakose CHF,
        in collaboration with Smile German Classes took place   Mother  General  of  Congregation  of  Holy  Family  and
        on 23rd January, 2022. Webinar on career guidance in   Sr. Elsy Kokkat, Provincial and Manager of our college
        association with SkillActz, was held on 6th Feb, 2022.   on 22nd December 2021. Christmas celebration of the
        Campus Recruitment Drives include: Wipro, TCS,     faculty and staff were conducted on 23rd December
        Infosys,  Federal  Bank,  Experion Technologies,  Byju’s   2021. The faculty and staff actively participated in the
        classes, Cognizant Technologies, Zifo R&D solutions,   cultural activities and games as part of the celebration.
        Episource.  Student Development and Training
        Programmes conducted include: Certification course on   WOMEN CELL
        RH124 System Administrator in association with Red
        Hat Academy, IIRS outreach programmes and Infosys   The activities of the year began with a planning session
        springboard certifications.                        and an enrolment process which was conducted in
                                                           online mode. An initial induction programme was held
        REV SR. MARY FRANCO MEMORIAL                       online and the Women Cell activities were coordinated
        EDUCATIONAL CHARITABLE TRUST                       through a WhatsApp group. The activities of the year
                                                           were initiated  by  the principal  Dr Sr Asha Therese
        Plus Two students who were identified as eligible were   as  she  launched  the  three  new  clubs  of  Women  Cell
        awarded Rs.15,000 for their study. Sports students   named  Maneeshi-for  academic  training,  Rasika-
        who excelled in their disciplines received a prize of Rs.   for  empowerment  through  culture  and  Arpitha-for
        20,000/-. Nursing students were given a prize of Rs.   community connect. Dr. Mary Matilda, an eminent
        18,000 /-.                                         academician and mind power led a seminar on “Gender
                                                           Awareness During Pandemic Times” which was held on
                                                           6/12/21. 46 students attended the programme under
        SPECIAL PROGRAMME                                  the banner of Maneeshi. The second activity held on
                                                           15/12/21 by Rasika, ensured student participation
                                                           by staging an act that facilitated the concept of
        The activities of the committee started off on 31st
        July 2021 with the online reception to the Hon. Higher   women empowerment through artistic expression. 45
        Education Minister, Dr. R. Bindhu. The Principal, Dr   students participated in team events and won prizes.
        Sr  Asha  Therese,  presided  over  the  function.  The   On January 5, 2022, Club Arpitha of the Women Cell
        Municipal Chairperson, Ms Sonia Giri, Ward Councillor   organized an invited lecture on the topic “Gender Issues
        Ms Feny, the retired faculty of the college and the   in Contemporary Kerala” which was attended by 43
        college alumnae attended  the programme. The festal   student members. The lecture was by Dr. Unnimol Biju,
        day of the principal, Dr Sr Asha Therese, was celebrated   Counselor, Snehitha Gender Help Desk, Kudumbasree
        on 7th September 2021. Various cultural programmes   Mission, Kottayam. Women Cell and Darpan Woman
        were arranged from different departments under the   Study Centre  jointly edited a book with ISBN number,
        leadership of the student coordinator, Anjaleena Biju.   titled  “Beyond a Thing of Beauty:  An Enquiry into the
        The First UG Induction Programme was inaugurated on   Life of Indian Woman” which is a collection of select
        4th October 2021. Dr. Sr Asha Therese presided over the   research articles on women. An online course on
        function and Dr Asha Thomas addressed the gathering.   Menstural Awareness and Hygiene by collaborating
        The Orientation Talk was delivered by Ms. Billijin K.I,   with Venture Village, Kochi was conducted in the month
        Motivational Speaker, Trainer, and Hypnotherapist.   of February.
        Initiation  Ceremony  of  first  year  P.G,  students  was
        conducted on 25th October 2021. The Orientation    WOMEN STUDY CENTRE
        Lecture was given by Adv. Meera V Menon.
                                                           The  centre  hosted  a  talk  on plastic-free  menstruation
        STAFF ASSOCIATION                                  on 16th November 202, collaborating with the Women
                                                           Cell of the college and Venture Village. The session was
        Staff Association celebrated Onam on 17th August   handled by the resource person Ms. Reshma Chandran,
        2021in both offline and online mode. The feast day of   Programme Manager, Venture Village. Mr. Anil Balan and
        our dear Principal Dr. Asha Therese was celebrated on   a faculty from Venture Village were present during the
        7th September 2021. An offline meeting was conducted   session. A clear idea about the usage of sanitary napkins
        in the Research block one day ahead of the feast day. An   and its dangerous effects  on environment, different
                                                           types of menstrual products  like Tampons, especially
           36   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[a detailed review on the positive sides of the usage of   traditional cookery show was conducted from 22nd
        Cloth Pads and Menstrual Cups through which we could   November 2021 to 29th  November 2021. Christmas
        bring out plastic-free menstruation was also provided   celebration  was  on  21st  December  2021  jointly  with
        at the session. The session through the google platform   Govt. Degree College, Shahpur in an online mode.
        concluded with an interactive session. Darpan Woman
        Study Centre and Women Cell jointly edited a book
        with ISBN number, titled  “Beyond a Thing of Beauty:     IEDC (INNOVATION & ENTREPRENEURSHIP
        An Enquiry into the Life of Indian Woman” which is a   DEVELOPMENT CENTRE),
        collection of select research articles on women.
                                                           ED  (ENTREPRENEURSHIP DEVELOPMENT
        RUSA – RASHTRIYA UCHCHATAR SHIKSHA                 CLUB)
        ABHIYAN
                                                           Innovation and Entrepreneurship Development Centre
                                                           (IEDC) started its activities for the academic year 2021-
        Our college has been Included in the list of RUSA Funded   2022 with a webinar entitled “Sambhav- A National
        Institutions by the Central and State Governments   level awareness Programme on entrepreneurship”,
        since 2018. A fund of Rupees Two Crores was allotted   jointly organized by IEDC and the Ministry of MSME,
        to our Institution which is a combined fund of both,   Government of India on 18th November 2021.  In
        the Central Government Share of Rupees 120 Lakhs   connection with Women Entrepreneur’s Day 2021
        and the State Government Share of Rupees 80 Lakhs.   an intercollegiate online Cartoon making competition
        There is a PMU and BOG for monitoring the utilization   was arranged in association with BBA department on
        of  funds and  giving  suggestions  regarding  the  works   25th November 2021. An invited e-talk was arranged
        done using the RUSA Fund. The Two Crore fund has   on the topic “Creating a Road Map for Student
        three heads of allocation as per the instructions from   Entrepreneurship” by Mr. Rahul Manohar O, IEDC Nodal
        RUSA SPD. Rupees One Crore was used to construct a   officer, Christ engineering college, Irinjalakuda on 2nd
        new academic Block. Rupees 43 Lakhs was allotted for   December 2021. IEDC in association with the computer
        Renovation and Upgradation Works in the Colleges Such   science department organized an idea pitching contest
        as Implementing Rain Water Harvesting System, Fixing   “IDEATHON 2K21” on 9th December 2021. In order
        Solar Panels, Implementation of Near Line Telepresence   to inculcate the spirit of innovation and a mindset of
        Room, and for Library Automation. The final Component   problem-solving  in young minds, IEDC in association
        is Purchase which includes funding of Rupees 57 Lakhs   with the Computer Science department organized a
        and is allotted to the purchase of Computers, Sports   one day ‘HACKATHON 2021’ on 9th December 2021.
        Equipment, Lab Equipment, and Books. As of now, a   A  three-day  hands-on  workshop  on  ‘Fabrication  of
        total work of Rupees 125 Lakhs has been completed and   Battery Eliminator with charger’ was conducted from
        other projects are progressing.
                                                           11th December to 14th December 2021 in collaboration
                                                           with the Dept. of Physics The main objective of the
                                                           workshop was to manufacture a Battery eliminator
        EBSB  - EK BHARAT SHRESTHA  BHARAT                 with a charger along with developing electronic skills
        CLUB                                               in the participants. In order to bring an environment-
                                                           friendly attitude and to avoid the one-time use of plastic
         As a part of the 75th Independence Day celebrations,   pens  IEDC  and  the  Department  of  Economics  jointly
        the NSS units of the college and EBSB club jointly   organized  A  Hands-on  training  session  on  Paper  Pen
        organized  a  webinar  through  Google  meet  on 14th   Making on 20th December 2021.
        August  2021  under  the  initiative  ‘Azadi  Ka  Amrut   IEDC in association with the MCJ department organized
        Mahotsav’. The speaker was Dr. Brahma Nand Sharma,   a  two-day  international  film  festival  related  to
        Director of cultural activities, Uttarakhand. The club in   Innovation on 21st and 22nd December 2021. Two films
        association with NSS, and Avinashilingam Institute for   were screened to promote the theme of innovation:
        Home Science and Higher Education for Women jointly   The Joy (2015) and The Social Network (2010).
        organized a video presentation through Google meet   IEDC in collaboration with the Dept. of Commerce
        on 15th August 2021’ on Azadi Ka Amrut Mahotsav’.   organized a “Santa’s Surprise Exhibition cum Sale”
        As a part of National Unity Day celebrations, the EBSB   on 22nd December. A two-day online workshop was
        club and Field Outreach Bureau, Shimla, Himachal   organized on the topic “Web design for beginners” by
        Pradesh jointly organized a webinar through Google   Ms. Sherin Jose T, Assistant professor, and Head, Dept.
        meet  on  27th  October  2021.  The  aim  of  the  talk  was   of Mathematics on 22nd and 23rd December 2021.
        to familiarize the participants about the culture and   IEDC in association with the IIC organized a one-day
        heritage of the pairing states Kerala and Himachal   workshop on mobile app development by Ms. Magniya
        Pradesh. The resource persons were Prof. Mridula   Davis and Anand Antony, Christ College of Engineering,
        Sharda,  HOD,  Political  Science,  HP  University,  and   Irinjalakuda on 28th December 2021. To give awareness
        Dr. Binu T. V., EBSB Coordinator, St. Joseph’s College   about digital marketing techniques and rules, IEDC
        (Autonomous), Irinjalakuda. A one-week-long online   in collaboration with the BBA department organized

                                                                                          WEAVES       37]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[an online workshop “Digital  Marketing” on 29th  PTWA
        December 2021. A motivational ‘I-talk’ was arranged
        with  MR.  Ajish  Ayikkarapadi,  Mobile  finger  artist  and   PTWA executive meeting was conducted on 15th
        proofreader, Calicut university on 30th December   September 2021 to discuss the procedure and plan for
        2021.  IEDC in collaboration with the District Industries   UG and PG admission. PTWA organized an orientation
        Centre (DIC), Thrissur organized an orientation session   class on the topic ‘Role of Parents in Exploration of
        “Samrambakathva Bhodavalkarana Silpasala” on 7th   Identity in Youth’ by Sr. Rose Jose CHF for the parents
        January 2022. In connection with National Youth Day,   of I DC students on 6th October 2021. An online PTA
        IEDC collaborated with the Dept. of Economics to   meeting was held for all UG and PG classes in the month
        organize a collage-making competition on 12th January   of August 2021.
        2022.
                                                           IQAC  - INTERNAL  QUALITY  ASSURANCE
        IIC- INSTITUTION’S INNOVATION COUNCIL              CELL


        International  Webinar  on  Thermal Batteries  for   The Internal Quality Assurance Cell of St. Joseph’s
        Renewable Energy Storage was conducted on 17th     College implemented plans and organized activities to
        September 2021. The cell conducted a Cartoon Making   augment the quality and ensure excellence at all levels of
        Competition in connection with Women Entrepreneurs’   the college. IQAC played a significant role in combining
        Day 2021 on the 25th of November. A webinar on     various  inputs  for  participating  and  submitting  the
        Creating a Road Map for Student Entrepreneurship   documents required for NIRF rankings. The IQAC cell
        was held on December 2, 2021. Hackathon 2021:      spearheaded the application and facilitated the NIRF
        ‘Smart Thinking for Smart Society’ was arranged on¬   ranking of the college, and the institution was able to
        9th December 2021. A hands-on workshop on Battery   secure a score band of 100-150. Under the leadership
        Eliminator Assembly was conducted on 11th December   of IQAC, the college successfully participated in the
        2021. Boot Camp for Young Innovators, Workshops to   National Atal Ranking of Institutions on Innovation
        introduce Digital marketing, and making Paper pens   Achievements (ARIIA) and was able to be recognized in
        were also organized in the month of December.      the band, “Performer.” IQAC was capable of directing the
                                                           departments in completing the survey conducted by the
        E-LEARNING CELL                                    prestigious News Magazine, India Today, and secured the
                                                           honour of being ranked as the 72nd India’s Best Science
        The college purchased G-suite for the effective    Colleges. Outcome Based Education (OBE) is becoming
        conduct of online teaching and an enhanced e-learning   a de facto standard in India, with the mandate from
        experience. For smooth streaming of online educational   regulatory bodies. IQAC has aided in implementing OBE
        and cocurricular programs in social media like YouTube   in association with the examination section and IPSR
        and  Facebook,  a  zoom  subscription  was  purchased.   solutions. deQ OBE software was used for this purpose
        Using media  Lab, the  cell produced  more than 60   that helped in defining the basic PO’s, PSO’s and CO’s;
        online  lectures.  The  installation  of  interactive  panels   calculating the level of attainment, and other additional
        in  one  classroom  of  every  department  has  been  done   features that assisted in slashing down manual labour
        successfully for a virtual and interactive classroom   and time of the faculty. IQAC has initiated faculty and
        experience.                                        student  exchange  programmes with  several  reputed
                                                           institutions and organizations to enrich the grounds of
        MINORITY CELL                                      academic and professional experience for our students
                                                           and teachers. The timely submission of AQAR was yet
        The Directorate of Minority Welfare under the Govt.   another step taken by IQAC during the year.
        of Kerala selected St. Joseph’s College, Irinjalakuda as
        a premarital counselling centre in the year 2021-22.  ADMISSION
        It was inaugurated on 15th October 2021 by Dr. A. B.
        Moideenkutty, Director, (DMW). Premarital counselling   Admission to the UG and PG programmes for the
        is specialized therapy, for girls above 18 years of age. It is   year  2021-22  was  done  online  via  Linways  Admission
        usually provided by a marriage and family therapist and   Management System. In addition to the sanctioned
        provides guidance to all who are considering a long-term   strength,  marginal  increase,  as  per  the  University
        commitment such as marriage. It helps persons of any   Circular, was taken into consideration due to increased
        gender, race, or religion to identify and address potential   demand for Admission. Covid Protocol was followed
        areas  of  conflict  in  the  relationship.  The  classes  were   throughout the admission procedures  in the college.
        organized from 16th November to 1st December 2021   Admission started from the month of July and was
        in five batches, each consisting of minimum 50 students.   completed in the month of November. 965 Students to 23
        Eight resource persons took classes as per the allotment   Graduate courses and 248 students to 15 Postgraduate
        from Directorate.                                  courses were admitted.



           38   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[EXAMINATION/RESULTS
                                                           GENERAL SECRETARY
        Dr. Asha Thomas stepped down after 3 years of her term   LAKSHMI
        of office as Controller of Examinations. Dr. Kavitha O.   (III DC MATHS)
        took over as the new COE. The pending end-semester
        examinations  of the last  academic year due  to the   JOINT – SECRETARY
        COVID  pandemic  were  completed  successfully  by   SANGEERTHANA VINOD
        September 2021 and the results were published on   (II DC PSYCOLOGY)
        time.  Covid  -19  Special  exams  were  introduced  and   UNIVERSITY UNION COUNCILORS
        conducted successfully along with the special exams for   ANJANA K P
        sports, NSS, and NCC students. Grace mark distribution   (III DC HISTORY)
        for sports NSS and NCC students was successfully
        completed. End-semester examinations were scheduled   AMEESHA WILSON
        for the current academic year. Two internal exams for   (III DC BIO TECHNOLOGY)
        UG and PG students in each semester were conducted.
        Odd Semester examinations were completed for both   FINE ARTS SECRETARY
        UG and PG programs except first semesters. Results of   RANJANA P H
        odd semester examinations of UG programs published.  (II DC ENGLISH)

        PASS PERCENTAGE FOR UG 2018 ADMISSION              STUDENT EDITOR
        90.88%                                             MELVY XAVIER
                                                           (II DC ENGLISH)
        PASS PERCENTAGE FOR PG 2019 ADMISSION
        81.42%
                                                           GENERAL CAPTAIN
        COLLEGE UNION ELECTION                             NANDANA K M
                                                           (III DC B COM)
        The college union election for the academic year
        2021-22 was held on 13-01-2022. The process began   I DC REPRESENTATIVE
        by  providing  notification  on  the  college  notice  board.   ASWATHY
        The  preliminary  electoral  role  and  the  final  electoral   (I DC MATHS)
        roll were published on the day of the election. Results
        were announced by the principal after counting on   II DC REPRESENTATIVE
        the same day. General secretary, joint secretary and   SHAMIYA S
        student editor were unanimously elected. Polling was   (II DC CHEMISTRY(SF))
        conducted for the other posts. Two nominations were
        filed for the chairman’s post and three for the post of   III DC REPRESENTATIVE
        vice-chairperson.  Four  nominations  each  were  filed   ARDHRA K S
        for the posts of Fine Arts Secretary and UUC. Two   (III B COM FINANCE A (SF))
        nominations  were  filed  for  the  General  Captain  post.
        Three students competed for the IIIDC representative   PG REPRESENTATIVE
        post, seven for the IIDC representative, eight for the   GAYATHRI JAYAN
        IDC representative, and two for the PG representative.   (I PG BIO TECHNOLOGY)
        Each candidate was asked to remit a fee of ₹50 for filing
        nominations and receipts were kept for the same. The   VIII. CLUBS
        filed  nominations  were  subjected  to  scrutiny  before
        polling.
                                                           NATURE CLUB
        The list of the elected members is as follows:
                                                           Nature Club conducted a training session in micro-green
                                                           cultivation and micro green cuisines. Nature club, along
                                                           with the Dept. of Botany, arranged a training programme
        CHAIRPERSON                                        for the students to make biodegradable grow bags
        ANJALEENA BIJU                                     out of water hyacinth, which is a weed interrupting
        (III DC ENGLISH)                                   water transport in the backwaters of Kerala. A survey,
                                                           Surveillance of water hyacinth in Thrissur district was
        VICE- CHAIRPERSON                                  conducted in collaboration with NSS and Green Kerala
        ANNA ROSE DAVIS                                    Mission.
        (III DC MATHS)


                                                                                          WEAVES       39]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[SPEAK ENGLISH CLUB                                 staff members. A body checkup for staff and students
                                                           with Body Composition Analyzer was held. The Principal
        The Speak English Club aims to improve the English   Dr. Sr. Asha Therese inaugurated this programme.
        verbal skills of the students through training sessions   Dr.Sakeer Hussain, Director, Department of Physical
        and competitions. Restituto Ecosystem, an online   Education, University of Calicut inaugurated ‘Shape up
        Recitation competition was conducted to celebrate   4 life’ project. This project is for developing fitness of the
        World Environment Day, in collaboration with the Dept.   students, faculty and staff. Another project ‘Body Mass
        of English. The programme was virtual and received   Index (BMI)’ point was inaugurated by the Principal, Dr.
        enthusiastic participation from students. The candidates   Sr.Asha Theres. This project is to understand the BMI
        composed and recited poems on the theme ‘Restituto   of faculty, staff  and students  of the college.  Another
        Ecosystem’. Ms. Anju Antony , Assistant Professor ,   project was ‘Talk series’, an awareness programme about
        Department  of English was the faculty coordinator   health for students ‘Class room stretching’ posters in the
        and the student coordinators were Hajara.P.Y, Aayisha   class rooms and staff rooms were displayed to spread
        Nazrin and Melvy Xavier. On account of Reading Week,   awareness about right body postures and movements.
        the Department of English hosted “Reading Reels”,
        an inter-collegiate online Book Review contest and   Conclusion
        Quiz competition with the Speak English Club and The
        Central Library of St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous),   As I conclude, allow me to bow in humble adoration
        Irinjalakuda. Nearly 20 entries on Book Review were   before the grace of Lord Almighty for showing us the
        received from the vibrant participants. The winners   right path even in these challenging times. May I express
        were rewarded with cash prizes and the participants of   sincere gratitude to the entire Josephite family for your
        the online Quiz received certificates.
                                                           dedication  and  resilience  in  performing  your  trusted
                                                           duties. May I pray for the perpetual patronage of St.
                                                           Joseph in all our future endeavours. I humbly beseech
        ORATORY AND QUIZ CLUB                              the intercession of Saint Mariam Thresia and Venerable
                                                           father  Joseph  Vithayathil  in guiding  us  through  our
        The club organized various discussions on different   frailties. Thank You.
        topics of current relevance in order to develop the
        oratory and quizzing skills of students. Our students
        participated and won prizes in various inter-collegiate
        competitions. A regional elocution competition was
        conducted in association with NSS unit of our college.
        Anagha Johnson of III BA English secured first prize and
        Anjaleena Biju of III BA English secured the second prize
        in district level declamation contest on ‘Patriotism and
        Nation Building’, organized by Nehru Yuva Kendra as
        part of the Republic Day Celebrations, 2022. Anjaleena
        Biju participated in ‘Keralotsavam’, the youth festival
        organized by the
        Government of Kerala, and won first prize in the district-
        level elocution competition.
        BIODIVERSITY CLUB


        In connection with the ‘International Day for Biological
        Diversity’, the club in association with the Dept. of
        Zoology organized an online Quiz Competition –
        ‘BioDive 21’ for the public on 22/05/21. The club
        members observed and recorded the biodiversity in
        their locality during the monsoon and post-monsoon
        periods. An intercollegiate PowerPoint presentation
        competition on the topic ‘Faunal Diversity in Wetlands
        of Kerala’ was organized in association with the Dept. of
        Zoology.

        HEALTH AND FITNESS CLUB


        ‘Fit 4 Life’ project was launched to promote a health and
        fitness  culture  among  students  as  well  as  faculty  and

           40   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[VICE PRINICIPALS                                  SELF-FINANCING
                                                                        COORDINATOR





















         Rev. Sr. Blessy CHF             Dr. Sr. Elaiza CHF               Dr. Sr. Rose Bastin CHF






                                                AWARDEES





















             Ms. Andrea Varghese        Dr. Binu  T.V         Ms. Elizabeth         Isha Farha Quraishy
             Teacher of the Year     Researcher of the     Researcher of the        Alumna of the Year
                                       Year - Science       Year - Commerce




              NEW RESEARCH                                             Ph.D. AWARDEE

                       GUIDES
















           Dr. Gigi Poulose      Dr. Naijil George                          Dr. Linet Sebastin


                                                                                          WEAVES       41]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[42   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[UNION



                                                                               AGNI




                                                                               2021-22

                                               Anjaleena Biju
                                               Chairperson























           Anna Rose Davis              Lakshmi            Sangeerthana Vinod              Anjana K.P
            Vice Chairperson        General Secretary          Joint Secretary                UUC

















          Ameesha Wilson               Ranjana P.H               Melvy Xavier             Nandana J M
                 UUC                 Fine Arts Secretary         Student Editor           General Captain

















                Aswathy                 Shamya                   Ardra K.S              Gayathri Jayan
            I DC Representative    II DC Representative      III DC Representative      PG Representative




                                                                                          WEAVES       43]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[44   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[WEAVES       45]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[AISWARYA            ALEENA            ANAGHA           ANJALEENA           ANJALY
                 MADHU             PRAKASH            V. GOSH             BIJU              JOSE
















                 ANSHINI            ARDRA              ARDRA            ASWATHY           ATHULYA
               RAHAMATH V. P     NADNAKUMAR             K. M            PRADEEP              B. P















                 ATHULYA            DRISHYA          FAJAR K. R         FATHIMA         FEBINA MARY
                  BENNY                K                                   T. M            JACOB














                GAYATHRI            GRACE           HASEENA V.S          ANGELA             JINCY
                    P. S             PHILIP                              SUNNY               C. J


           46   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[JISMY            JYOTHIKA        KRISHNAPRIYA          MITHRA            NAJA V
                VARGHESE            SEKHAR               T.L              N. M
















                NASLA V.A           NIKITA          SHAROL M.A            SIBA          SIRIN ASHRAF
                                     T. DAS                             BHASEER















                SIVAPRIYA           SMIJA M            SRUTHI           SUHAILA            ARRYA
                   V. B                                 T. A             SALAM               E. S














                GAYATHRI             SONA            SURYASREE           ATHIRA           AISWARYA
                 UDAYAN               T. V           SUNANDAN              DAS               K. V














                         SREELAKSHMI          APARNA            JYOTSNA            JASTINA
                              T. S              N.S              JAMES              JAISON


                                                                                          WEAVES       47]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[A SAGE  SAGA








                                             Situated in the heart of Irinjalakuda,
                                             St. Joseph’s College (Autonomous) is a college for women affiliated to
                                             the University of Calicut and managed by the St. Joseph’s Educational
                                             Society of the Congregation of the Holy Family. Saint Mother Mariam
                                             Thresia, a pioneer in the field of family apostolate who was canonized
                                             on 13 October 2019 prompted the visionary enthusiasm that resulted
                                             in the congregation’s establishment in 1914. A significant moment in
                                             the Congregation’s history was the College’s establishment in 1964
                                             under the capable direction of the late Mother Josephine, the Superior
                                             General. The College, founded in response to the rising demand for
                                             higher  education  among  young  women,  obtained  reaccreditation
                                             from the National Assessment and Accreditation Council (NAAC) in
                                             October 2013 with an “A” Grade.

                                             “Not many know that our college was once a part of Christ College.
                                             Till the year 1963, girls who wished to pursue college education were
                                             increasing but did not have a college to go to. Meanwhile, the male
                                             students had the facility of Christ College. With huge buildings on a
                                             hill accompanied by football and tennis courts and the NCC cadets
                                             marching to the rhythm of drums and fife, they were being pampered.
                                             But  the young women  had  to  trek  too  far  to  places  just  to  seek
                                             education. As an answer to all the worries, in 1963, a committee was
                                             formed, funds were raised and after approaching Rev. Father Gabriel,
                                             the Principal of Christ College of that time, a “women’s section was
                                             allowed  for  Christ  College.  The  academic  year  had  started  and  the
                                             college  committee  was frantically  searching  for  a building in which
                                             to start the “Women’s section”. After finding a building in the heart of
                                             the town which had lately been used as a post office, classes began.
                                             Finding  that  the students  were  not  properly  housed,  Mr. K P John
                                             offered his extensive coconut grove on the crest of the town to be
                                             used as the campus for the new college.”

                                                                                ~The College Historiographer
























           48   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[A SAGE  SAGA










        The  college  is an  embodiment  of  the  ambitions  of  visionaries  Saint
        Mother Mariam Thresia (Foundress, Congregation of the Holy Family)
        and Venerable Fr. Joseph Vithayathil (Co-Founder of Congregation of
        the Holy Family). The institution blossomed during the Christmas of
        1964, with the architectural prowess of E. G Panikkar. The college was
        helmed by the able and zealous Late Mother Josephine. Thus, started
        the journey of St. Joseph’s College as a pioneer of women’s education
        in Kerala.

        Over  the  years  the  college  has  found  pride  in  many  laudable
        milestones. The committed and consistent work of the administration
        assisted the college establishment in getting an ‘A’ in the third cycle
        of accreditation by NAAC in 2013. Besides, the college also clinched
        the Rajiv Gandhi Golden Award for Best Women’s College in 2015.
        And on top of it, the college got Autonomous status in 2016 and the
        status of Potential for Excellence by the UGC in April 2016. A streak of
        awards like Calicut University Best Sports College and Best Women’s
        Aggregate Championship, and the like added many accolades to St.
        Joseph’s  glory. The  college  was placed  in the 42nd position in the
        NIRF ranking of 2018. Furthermore, the college bagged the Overall
        Championship in Kerala College Games in 2022.
        At present, the college is regarded as one of Kerala’s top institutions
        for  women’s higher  education.  The  robust  alumni  organization
        maintains  an  extensive  informal  network  among  itself  and  an
        incredibly  strong  connection  with the  college.  They are dispersed
        all across the world and occupy a variety of jobs, including those of
        housewives,  educators,  academics,  engineers,  researchers,  political
        trailblazers, and many more. The former students do make academic
        and  financial  contributions  to  the  comprehensive  development  of
        their college. St. Joseph’s College is standing tall as an answer to the
        ever-increasing  demand  for  higher  education  among  young women
        in today’s society. The college becomes increasingly significant as a
        result of its continuing contribution to the empowerment of women
        through higher education.





















                                                                                          WEAVES       49]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Hangout    Spots
























                                                                           SPOT : Football Ground, Behind
                                                                           Self-Financing Building



     SPOT : Garden, In front of the Main Building

     These moments which brought all of us togeth-                                           SPOT : Outdoor
     er into a single frame are my favourite! Maybe                                          GYM and Adventure
     this isn't vibrant enough because of some smiles                                        Park
     which are missing out in this picture but still….                                       With the crazy,
     Looking back at the first day, am sure none of us                                       same ‘vibe' people
     knew how it was going to be in the next three                                           we found here, we
     years… It wasn't about leaving behind what                                              lived these moments
     we had, but opening our hearts to accept and                                            which will, like
     appreciate the changes. From school to cam-                                             anything, become
     pus, what all we had to leave behind, whatever                                          memories… But
     changes happened to us, I hope none of us felt                                          when we reminisce
     lonely. I hope our smiles could light up each                                           those memories in
     other's days…                                                                           the future, I hope
                                                                                             we don't have any
                                                                                             regrets and can smile
                                                                                             at the times we spent
                                                                                             together instead of
                                                                                             being sad about the
                                                                                             things we didn't get
                                                                                             to do together…














         SPOT : Garden, In front of the Main Building
         To the beautiful girls of Finance (A), Thank you for being the
         kindest buddies for each other… For the seasons that passed
         and those to come, I wish we can be those comfy, warm pillows
         and be there for each other as always. The stories we told are   Your Friend,
         beautiful and those yet to tell, are more beautiful than ever
                                                                    Third Year B.Com Finance (A) (SF)


           50   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Hangout    Spots

































            Corona drew people apart. Especially students. Online classes, work
            from home all these made everyone introverts. College life is known
            as one of the most memorable years of one's life. But for us , the first
            year of college was just a forgettable event. Mobile phones and
            laptops became our class rooms. At last we came to the college as Second year
            students. And then, what attracted us the most aren’t the  classes.

            But it is:
             " The kiss of the sun for pardon
             The song of the birds for mirth
             You are nearer God's heart in a garden
            Than anywhere else on earth. "

            Yes, The elegant garden attracted us than anything else in the
            college. It bonded us again with people. When corona made us apart ,
            the garden pulled us close. It was the only place on college where we
            found the liking of our soul and a start for our friendship. In between
            the four walls of the classes we found people and not friends. But
            those botanical and mystical gardens enclosed us with a special bond
            which we call as FRIENDSHIP.                                      Annapoorna Boban
                                                                             Ananya Santhosh
                                                                             Krishnanjaly K.
                                                                             Bsc. Botany



















                        SPOT : Script Garden

                                                         SPOT : Open Gym and Adventure Park WEAVES     51]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[52   WEAVES








































            a complete solution for Fashion & Beauty]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[GRACEFUL METAMORPHOSIS



                                                          When past knocks on your door
                                                          Asking for its debts
                                                          You will be picking coins
                                                          A handful , that you loose midway .
                                                          We call ourselves Josephites
                                                          Varnished in hues of pinks
                                                          Embraces you in warmth
                                                          A home with holy spirits .
                                                          From one end of your dupatta
                                                          You link to next
                                                          And to next
                                                          A sisterhood you never dreamed off .
                                                          For Josephites is for women
                                                          The kindred witches
                                                          That blazes like sun
                                                          Taught by humble teachers
                                                          To reclaim power she yearns for
                                                          A classroom on
                                                          Feminism, modernism and humanity,
                                                          Were thoughts like horses
                                                          Wild like wind
                                                          Reigned lands it went.
                                                          Three years of life
                                                          A million strings of memories.
                                                          To walk through the same footprints
                                                          Is a sweet wish on my growing years
                                                          A goodbye worth of tears.


                                                                                    - Krishna Ramachandran M
                                                                                               III DC English


















                                                                                          WEAVES       53








































 a complete solution for Fashion & Beauty]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[54   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[WEAVES       55]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Stalia Sabu
                                                                               III DC BSc, Psycology


           56   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Retiree
        tUm.kn.B\okv sI.hn
                                                                  skâv tPmk^vkv tImtfPnsâ kmcYn F¶
                                                                 henb D¯chmZn¯zw hnizkvXXtbmsS
                                                                 \ndthänb knÌdpsS HutZymKnI PohnXw
        temI¯nse Gähpw kp{][m\amb tPmen A[ym]\
                                                                 ChnsS  Bcw`n¨Xv  2005 sk]väw_dnemWv.
        amsW¶pw       A[ym]IÀ       aäpffhcpsS      PohnXs¯
                                                                 A[ym]nI, tImtfPv tlmÌÂ  hmÀU³,
        Pzen¸n¡p¶hcmsW¶pw {]kvXmhn¨ tUm.F ]n sP
                                                                 kpthmfPn hIp¸v ta[mhn, dntkÀ¨v ssKUv,
        A_vZpÄ Iemansâ Bib§Ä¡v kz´w PohnX-
                                                                 sshkv {]n³kn¸Â  F¶o  \neIfnseÃmw
        ¯neqsS \ndw ]IÀ¶ hyXykvXamb Hcp   A[ym]nI
                                                                 D¯chmZn¯zt_m[t¯mSpw hnizkvXXtbm-
        bmWv knÌÀ Bj. ssZhnIamb ]²XnIÄ X¶neqsS
                                                                 Spw tkh\w sNbvX knÌÀ C¶v
        \n-dthds«sb¶ {]mÀ°\ Hcp sNdp]p©ncnbnÂ
                                                                 {]n³kn¸Â  F¶ ]Zhn Gähpw at\mlcambn
        ebn¸n¨v Xsâ IÀ½ aWvUe¯nÂ  FfnatbmsS
                                                                 Ae¦cn¨p sImï-pXs¶ Cu hÀjw ChnsS
        hym]cn¨ hyànXzw. s]¬Icp¯v ]n¶nesÃ¶v
                                                                 \n¶pw hncan¡p¶p. IrXy\njvTbpw, efnXambn
        A\p\nanjw sXfnbn¨v ap³\ncbntebv¡v IpXn¡p¶
                                                                 ]Tn¸n¡m\pff Ignhpw, Ip«nItfmSpff IcpX-
                                                                 epw knÌdns\ F¡mehpw hnZymÀ°n\nIfpsS
                                                                 {]nb¦cnbm¡n amän. {]mIvSn¡Â  ¢mÊpI
                                                                 fnÂ  knÌdnsâ ssIhg¡hpw, IrXyXbpw
                                                                 kq£vaXbpw FÃm A[ym]IÀ¡pw {]tNmZ\
                                                                 hpw, amXrIbpamWv.
                                                                 hnZymÀ°n\nIfpsS ka{K hyànXz hnIk\w
                                                                 e£yw h¨v {]hÀ¯n¨ncp¶ knÌÀ AhÀ¡v
                                                                 Htc kabw Kpcphpw A½bpw
                                                                 kplr¯pambn         cq]m´cw      {]m]n¡p¶Xv
                                                                 XnI¨pw Ahnizk\obhpw    AÛpXIchpam
                                                                 bncp¶p. kl{]hÀ¯Isc   _lpam\n¡pI
                                                                 bpw kz´w IpSpw_mwK§sft¸mse kvt\
                                                                 ln¡pIbpw sNbvXncp¶ knÌÀ Hcpabv¡pw
                                                                 sFIy¯n\pw henb hne Iev]n¨   hyànbm
                                                                 bncp¶p. emfnXy¯nepw kuayXbnepw
                                                                 Hfn¸n¨ anIhpä Imcy£aX, D¯chmZnXz§Ä
                                                                 im´XtbmsS \ndthäm³ t]m¶Xmbncp¶p.
                                                                 kwKoXs¯bpw {]IrXntbbpw HtcbfhnÂ
                                                                 kvt\ln¡p¶ knÌÀ IcpWbpsSbpw IcpX-
                                                                 ensâbpw apJambn tImtfPnâ CS\mgCIfnÂ
                                                                 k©-cn¨ncp¶p. Bgamb ssZhhnizmkhpw
                                                                  {]hÀ¯\¯neq¶nb kaÀ¸Whpw sImï-v
                                                                 GsäSp¯ D¯chmZnXz§Ä {]XnIqe kml-
                                                                 Ncy§fnÂ  t]mepw   kaNn¯X ssIhnSmsX
                                                                 \ndthänsb¶v       knÌdn\v       A`nam\n¡mw.
                                                                 XpSÀ¶pff       {]hÀ¯\         taJeIfnseÃmw
                                                                 ssZh¯nsâ          Ir]bpw       A\p{Klhpw
                                                                 knÌdns\ hgn \S¯s«. C\nbpw At\
                                                                 IÀ¡v shfn¨amIm³, km´z\amIm³ ssZhw
                                                                 A\p{Klw sNmcnbs«, kam[m\hpw
                                                                 kt´mjhpw \ndª dn«bÀsaâv PohnXw
                                                                 Biwkn¡p¶p.










                                                                                          WEAVES       57]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[Retiree












































        tUm.enk½ tPm¬


        hmg¡pf¯n\Sp¯v Imh¡mSv F¶ {Kma¯nÂ  \n¶pw h¶v skâv tPm^vkv tImtfPnÂ
        kvt\l kpKÔw ]c¯nb kvt\lkq\amWv tUm.enk½ tPm¬. amXrklPamb kvt\l
        `mh§tfmsS F¶pw \ap¡v ap¶nse¯p¶ anÊv Cu Iemeb¯nse lnµn Un¸mÀ«vsaânsâ
        kmcYyw Gsd kt´mjt¯msS GsäSp¡pIbpw at\mlcambn \ndthäpIbpw sNbvXp. Hmtcm hyàn-
        bptSbpw PohnXmhØsb¡pdn¨v ssZh¯n\v IrXyamb ]²Xnbpsï-¶Xn\v hyàamb sXfnhmWv
        ankv enk½. {]o Un{Knbv¡v tijw \gvkn§v taJebntebv¡v t]mIphm\mbncp¶p B{Klsa¦nepw lnµn
        tbmSpff anÊnsâ Xmev]cyw a\Ênem¡nb A[ym]IcpsS amÀ¤\nÀtZia\pkcn¨v ]mem skâv tXmakv
        tImtfPnÂ  \n¶v hnPbIcambn ]T\w ]qÀ¯nbm¡nb ankv enk½ 1989 Â  \½psS Iemeb¯nse
        AwKambn. DuÀÖkzeXbpw {]hÀ¯\ ]mShhpw BßmÀ°Xbpw \ndª Cu hyànXzw 33 \oï-
        hÀj§fmbn Hcp]mSv hnZymÀ°n\nIfnÂ  \· Pzen¸n¨p sImï-ncn¡p¶p. HutZymKnI PohnXhpw
        IpSpw_ PohnXhpw anIthmsS ka\zbn¸n¡p¶Xnepw ASp¡pw Nn«tbmSpw IqsS IÀ½§Ä sN¿p¶
        Xnepw Hcp DZm¯ amXrIbmWv anÊv. Iemeb¯nse A[ym]\ cwK¯pw hnhn[ I½nänIfnse
        {]hÀ¯\§fnepw kvXpXyÀlamb tkh\w Xs¶bmbncp¶p anÊntâXv.
        kl{]hÀ¯Iscbpw hnZymÀ°n\nIsfbpw kvt\lt¯msS {ihn¡phm\pw ]cnKW\tbmsS s]cpam-
        dphm\pw Gsd {i²n¨ncp¶p. ]mNIw Hcp Iebmbpw Bthiambpw IcpXp¶ ankv enk½ cpNnbpsS
        hIt`Z§Ä  aäpffhÀ¡mbn ]¦psh¡m³ kabw Isï-¯nbncp¶p. XnIª anIthmsS ]mT`mK§Ä
        Ip«nIfntebv¡v F¯n¨ncp¶ So¨À F¶Xp sImï-p Xs¶ tImhnUv almamcnbpsS Ime¯pw anÊnsâ
        Hm¬sse³ ¢mÊpIÄ ]ptcmKan¨ncp¶p. B[ymßnIambn iàamb \ne]mSpff, a\pjykvt\lnbmb,
        IÀ½\ncXbpw {Intbäohpamb anÊv enk½bv¡v hn{ian¡pI km[yaÃ.
        {]iwk\obhpw A\p`h k¼t¯dnbXpamb Cu amXrIm[y]nIbpsS A`mhw Iemeb¯n\v henb
        \jvSw Xs¶bmIpw. a\pjykvt\lhpw kmaqlnI tkh\hpw ]mNI Iebpw CgtNÀ¶ ankv
        enk½bpsS dn«bÀsaâv PohnXw kÀtÆizcsâ Ir]bmbn  aäpffhÀ¡v Hcp km´z\ km¶n[yambn
        amds« F¶v Biwkn¡p¶p. FÃm \·Ifpw {]mÀ°\Ifpw t\cp¶p.
           58   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Retiree



















































        anÊnÊv tPmbvkn kn hn


        ZoÀLamb 36 hÀj§Ä Cu Iemeb¯nÂ  Pzen¨p \n¶ncp¶ XymK¯ntâbpw A[zm\¯ntâbpw
        Xncn\mfamWv tPmbvkn tN¨n. {]IrXn caWobamb ]d¸qÀ {Kma¯nÂ  \n¶v 1985 HIvtSm_dnemWv
        HutZymKnIambn skâv tPmk^vkv tImtfPntebv¡v tPmbvknt¨¨n h¶Xv. ChnsS DZzym\¯nepw   Hm^o
        knepw sImtagvkv Un¸mÀ«psaânepambn AÀ¸W t_m[t¯msS tPmen sNbvXv Cu Iemeb¯nsâ
        Hmtcm kv]µ\§fnepw Xsâ PohnX¯nsâ Xmfw ebn¸ns¨Sp¯p. IÀ½ aWvUe¯nse Imcy£aX-
        bpw Dd¨ Xocpam\§Ä FSp¡p¶Xn\pff at\mss[cyhpw FSp¯p ]dtbï- KpW§fmWv. ap¸Xp
        Intemaoädntesd k©cn¨n«msW¦nepw ]e Znhk§fnepw tImtfPnÂ  cmhnse BZyw ImWp¶ apJw
        tPmbvkn tN¨nbptSXmWv. tImtfPv Hm^oknÂ  Ibdns¨Ãp¶htcmSv ]p©ncn¨ apJt¯msS Bh
        iy§Ä tNmZn¨dnªv sN¿phm³ {]tXyIw {i²n¨ncp¶p. efnXamb PohnXssienbpw hn\bm\znXamb
        {]hÀ¯\ coXnbpw tPmbvkn tN¨nsb aäpffhcnÂ  \n¶v hyXykvXam¡p¶p. tImtfPv Nm¸epw
        Iemeb¦W¯nse ]qt´m«hpw hr¯nbmbpw at\mlcambpw Hcp¡n kq£n¨ncp¶ tN¨n ssZh-
        k¶n[nbnÂ  Ccp¶v {]mÀ°n¡m\pff kabhpw Isï-¯pambncp¶p. Xsâ PohnX¯nse henb Hcp
        Imebfhv ChnsSbmbncp¶ tN¨nbv¡v ChnsS FÃmw \ÃXpw {]nbs¸«Xpw Bbncp¶p. IpSpw_sa¶
        t]mse tImtfPns\ kvt\ln¨ncp¶ tPmbvkn tN¨n \µntbmSpw kvt\lt¯mSpw IqSn tPmenbnÂ
        \n¶pw hncan¡pt¼mÄ FÃm \·Ifpw t\cp¶p. Iemebw t\Sn¯¶ \·ItfmSpw A\p`h§tfmSpw
        IrXÚXm]qÀÆw {]Wan¨v tPmbvkn tN¨n hncan¡p¶ Cu thfbnÂ  skâv tPmk^vknÂ  Hcpa
        tbmsS, Hs¶¶ t_m[yt¯msS \nesImffp¶XnÂ  A\nÀÆN\obamb Hcp at\mlmcnXbpsï-¶v
        tPmbvkn tN¨n \t½mSv ]dbmsX ]dbp¶p.

                                                                                          WEAVES       59]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[60   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[WEAVES       61]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[To the Gulmohar!



                                                    To the Gulmohar that majestically towers the college…


                                                     On these concrete benches where your roots crawl,
                                                      The seed of my dream sprouted, and leaves bore.
                                                       I mused on your side where red blossoms bleed,
                                                              It was a grey aura that spread,
                                                               Not white or inky, a balance.
                                                          You, like an Angel with horns on willows,
                                                          Your wand a swish to let happiness drip.
                                                        And the wrinkles that crawled up your trunk
                                                              Shows how I was not the first.
                                                          The ghosts of youths that fed your love
                                                           Will haunt it when memory chuckles.
                                                        The elixir you gave, to which I deepen my lips
                                                 And I will trip, all drunk, when I walk through it all over again.
                                                        On this ground where I tamed my thoughts,
                                                         Where I sat with my pals, when time runs
                                                           Looking for the discussion that roam
                                                               I will let my happiness brood.
                                                                         Hey,
                                                            Gratitude to you and your grandeur
                                                             Where I found me and my youth

                                                                    Aparna Sudheer
                                                                     III DC English










           62   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[EXHAUSTION


                                                                                          Arsha Dinesh Babu
                                                                                           II DC Psychology































        Exhaustion loiters around
        This tubby, sluggish body
        Sometimes holding on to my arms
        To keep going,
        Yet other times spent stuck on a piece of squared tile,
        Too weak to keep going.
        Sleep is a distant, grumpy aunt,
        Who visits around the holidays.
        She sits on an old rusty arm chair,
        All day long, complaining
        About how I fail to take care of myself
        In the absence of her, for my eyes
        Are as dark as that of a gothic witch.
        Exhaustion and Nights are lovers.
        They meet, they romance and they dance.
        They caress their long hair- the latter,
        Jewelled with stars and vapours, while the other…
        Is just griefs and knots.
        Nights seems lustful, even greedy and possessive.
        It sends Sleep away,
        And keeps Exhaustion awake,
        Sucking out every last drop of her spirit,
                                                                Eventually turning her pale and transparent.
                                                                So, at the break of dawn,
                                                                When Nights depart,
                                                                Exhaustion takes its form again.
                                                                Then we lie on the coarse mattress for a while...
                                                                And she looks into my
                                                                eyes, helplesslyBut
                                                                I get up and walk away,
                                                                Dragging poor Exhaustion around through my
                                                                hectic days.

                                                                                          WEAVES       63]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[EUTHANASIA




                                                     I went to meet her on a lazy Sunday afternoon. She was sitting
                                                     on a park bench down the avenue. She seemed bereft of life
                                                     even before I got there, but she was breathing. All along my life
                                                     I've seen her sitting on this same old bench, staring at the end of
                                                     the road as if waiting for someone. I sat beside her as softly as
                                                     possible.
                                                     She sighed.
                                                     "You don't have weekends off; I suppose."
                                                     I couldn't help smiling, for I must admit, that was the first time
                                                     someone's ever cracked a joke on my arrival.
                                                     "And I suppose it's time? "she asked.
                                                     I nodded.
                                                     A gentle breeze brushed her hair off her face. She wasn't really
                                                     beautiful, but she was definitely pretty.
                                                     " You know, I always thought at least one of them would return.
                                                     I wonder why I expected so much."
                                                     I have seen her love. She loved with her whole heart, mind, soul
                                                     and body. Hence, she always lost a part of herself when they
                                                     walked away. And somehow, she believed that one day, they
                                                     would bring those little pieces back. Damn narcissists!
                                                     We sat in silence until the sun started setting, and the first
                                                     touch of twilight appeared. She took one last deep breath and
                                                     looked at me. She had a jade smile of relief across her face. I
                                                     stood up and held out my bony hand. As she took it in hers, her
                                                     big blue eyes danced with joy.
                                                     Taking her soul back home that day, I realized that not all people
                                                     see me dressed in blacks with a scythe in my hand, and that for a
                                                     fraction of people, I am simply a superhero at their rescue.
                                                     Sometimes, the end can be beautiful too.

                                                                            Arsha
                                                                            2nd DC BSc Psychology









































           64   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Iq«nse InfnbpsS hyY


                                                                sXfnbp¶p hm\taLw
                                                                Xncbp¶p thZhmIyw
                                                                Xocm¯ Xoctam…. tXSpw
                                                                tX\qdpw Xp¼nt]mse
                                                                Xncpap¼nÂ {]Xn_nw_w


                                                                CS\mgnIfnÂ tXSp¶ sh«w
                                                                achn¨ I¼nIfnÂ Zp:Jw
                                                                ImWm¯ ImgvNIÄ ImWm³
                                                                I¬Nn½msX Im¯ I®pIÄ t]mse
                                                                AIe§fnÂ AÚmXw


                                                                ]mZ§fmÂ ]mXtbmc§fnÂ
                                                                ]mXn ]Xn¸ns¨m¶p \S¡m³
                                                                BImi¯¼nfnsbþ
                                                                sNs¶m¶p Npw_n¡m³
                                                                tamln¨ an{Xambn am\w


                                                                                                  Devika K A
                                                                                      Third  B.Sc Mathematics







                                                                                          WEAVES       65]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Different Generations; Different Thoughts


              We all have heard the terms GenZ, Millennials, Boomers, and Centennials. And we belong to one of
              these categories. The way we perceive things are very different when we generalise them. This can lead
              to disagreements, especially between the younger and older generation. You all have experienced that
              at least once. No matter how cool you are or how understanding you can be, there would have been at
              least one instance where you had to disagree with how the other person views something.
                   To look at this argument from a child's perspective, one of the most common things you will hear
              them say is the lack of personal space that the parents don't provide. It is necessary to provide space
              for a child as they s/he is an individual. Still, these things have to be monitored until they reach a certain
              age. But keeping an eye on them even after reaching an age where they can take care of themselves is
              overprotective. We all know how competitive and cruel the real world can be. Sheltering them for too
              long will not protect them from that same world that they are supposed to get exposed to at one point in
              time, but rather make them more scared to face the actual reality. The children should be given enough
              freedom where they can decide on weighing down the good and the bad. The parents can always pro-
              vide them guidance on how they can be faced but not do it for them. This, in my opinion, shapes better
              humans for the future. While talking about protectiveness, another concern that we hear is not being
              able to go out. This is mainly focused on girl children. It is also important to note that our country is not
              the safest to go out alone. This increases the concern level of the parents. I feel that the best way to
              "resolve" these problems is to find the middle ground between the views of parents and children.
                  Now, the fact is that the parents and the children have been very different. An important factor
              contributing to this might be the generation gap. The way things are understood can be very different
              depending upon the generation that we belong to. In the opinion of generational theorists, generational
              cohorts are deeply influenced in their thinking by events, experiences and technology that are part of
              their world during their formative years. So, the time that we grow up certainly has an impact on the way
              we think. It is important that as time moves, both parent and children should change their perspectives
              (at least be a little more open). That doesn't mean that it is okay for the children to keep facts away from
              their parents. We all have kept secrets from our parents. Why do we keep it away if we think that it is
              correct? So, the reason why it is being hidden is that there is a guilty note attached to it.
                  In conclusion, both parties won't be able to understand what the other thinks completely (maybe the
              children will be able to once they are parents) and a common ground needs to be found. It is also im-
              portant that understanding nature is needed and those matters which lead to disagreement are to be
              confronted and opened up in order to reduce conflicts.

                                                                     Anna Mariya
                                                                     3rd DC English





































           66   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[b


                                         As the world falls under our feet
                                      And the sky we love,
                                    loses its colours
                                  I’m standing there still, with
                                 Shivering hands covering my eyes
                                I’m trying to keep my self up,
                               Watching all that happens.
                               For not only the eyes can see,
                              And it all became ashes and
                              It turned to deep darkness
                              infornt of these eyes
                               it’s the sigh of rebirth, I realised
                               there’s more to it, the world
                                to us, hidden deeply inside.
                                 These mazes, behind strong wall
                                   There are souls……

                                                                  Vyshnavy R Sharma
                                                           3rd DC  B.Com F(A)



















                                                                                          WEAVES       67]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[A´yao bm{X






                                                                                             ZpÀ¤ kn²mÀ°v
                                                                                          II nd B.Com Finance








                   A´yao \nanjsa³ PohnXbm{Xsb                            A\p{KltamXp¶ InfnIfpïv,
                       XgpIp¶ ssIIfmbv Imäpïv,                            A´yao bm{Xsb thKam¡m³
                Imän³ hncÂ¯p¼nÂ ssItImÀ¯v                          Fsâ IqsS Pzen¡phm³ Aánbpïv.
                              bm{X sNmÃm\neIfpïv                        DbÀ¶p s]m§psa¶mßmhns\
                Icsªsâ bm{Xsb IpXnÀ¯msX                                   hcthÂ¡m\mbv BImiapïv
                   s]bvXv IpfntcIps¶mcp agbpïv                                 Zriyamw temIanXnÂ \n¶v
                       agbpsS I®p\oÀ ISsaSp¯m-                   AZriybmbv Rm³ bm{X t]mIpt¼mÄ
                      cpadnbmsX Icbp¶ ]q¡fpïv                \\hpff angnIfmÂ, Xfcp¶ samgnIfmÂ
                  XncntI hnfns¨sâ bm{XapS¡msX                    hnXp¼p¶, Icbp¶, kvt\lnXcpïv....



           68   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Cage

















































        New lives thrusting around
        in a little cage;
        their empty stomachs filled by
        the long red beaks.
        As every season goes by,
        their quills grow longer
        and longer.

        ‘ When will our eyes
        meet the blue skies and
        the blue oceans?’, they cried.
        ‘Don’t spread your
        wings until the sunrise’,
        said the garnet red beaks.
        To the first ray of sunlight,
        they rose like a Phoenix,
        flaring their feathers.
                                                                                                 Alena Joy
        Only to realize they’re                                                                                                                                           1st DC Biotech
        trapped in loops of snares.


                                                                                          WEAVES       69]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[\S¸nem¡mt\m Hcp
                                                                            kv{Xosb F§s\ _lpam\n¡Wsa-
                                                                            ¶v hfÀ¶phcp¶ ]pcpjhÀ¤s¯
                                                                             DZvt_m[n¸n¡mt\m       D]tZiw
                                                                              \ÂIp¶hÀ DÕmlw ImWn¡m
                                                                              dnÃ. CjvSapff hkv{Xw [cn¡pI
                                                                             F¶Xv  s]®nsâbpw BWnsâ
                                                                             bpw kzmX{´yamWv. HcmÄ¡pam{Xw
                                                                            B kzmX{´yw DïmhpIbpw asäm-
                                                                           cmÄ¡v  AXv \ntj[n¡s¸SpIbpw
                                                                           sN¿p¶Xv icnbmb \S]SnbÃ.
                                                                          ]mc¼cys¯  Iq«p]nSn¨mWv  Ft¸m
                                                                          gpw   hkv{X[mcW     kzmX{´ys¯
                                                                         l\n¡p¶Xns\ \ymboIcn¡p¶Xv.
                                                                     ]t£, C¶v \½Ä DbÀ¯n¸nSn¡p¶ hkv{X-
                                                                   §sfm¶pw Xs¶ \½ptSXÃ. \½sf `cn¨v
                                                                   IS¶pt]mb     {_n«ojpImcptSXmWv,   \½Ä
                                                                  C¶v DbÀ¯n]nSn¡p¶ kwkvImcw.
                                                                DZmlcWklnXw  Nqïn ImWn¡pIbmsW¦nÂ,
                                                               »ukv F¶Xv _wKmfntebpw sX¡³ C´ybntebpw
                                                               kv{XoIfpsS hkv{X¯nsâ `mKw Bbncp¶nÃ. 1900
                                                              emWv {_n«ojv \nba¯n\pIognÂ »ukv [cn¡Ww
                                                           F¶ \nÀ_Ôw h¶Xv.
                                                           hkv{X¯n\v Aev]w \ofw Ipdªpt]mbmÂ AXv
                                                           ]mÝmXy kwkvImcamWv F¶v hmZn¡p¶hÀ HmÀ¡msX
                                                           t]mIp¶ Imcyw F´msW¶mÂ ]mc¼cy coXnbnepff
                                                           hkv{Xw F¶v ]dªv AhÀ hfÀ¯n ]nSn¡p¶Xpw
                                                           ]mÝmXyhkv{XamWv F¶ hkvXpXbmWv. F´nt\sd
        N«¡qSpIÄ¡v                                         ]dbp¶p Hcp]mSv BfpIÄ kµÀin¡p¶ ]pcmX\
                                                           t£{X§fnÂ \áamb {]XnaIfpsS tiJcWw Xs¶
                                                           bpïv.
        Hcp AdpXn                                            \áamb Hcp icoc`mKw ImWpt¼mtgbv¡pw Imaw

                                                           aq¯v ]oU\¯nÂ hsc F¯n \nÂ¡p¶ Hcp kaqlam-
                                       Aleena Rose Stanly  Wv  \½ptSXv F¶v  hmZn¡p¶hÀ  a\Ênemt¡ïp¶,
                                         III DC Psychology  AsÃ¦nÂ AhÀ ]dbmsX ]dbp¶ Hcp hkvXpXbïv.
                PohnX¯nÂ Hcn¡se¦nepw am\yamb hkv{X[m-      A{XtaÂ ssewKnI AcmPIXz¯nemWv \½psS cmPy-
        cWw F§s\bmbncn¡Ww F¶Xns\¡pdn¨v hniZamb             sa¶v. hkv{X[mcWw ]oU\s¯ kzm[o\n¡ps¶¦nÂ
        D]tZiw tIÄ¡m¯ al¯mb tIcfob kwkvImc¯nÂ              Gähpa[nIw ]oU\§Ä \St¡ïnbncp¶Xv hntZicmPy-
        P\n¨p  hfÀ¶ s]¬Ip«nIÄ  Ipdhmbncn¡pw.  hkv{X-       §fnembncp¶p.. ]pcpj·mcmb ssK\t¡mfPnÌpIÄ
        [mcW¯nsâ N«§Ä kaqlw Iev]n¨p sImSp¡p¶Xv             Hcp {]khw ssIImcyw sN¿pt¼mÄ Xsâ tcmKnIfpsS
        s]®n\pam{XamWv     F¶XmWv     {i²    \ÂtIïp¶             \áX ImWpt¼mÄ AbmÄ¡pffnÂ Dcp¯ncnbp¶Xv
        Imcyw. kv{XoIfpsS icoc{]ZÀi\amWv ]m]¯n\v hgnsX-    ImaaÃ, adn¨v Xsâ tcmKntbmSpff ImcpWyw am{XamWv.
        fnbn¡p¶Xv F¶mWtÃm AenJnX\nbaw. kXy¯nÂ              hkv{X[mcWaÃ, Hmtcmcp¯cpsSbpw am\knI
        F´mWv  am\yamb hkv{X[mcWw?  am\yamb hkv{X[m-       \nebmWv ]oU\w t]msebpff sXäntebv¡v \bn¡p¶Xv.
        cW¯nsâ  \nÀÆN\w  Hmtcm  hyànIÄ¡\pkcn¨mWv.          {]mbamb kv{XoIfpw ]n©pIpªp§fpw
        Hmtcmcp¯À  P\n¨phfÀ¶  kmlNcy§fpw  PohnXm           Ccbm¡s¸Sp¶Xv Hcn¡epw hkv{X[mcWw sImïÃtÃm..
        \p`h§fpw hkv{X[mcWs¯¡pdn¨pff  ImgvN¸mSns\          hmÕeyw  P\nt¡ïp¶  I®pIfnÂ  Imaw  ]q¡p¶Xv
        bpw kzm[o\n¡p¶pïv.                                 am\knI hn{`m´nbpsSbpw Ac£nXmhØbpsSbpw
                ]oU\§fpambn _Ôs¸Sp¯n hkv{Xs¯               e£W§fmWv.  C¯cw  AhØIfnte¡v  hyànIsf
        \nÀÆNn¡pt¼mÄ          am\yamb       hkv{X[mcWw     XffnhnSmXncn¡m\pff  amÀ¤§fmWv s]¬Ip«nIfpsS
        F¶XpsImïv kmwkvImcnI \mbI·mÀ Dt±in¡p¶Xv            hkv{X[mcW kzmX{´ys¯ l\n¡p¶Xn\v ]Icw
        icocw apgph³ aqSn \S¡p¶ hkv{Xs¯bmWv.               sNt¿ïXv. aäpffhÀ¡pthïn HcmfpsS CjvS§sfbpw
        ]oU\§sf  XSbm\pff  Gähpw henb  {]Xnhn[nbmbn        Xmev]cy§sfbpw amäpt¼mgÃ, Ahsc Ahcmbn Xs¶
        ChÀ IW¡m¡p¶Xv, C¯c¯nepff hkv{X[mcW§                XpScm³ A\phZn¡pt¼mgmWv Hcp kaqlw D¶Xn ssI-
        fmWv. Cu e£yw \ndthäp¶Xn\pthïn HcmfpsS             hcn¡p¶Xv. \½fmIp¶ Cu kaqls¯ ]ptcmKXnbn-
        hkv{X kzmX{´y¯nte¡mWv D]tZinIÄ IS¶pIb-             tebv¡v ssI]nSn¨pbÀ¯m³ hyànIfmb
        dp¶Xv.  Ccbm¡s¸Sp¶  hn`mK¯n\mWv  Ft¸mgpw                            \apt¡mtcmcp¯À¡pw ISabpïv. C\nbpw DSbm¯
        \nb{´W§fpw aXnÂs¡«pIfpw kaqlw Iev]n¨p              N«¡qSpIsf s]mfns¨gptXïXpw \mw Xs¶bmWv.
        sImSp¡p¶Xv.  th«bmSp¶hÀ¡v  iàamb  in£mcoXn

           70   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Ammama…




          The six letter emotion
          Embracing the three year old child
          A lot with endless queries
          Feet running around in anklets
          And tiny hands collecting manjadikurus
          The little brain behind the
          Vanishing Munch Bars of the House
          A Wild Little Child
          A Child of Hues
          Little Amy flying, Not Running
          Everyone would reminisce
          Around the Church
          Her Slap-happy voice
          Bellowing alone the rest
          Indifferent to Protests
          Even from Priests
          For the hullabaloo she created
          With her jingling anklet feet
          Left everyone in giggles and
          her mother in troubles

          Ammama…
          The Six Letter Archangel
          Embracing the three year old child
          From the Wrath of her mother
          The Little Mistress Stubborn in her meals
          Stubborn in her ways
          Chose to keep up
          Only to her Grandmother’s pace
          Into the Abyss of this wild little child
          I thrust my hand
          Yanking it back, I found in them Remains
          Of Boats made of Paper






                                                    Annmary Charles
                                                    II DC English






                                                                                          WEAVES       71]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[72   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[WEAVES       73]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Nn{Xw




          hnNn{Xw




                                                                                         Elizabeth Mariya Jijo
                                                                                             II Dc B A History




          AhÄ     R§fnÂ     \n¶pw   hyXykvXbmbncp¶p.    \   CsXm¶paÃmbncp¶p.  kz]v\Xpeyamb  Hcp  ]pXnb
          S¯¯nepw \nÂ¸nepw `mh§Ä sImïpw Gsd Akz`m  BImi¯nte¡v NndIpbÀ¯n ]d¶ Hcp IpªpIn-
          hnIXIÄ \ndªhÄ. BcpsS CSbnepw AwKoI  fnbpsS IYbmbncp¶p AXv. IpªpssIIfnÂ Ip¸n
          cn¡s¸Sm¯hÄ. AhKWIfpsS aSn¯«nÂ \n¶pw,  hfsbSp¡m³  XpS§nbt¸mÄ,  BZyambn  arZpe  \b\§
          kzbw ]d¶p DbÀ¶hÄ. DSensâ ]mXn ]pcpjXzs¯bpw  fnÂ Im¡¡dp¼sâ Icnsbm¶v \of¯nÂ hmens«
          adp]mXn kv{XoXzs¯bpw hln¨hÄ. a\Ênem¡m\pw  gpXnbt¸mÄ,  ]«p]mhmSbWnªv  Inep§p¶ ]mZk-
          tNÀ¯p \nÀ¯m\pw Rm³ AS¡apff                        cant«mSm³ a\Êv B{Kln¨t¸mÄ, BZyw tI« hmNIw,
          GI     enwK¡msc¶v      A`nam\]qÀÆw                F¶pw Cu kaql¯nÂ AhfpsS hyànXzs¯ ad¨p
          sIm«ntLmjn¨hÀ¡v sXänsb¶v AhÄ                      ]nSn¡m³  Ahsf \nÀ_ÔnXbm¡n.  ‘\o Hcp  B¬Ip«n-
          R§sf ]Tn¸n¨p.                                         bmWv‘, H¶pds¡ Icbm³ t]mepw Dff kzmX{´yw
                                                                     CÃmXm¡nb hm¡v. asä´nepw A[nIw CXv
                                                                        Ahsf XfÀ¯n; Ahfnepff kv{XoXzs¯
          BZy    Znhk§fnÂ     Xs¶                                          Hfn¸n¨p sh¨p.
          R§fpsS CSbnÂ AhÄ
          Hcp       tNmZyNnÓam                                                hfÀ¨bpsS     ]mXbnÂ     Xncn¨dn-
          bncp¶p. F§s\bmWv                                                       hpIfpsS  bpw km[yXIfpsS-
          Ahsf,     F´mWv                                                           bpw    temI¯v      AhÄ
          AhÄ, AhfpsS                                                                 ss[cy]qÀÆw     A`nam\
          I®nÂ R§Ä                                                                      t¯msS         ]dªp
          F   §   s  \                                                                     Rm³  H¶Ã  F¶nÂ
          bmbncn¡pw-                                                                        Rm³ cïmbn {]
                                                                                              Xn^en¡psa¶v,
                                                                                              Htc kabw

                                                                                              kv{Xobmhm\pw,
                                                                                            ]pcpj\mhm\pw
                                                                                          F\n¡v Ignbpsa¶v
          Fs¶ms¡bp-                                                                       CXv  Hcp  Ipdhmbn
          ff tNmZy§fmWv                                                                   AhÄ     Iïncp¶nÃ.
          NnecpsS    DffnÂ                                                               adn¨v CXv Hcp anI-
          F¦nÂ,  aäp NneÀ¡v                                                             hmWv.   CtX    anIhp-
          AhÄ ]cnlmk§Ä                                                                  ff  Ip«nIÄ¡v  AhÄ
          Gäphm§m³  ]änb  Hcp                                                           A½bmbn.
          \Ã tImamfnbmbn. thsd                                                           C¶v AhÄ hnNn{X
          Ipd¨pt]À¡v    aX{`m´nsâ                                                      AÃ.  R§fpsS  CSbnÂ
          t]cnÂ    AhÄ     ]m]¯nsâ                                                    HcphfmWv. R§sf¡qSn
          ^eambn. _m¡nbpffhÀ Aw_                                                    amän Nn´n¸n¨, R§Ä Im-
          bpsS asämcp AhXmcamb in-                                                 WmsX t]mb `wKnbpff Nn{X-
          JWvUnbmsW¶pw  ]dªp.  ti-                                               §sf R§Ä¡v  kp]cnNnXam-
          jn¡p¶hÀ Ahsf                                                          ¡nb R§fpsS Nn{XbmWv.
          klXm]¯nsâ           ap\bpff
          t\m«§fmÂ  {Iqin¨p.  F¶mÂ
          AhÄ¡v           ]dbm\pffXv

           74   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[{]WbaÀ½c§Ä


          lrZb imJIfnÂ Hcp
          XfnÀ hk´w ]q¡p¶Xv Ft¸mgmWv?
          au\w aghnÃv t]mse
          at\mlcamIp¶Xpw,
          tIÄ¡m³ sImXn¨ ]m«pw
          ]mSm³ sImXn¨ CuWhpw
          a\amsI \ndbp¶Xpw
          aªpt]mse am\kw
          DcpIp¶Xpw,
          F´ns\¶dnbmsX
          a\w ]mSp¶Xpw
          Ce¯p¼nÂ \n¶qÀ¶p hogp¶
          ag¯pffnIfpsS i_vZw t]mepw kwKoX
          km{µamhp¶Xpw….
          Ft¸mgmWv….
          Hcp aªp XpffnbnÂ t]mepw Hcp
          Ipªp kqcy³ DZn¡p¶Xpw
          Hmtcm ag\qenepw In\mhpIÄ
          \ndbp¶Xpw
          I\amsI ]q¡Ä Xp¶nb ]«p
          XqhmebmÂ s]mXnbp¶Xpw
          lrZbktcmhc¯nÂ hÀWie`§Ä
          hncps¶¯p¶Xpw
          a[pclÀjambn IcfnÂ
          GtXm ]q¦pbnÂ ]mSp¶Xpw
          kvt\lmÀ{Zambmtcm s\dpIbnÂ
          XtemSp¶Xpw
          \\p¯ IpfntcmsS ImtXmcamtcm Hcp
          arZpcmKw aqfp¶Xpsat¸mgmWv?
          Aebmgn t]mse a\ÊnÂ {]Wbw
          \ndbpt¼mÄ!!
          A\pcmK¯nÂ Rm\m
          {]Wb¯n³ ags¸bv¯v!!
          hm¡pIfmÂ hÀ®\mXoXao
          lrZb kv]Àinbmw A\pcmKw…,.
          lm, F{X at\mÚao {]Wbw !!!


          NAVAL SHIRIN P S
          IInd DC BBA




                                                                                          WEAVES       75]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Queer book recs
          Q   ueer book r                 ecs

























































































           76   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[The acronym LGBTQIAP2S+ though not uncommon may bewilder at least a few. This
          term includes the diverse identities of the queer spectrum. The acronym is increasing
          in length by adding new letters to it as in the case of the extension of this community.
          Here is an informative expansion of each letter of the acronym along with a book
          suggestion for each category.


          L –     Lesbian
                  One Last Stop by Casey McQuiston (Romance)
          G –   Gay
                  Heartstopper Graphic novel series by Alice Oseman
                        (Romance, Graphic novel)
          B –      Bisexual and Biromantic
                     Take a Hint, Dani Brown by Talia Hibbert (Rom-com)
          T –     Transgender, Transsexual
                     Cemetery Boys by Aiden Thomas (Fantasy Romance)
          Q –   Queer or Questioning
                     Rick by Alex Gino (Children’s literature)
          I –     Intersex
                   Middlesex by Jeffrey Eugenides (Family saga)
          A –   Asexual, Aromantic, Agender
                     Loveless by Alice Oseman (Asexual, Aromantic)
                     Summer Bird Blue by Akemi Dawn Bowman (Aromantic)
                     I Wish You All the Best by Mason Deaver (Agender)
          P –   Pansexual, Panromantic
                     A Dark and Hollow Star by Ashley Shutterworth (Fantasy)
          2S –   Two Spirit

                     Johnny Appleseed by Joshua Whitehead

          The plus sign (+) at the end of the acronym stands as an indicator of more identities. These
          books may not be the definitive representation of each identity, but only represent one
          side of many. A few other ‘Goodreads’ are also listed: 1. Iron Widow by Xiran Jay Zhao
          (Fantasy),  2. Pet by Akwaeke Emezi, 3. Love and Other Disasters by Anita Kelly (Romcom)
          4. Gender Queer by Maia Kobabe (autobiography/graphical novel), 5. She Who Became the
          Sun by Shelley Parker-Chan, (fantasy). One can merely suggest innumerable books but
          only the actual act of reading the books will make all the difference. You may traverse
          through the joys, sorrows, life situations, and fantasies of the ‘other’. Read them all
          year round, not only in June (LGBT Pride Month). Queer Stories all year long! Happy
          reading!





                                                                                Aswati Biju
                                                                                3rd DC BSc. Botany





                                                                                          WEAVES       77]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[78   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[WEAVES       79]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Pzen¡p¶ HmÀ½




        IpfnÀ aªps]¿p¶ {]`mXw. aªpXpffnIsf sshUqcyam¡n sImïv kqcy³ DZn¨p
        XpS§n. A]IS¯nsâ cq£KÔw Xfw sI«n \nÂ¡p¶ B tdmUnÂ \n¶pff XpSsc
        bpff tlmWpIÄ Abmsf {`m´p]nSn¸n¨p. kabw 8 Bbncn¡p¶p. F¦nepw Unkw_À
        amk¯nsâ B XWp¸nÂ AbmÄ aqSn¸pX¨p InS¡pIbmWv. ImepIÄ s\t©mSp tNÀ¯v
        InS¡p¶ Hcp KÀ`Ø iniphns\ t]mse AbmÄ ImWs¸«p. FhnsS \nt¶m h¶ aµam-
        cpX³ Abmsf XtemSnt¸mbn. Bekyw sImïmImw B cm{Xn¡v \ofw Ipdªt¸mse A
        bmÄ¡v tXm¶n. ]e cm{XnIfnÂ X\n¨ncn¡pt¼mgpw AbmfpsS a\Êv thsdsbhnsStbm
        B bncp¶pþ sXcphp hoYnIfnÂ Aeªp Xncnªv \S¡p¶ {`m´s\t¸mse, sIm¯pw
        InfbpanÃmsX Xcnip \neambn¡nS¡p¶ B a\ÊnÂ a[pckz]v\amIp¶ hn¯pambn
        F¯m³, Ft´m Xqhme¡nfn t]mepw aSn¨n«pïmIpw.
               PohnX{]mcm_v[§Ä¡nSbnÂ IpSp§nt¸mIpt¼mgpw AbmfpsS a\w \ndsb
        Ahfmbncp¶p. A¶v ISÂ¯oc¯p sh¨p Iï B kpµcn. apSnIÄ ImänÂ ]d¯n
        ISensâ `wKn BkzZn¨ncn¡pt¼mgmWv A¶mZyambn AbmÄ Ahsf IïXv. Ahsfm-
        cp amemJbmbncp¶p.  CW¡nfnIfnsem¶mbn  Xsâ  PohnX¯nte¡p IS¶ph¶  amemJ.
        F¶ns«t´ AhsfhnsSbmWnt¸mÄ?                          AtXmÀ¡pt¼mÄ             AbmÄ        IcbpIbm
        bncp¶p.  \nioYn\nbpsS  \ni_                            vZXbv¡v `wKw hcp¯ns¡mïv F¶pw
        Iot_mÀUv AhÄ¡mbn                                           i_vZn¨ncp¶p.          ]e        cm{XnI
        fnepw      ]pecpthmfw                                          AhÀ  kwkmcn¨p.  B  ^vfmäv
        kap¨b¯nsâ  \mep                                                     NphcpIfnepw B {]Wbw
        \ndªp \n¶ncp¶p.                                                       Ahsf          Iïam{XbnÂ
        Xsâ        kncIfneqsS                                                  Acn¨ph¶ {]Wbw A
        bmfdnªp.
                                                                              AtXmÀ¡pt¼msgms¡
        AbmfpsS            I®v                                               \ndª pXpfp¼ n.
        F¶n«nt¸mÄ         F´m.                                             F´m kw`hnt¨?
        AtXmÀ¡pt¼mÄ             B                                        a\Êv achn¨ncp¶p. Xms\¶
        Zo]s¯         DuXns¡Sp¯n                                       AhÄ        Häbv¡p      t]mbt¸mÄ
        B        kXyw        DÄs¡mffm³                               AbmÄ Gsd ]Wns¸«p. A¶v
        B ISÂ¯ocw t{]atemeam                                         bncps¶¦nÂ  C¶v  AXv  acWam-
        Wv. Xsâ CWsb ImÀ¶p                                           Xn¶ acWw. Sm! lcn \o
        ChnsSbncn¡ymtWm..?          IÀ½w                             sN¿m³ kabambn. tIith«sâ
        B hm¡pIÄ Abmsf kvacWI                                        fnÂ \n¶pw DWÀ¯n.
        \ndI®pIfmbn AbmÄ \S¶p                                       \o§pt¼mÄ NnX
        Bfn¡¯pIbmbncp¶p.                                                Pzen¡p¶ HmÀ½Ifmb...

        sX¶Â IrjvW.]n
        III DC B.A HISTORY














           80   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[\ndª a\Ênsâ \nizmkw……



          Hcp ]pgsbmgpIm³ shffapïnhnsS
          AWs]m«nsbmgpIm³ AXnhÀjapïnhnsS
          imkv{Xw ]Tnbv¡m³ KWnXw ]Tnbv¡m³
          `mj ]Tnbv¡m³ kmt¦XnI hnZy ]Tnbv¡m³
          BfpïnhnsS Beb§fpïv
          AdnhpIÄ t\Sm³ hnZymeb§Ä
          t\Àhgn Im«m³ almßm¡tfsd
          sXmgnepIÄ ]Tnbv¡m³ ]cnioe\§Ä
          tPmenIÄ t\Sm³ B¸okpIÄþ ]gpXpIÄ
          Hcp tPmen Hcp Iqen Im¯ncnt¸msc
          HmÀ¡m³ IgnbtW, I\nbtW hcZm\w
          CS\mgnbnse t]m¡pshbnensâ Xncn\mf¯nÂ
          \ndw h¶v tim`n¨ BÄcq]§sf
          sh«w adbpt¼mÄ Xmt\ adtªmfpsa¶mbv
          \ngembv XfftÃ sImtffWw \tÃmWw
          kvt\l¸pgIsfmgp¡m³ Xcnt]mepapïm-þ
          bnänäp hogm³ I®oÀ IW§Ä _m¡n
          k¦S§tfsd CSs\©nsemXp¡n
          kvt\l¡®ocn\mbv Im¯p \nÂ¸q P\w
          sImSp¡ntÃ `n£ bmNn¨ ssIIfnÂ
          t\SntÃ \ndª a\Ênsâ \nizmkw



          [\y Fw. thWptKm]mÂ


                                                                                          WEAVES       81]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[TO NOT BE OKAY





                                                                              Anna Reejo
                                                                              II DC Mathematics






























        There is nothing easier than justifying yourself in today’s   victim, a culprit — a human being to simply put it. Being
        world—  I  should  know  since  I  do  it  without  end.  The   mentally healthy is not about using something hurtful in
        reason is the fact that the world is filled with people who   your life as a shield to prevent criticism. It is not about
        try to justify all they do. We live in an age of ‘wokeness’.   digging a hole to bury yourself in. Rather, its about finding
        This means that the only way to keep your popularity   a way to emerge from that shell you’ve created, its about
        index going up is to be seen as a good person, a person   acknowledging that life has room for mistakes, that no
        who says what everybody wants to hear, supporting   matter how many times you fall, you can and will keep
        causes everybody wants supported. If any given ‘famous   getting up. You can always sit in the dark because no one
        face’ comments on one of the many ‘sensitive issues’ and   can see you there, but tell me, is that really healthy, or
        takes the ‘wrong side’, then that person’s career is done   successful?
        for good.
                                                           The only people who succeed in life are those who
        Believe me, vulnerability is becoming or rather has   overcome their weaknesses (which come in different
        become the new trend in Hollywood, Bollywood,      shapes and sizes like we all do). Yes, as they say, it is
        Mollywood or any part of the woods you live in. Because   okay to not be okay, the problem begins when it is not
        it build up fan bases in lightning speed. Don’t get me   okay, to be okay. If in a ‘not at all real’ situation, a ‘famous
        wrong, weakness is as real in every one of us as the fact   person’ is not okay, that person is most likely going to
        that we breathe oxygen. Vulnerability is certainly not a   call a doctor— or a family member (provided they’re not
        crime, and certainly nothing to be ashamed of. But there   feuding you know). There’s nothing wrong with it. The
        are times when people tend to use it as a shield to cover   thing is if we want to be and not see someone successful,
        up the  wrongs they commit.  Whether  you cheat on   maybe we should do the same. Maybe all of our mental
        your husband with his best friend, sell drugs to friends,   health problems should start being discussed with
        or hit someone while driving drunk— its all due to your   people we know, maybe we should stop commenting on
        vulnerable, pitiful state! We live in a world where one’s   them and start commenting on us.
        ability to gain empathy decides if s/he is a victim or a
        culprit. And that is terrifying. Because regardless of   We are all weak just like we are all strong. Being mentally
        whether you are black/white/brown/yellow, if you kill,   healthy is about finding our weak spots, but its also about
        you kill and if you steal, you steal. Equality is not when   weakening those spots. Maybe it won’t be easy and I bet
        the  oppressed  becomes  the  oppressor;  it  is  when  all   we’ll continue to find new weaknesses, weaknesses that
        parties lose all labels.                           we can’t ever fully conquer. And that, well that  is okay—
                                                           as long as we try.
        Surely, every single person reading this is a survivor, a

           82   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[THE BIRTH Of ART


        A million miles away, saw a white canvas.
        Here beneath I stand perplexed.
        No paints, no brushes!
        I stand here gazing at it.


        At a slow pace,
        Appeared the big shaggy clouds,
        And the big bright sun.
        I started reaping yields.


        Why wish for brushes and colours?
        When it paints on its own.
        Why wish for smudging the sky?
        When it is finer the way it is.


        You can only create art in yourself.
        And I vow, that’ll be your masterpiece.


         Gayathry N.S
        1st DC, BA English
















































                                                                                          WEAVES       83]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[You entered my life
          perfectly blissful,
          Like a house turned into home.
          You are the home
          while I kept enjoying your presence,
          the impeccable beauty you revealed;
          hard to find a speck of dust,
          glad to see a home, its own,                          The Wicked
          mesmerised till I know not.
          And then the humanly beast                            House
          finds the tiniest of dust a huge mess,
          wanting to renovate the home;                         Lost The
          no more the old home,
          wanting to add filters,
          and I began the process;                              Home
          Realised I finally lost a home.
          The beast in me, or the beasts,
          overpowered me.
          Over expectations, conceit, greed,
          and what not, I aware not.
          Enslaved by my own beasts,
          I, a wicked house
          Lost the home.

          Nahla Latheef
          BSc Psychology
          3rd DC


           84   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[{`m´³                                              NneXnÂ klXm]w
                                                           NneXnÂ IuXpIw
                                                           NneXnÂ A¼c¸v
                                                           NneXnÂ ImcpWyw.

                                        V.M Salima Habeeb  Rm\dnbp¶pthm F\n¡p {`m´msW¶v?
                                        IIIrd Dc Psychology Xmfapïmbncp¶ F³ lrZb¯n³
                                                           hmNmeX

                                                           Bcpta tI«nÃ.
                                                           F³ a\IhmSw Xpd¡phm\mbv
        hgnsb t]msbmcmÄ X³ InSmhn\p                        Adnbphm\mbvþþ tIÄ¡phm\mbv

        sNmÃns¡mSp¯p...                                    Iq«ambv hcpao ag¯pffnIÄ am{Xw!
        Øncsas¶ ImWp¶hÀ F¶cnInÂ                            Fs¶m¸apsï¶v sNmÃn hnizkn¸n¨hÀ
        \n¶                                                F³ a\¯n³ Xmfw sXän¨p s]mb-
               ]cnNnXt\mXns¡mSp¯p.                         v¡fªp
        Zm! AbmÄ {`m´\mWv..!                               Rm³ {`m´\mbn.AÃ.
        ]e `mh§Ä kv^pcn¡pam I®pIfnÂþ                       ImWnIÄ {`m´s\¶p ap{ZIp¯n!
               Fs¶ ho£n¡pt¼mÄþ
               Ft·Â I®pS¡pt¼mÄ.

                                                                                          WEAVES       85]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[^mÌv ^pUv





        Hcp t\cs¯ hni¸Iäm³                                 I¿nÂ IcpXmw s]mXnt¨msdm¶v
        ]mXnhbdnsâ aSp¸Iäm³                                ]Ww sImSp¯hkm\w ]nWamIcpXtÃm
        tdmUcnInembv Xpd¶p h¨ncn¡pw                        ]e ]e ]mT§Ä ]Tns¨¶mepw
        A¶ZmXmsh¶ t]mÂ                                     s]mXphmbn AcpsX¶ptamXnbmepw
        s]mbvImÂ aµncw                                     kzbw I®S¨ncp«m¡n
        Ae¦mc ]qcnXw                                       XInSw adbp¶p \o am\ht\.......
        IhmSw Ia\obw
        kpKÔw \mknIbnÂ Dt¯P\ckw
        \mhp XpSn¨p cpNn¨pt\m¡m³
        Nn¯w ASnabmbv _mlytamSnbnÂ                         Aiz\n hn.Fkv
        Ibdns¨¶pcp«n hngp§n¯n¶oþ                           III DC B.Com Finance
        thK `£Ww
        A½ \ÂIpw cpNnbmIptam
        Imcyw Ct¸mfnsÃ¦nepw Im¯ncn¡mw
        `£n¡m\tÃm Pohn¡p¶p \mw
        Hcp t\cantÃÃpw Ign¨p Iq«mw
        Ch IjvSp t]me\§msX \mep \mÄ InS¡pw
        ]mXn t]mbv ]mXn ]ns¶bpw InS¡pw
        DÄ¯nI«n hcp¶Xv ]pdt¯s¡mgn¡Ww
        InS¡WsamcmgvN Ign¨Xn\mte
        Nnet¸mÄ hnfn¡pw Ime³
        Ibdpamsb¯n
        F´n\o thïm¯ the







































           86   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[IS¸mSv                                                 Sr. Aneeta Stephan
                                                                         II DC B.Com Finance



                  ]n¶m¼pd§fntebv¡v Xncnªp kq£vaXtbmsS t\m¡pt¼mÄ
                  Xncn¨dnbm\mIpw BcpsSsbms¡tbm I\nhmWv Fsâbpw \n§fpsS bpw PohnX-
                  sa¶v. Npänepw Iqcncp«mbncp¶t¸mÄ \s½ tXSnsb¯nb Ir]bpsS an¶Â¸nW-
                  cpIÄ. AÀln¡m¯ ImcpWy¯nsâ Du«ptaiIÄ £WnIsa¦nepw e`n¨ kvt\
                  l¯nsâ ssI¯m§pIÄ‘ AtX, F{Xtbm, Ic§ fmWv \nÊmcamb \½psS
                  PohnXs¯ sXm«nem«p¶Xv. AXn\mÂ IS¸mSpIsfm¶pw ad¶pIqSm. sImSp¯p
                  XoÀ¡phm³ km[n¡m¯ Nne IS§ fpïv. Id³knbnÂ HXp¡m\mIm¯, \µnbp-
                  ff PohnXw sImïv am{Xw ho«mhp¶ Nne IS§Ä.
                          H¶pw     ad¡m\mInÃ.       A½nª        ]ment\msSm¸w       kvt\lw
                  Nment¨Inb kvt\l¡Semsbmc½. \n\¡pthïn cm¸IÂ A²zm
                  \n¨v, Xg¼n¨ ssIIfnÂ \ns¶ tNÀ¯p]nSn¨ \nsâ ]nXm-
                  hv. CW§nbpw ]nW§nbpw ]¦psh¨pw kvt\l¯nsâ
                  hn¯v  \nsâ lrZb¯nÂ \nt£]n¨ ktlmZc§Ä,
                  GIm´XbnÂ Bcpw IqsSbnsÃ¶p
                  tXm¶nbt¸mÄ \n\¡pt\sc Icw













                                                                       \o«nb \Ãkplr¯p¡Ä,
                                                                    t{]mÕl\¯nsâ             I¿SnIÄ
                                                               \n\t¡InbhÀ, XIÀ¨IfnÂ km´z\
                                                           taIn IS¶pt]mbhÀ. a\Ênsâ AÔIm-
                                                        caIän ssZh¯nte ¡pff hgn sXfn¨p X¶
                                                      Kpcq`qXÀ. F´n\v, \o `£n¡p¶ tNmdn\p
                                                  t]mepw BcpsSsbms¡tbm hnbÀ¸nsâ KÔantÃ?
                                              h¶ hgnIÄ Hcn¡epw ad¡cptX
                          B[p\nIXbpsS IpXn¸nte¡v ImseSp¯p h¨ncn¡p¶ Cu ssl sSIv bp-
                  K¯nÂ IS¸mSv F¶ hm¡n\v F´p {]kànbmWpffXv. F.kn apdnbnÂ Id§p¶
                  ItkcbnÂ sXÃv Al¦mct¯msS Ccn¡p¶h³, Xm³ IS¶ph¶ hgnIsf bpw
                  ssZh¯nsâ A\´amb ImcpWys¯bpw ]än H¶p Nn´n¨ncps¶¦nÂ a¡Ä
                  kz´w amXm]nXm¡sf `mcambn Iïv hr²kZ\¯nÂ sImïm¡m³ sh¼Â sIm-
                  ffpt¼mÄ, s\m´p {]khn¨p Ca sh«msX t\m¡n kwc£n¨p, a¡Ä¡pthïn
                  PohnXw tlman¨ amXm        ]nXm¡fpsS XymKs¯bpw kvt\ls¯bpw H¶p Xn
                  cn¨dnªncps¶¦nÂ Ht¶mÀ¡tW, ]Whpw {]Xm]hpsaÃmw \nanj§Ä¡Iw am
                  dnadbpw. AXn \mÂ h¶ hgnIfnse ]qhnXfpItfmSpw apffpItfmSpw t]mepw Dïm-
                  IWw Hcp kvt{XmX k¦oÀ¯\w. \½psS PohnXw ssZh¯nsâ henb Zm\amWv.
                  Cu Zm\¯n\v \ap¡v \µnbpffhcmImw. ssZht¯mSpw a\pjytcmSpw Hcp IS¸mSv
                  lrZb¯nÂ kq£n¡mw.

                  ssZhta, \otbIp¶ \ndtImSn \·IÄ¡v \nda\tÊmsS \µn......





                                                                                          WEAVES       87]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[88   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[Department Highlights






         AICUF













































             Alumnae Association




































                                                                                          WEAVES       89]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[90   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[B.Voc, Mathematics and Artificial Intelligence































          Business Administration
































            Biodiversity Club























                                                                                          WEAVES       91]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[92   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[Commerce (Self-financing)
































           EBCS Club




























           Economics


























                                                                                          WEAVES       93]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[Hair Smoothening Ear & Nose Piercing  Keratin Treatment  Warts Removing  Body Polishing  Volumizing, etc...   Beauty Hub  Our Duty  Is Your Beauty









                                                                                                Miji Jolly Nandanam Business Center UNIOUE   8943193194






                                                                                              Thelappilly Jn. Madayikonam Post Karuvannur South Thrissur - 680712




           94   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[Biotechnology





























         Botany






























         Commerce



























                                                                                          WEAVES       95]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[96   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[Department of English
























           Costume and Fashion Designing





































          Health and Fitness Club
























                                                                                          WEAVES       97]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[98   WEAVES]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[Hindi































           History





























        IEDC

























                                                                                          WEAVES       99]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[100  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[Journalism and Mass Communication


























           Department of Malayalam


































             Mathematics

























                                                                                          WEAVES      101]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[102  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[Minority Cell























            NSS

































            Physical Education





























                                                                                          WEAVES      103]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[104  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[Physics
























            Phsycology























          Social Work





















          NCC

















                                                                                          WEAVES      105]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[106  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[Special Programme






























          Staff Association





























         Women Cell



























                                                                                          WEAVES      107]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[108  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[Zoology


























































































                                                                                          WEAVES      109]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[110  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[WEAVES      111]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[PohtemIs¯ alm_en

                                                                                            Dr. Sandeep Das
                                                                                    Faculty, Department of Zoology


        cï-mbnc¯n BdnÂ Un{Kn cï-mw hÀjw ]Tn¡p¶  AXpsImï-v Xs¶, C´ybpw B{^n¡bpw H¶m
        kab¯mWv  \mknIm _{Sm¡kv  klym{K³knkv  bncp¶p F¶m tKmï-zm\ kn²m´¯nsâ Pohn¨n
        F¶ t]cv tIÄ¡p¶Xv. Ime§fmbn ImSns\ B{i              cn¡p¶  sXfnhpIfnÂ  H¶mbn  ]mXmf  Xhfsb ]
        bn¨pw  ImSnt\mSv  tNÀ¶pw  Pohn¡p¶  a\pjyÀ¡v  cnKWn¡mhp¶XmWv.
        kp]cnNnXamb  PohnbmWv F¦nepw  cï-mbnc¯n                   sF bp kn F³ Nph¸v ]«nI{]Imcw
        aq¶nemWv, aebmfnbmb tUm._nPphneqsS, \mkn  hwi\miw t\cnSp¶ hn`mK¯nÂ s]Sp¶ Ch t\
        Im_{S¡kv klyms{Z³knkv  (Nasikabatrachus  cnSp¶ `ojWnIÄ ]e Xc¯nemWv. Hcp hn[w FÃm
        sahyadrensis) F¶ imkv{X\maw Dff ]À¸nÄ t{^m-        PohnIfpw  A`napJoIcn¡p¶  {]iv\amb Bhmkhy-
        Kv (Purple Frog) F¶ ]mXmf Xhfsb imkv{Xtem-         hØbpsS \miw Chtbbpw kmcambn _m[n¡p¶p.
        Iw ]cnNbs¸Sp¶Xv. Hä t\m«¯nÂ DuXn hoÀ¸n¨  \ZnIfnsebpw AcphnIfnsebpw hepXpw
        Hcp Xhfsbt]mse Ccn¡psa¦nepw kz`mhw sIm  sNdpXpamb UmapIÄ, Sqdnkw aqew Dff thÌv, Ir-
        ï-pw AhbpsS {]tXyIX sImï-pw temI D`bPohn  jnbnS§fnÂ \n¶v hcp¶ cmkhf§fpsS Ahin-
        `q]S¯nÂ C´ybv¡v, tIcf¯n\v, anI¨ Hcp Øm\w  jvSw, ]e Xcw hnjamen\y§Ä, tdmUpIfnse hml\
        sImSp¡p¶XnÂ henb Hcp ]¦p hln¨ XhfbmWv  KXmKXw, XpS§n \nch[n `ojWnIÄ BWv Ct¸m
        ]mXmf Xhf.                                         gpffXv. t\cs¯ kqNn¸n¨ ImemhØbnÂ hcp¶
                              ]À¸nÄ    t{^mKnsâ    icocw   amä§Ä asämcp `ojWnbmWv. cqNntbdnb Cd¨n-
        t]cp kqNn¸n¡p¶Xpt]mse Xs¶ [qa \nd¯nep-             bmWv F¶pw Huj[ KpWapï-v F¶papff hymP {]
        ffXmWv. ]£nIsf ImWm³ Xt«¡mSv t]mb ka-              NcW§fnepw hnizkn¨v IpäIcamWv F¶dnªn«pw
        b¯v AhnSSp¯p \n¶v sdkvIyq sNbvXp Sm¦nen«p  Ahsb th«bmSp¶Xpw hwi\mi¯nte¡v hgn sX-
        h¨ncp¶ ]mXmf Xhfsb Iï-t¸m Hcp ]s£  fn¡p¶p.
        `mhnbnÂ  CtX  XhfbnÂ  KthjWw  \S¯psa¶v  C¶nt¸mÄ                 Ahsb       ]n´pScm\pw    ]Tn¡m\pw
        As¶mcn¡Â t]mepw {]Xo£n¨ncp¶nÃ.                     XpS§nbn«v ]Xns\m¶p hÀjt¯mfambn. BZyw a\
               F¬]Xv  apXÂ  \qän  Ccp]Xp  Zie£w  Ênem¡nb ]eXpw \½Ä IcpXnb t]mesÃ¶pw Hcp
        hÀjw apt¶ ]cnWan¨p F¶p ]T\§Ä sXfn-                 ]s£  ImemhØm  hyXnbm\w  t\cn«v  _m[n¡m³
        bn¡p¶ ChbpsS Gähpw ASp¯ _Ôp¡Ä,  t]mIp¶ C\amWv F¶psams¡ Dff AdnhpIÄ ]
        B{^n¡bpsSbpw C´ybpsSbpw CSbnÂ C´y³  eXpw \½p¡v ]pXnbXpamWv. aebmfnIfpsS alm_
        almkap{Z¯nse Zzo]v cmjv{Samb kotjevknÂ Dff  ense t]mse hÀj¯nÂ Hcp Znhkw am{Xw AXpw
        kqt¥mÊnsS  (Sooglossidae) F¶ IpSpw_¯nse  Ipd¨p aWn¡qÀ am{Xw a®n\Snbnse AhcpsS hmk
        XhfIÄ BWv. ]£nIsf t]mse BImi amÀKtam  Øe¯p \n¶pw ]pd¯v hcp¶ Hcn\s¯ F§s\
        aäp  PohnIsf t]mse  ISÂ  amÀKtam  k©cn¡m³  ]Tn¡pw F¶Xmbncp¶p. BZys¯ shÃp

        D¸p shffw H«pw ]äm¯ D`b PohnIfpsS hchv,  hnfn. ]Xnsb ]Xnsb AhcpsS coXnIfpw kabhpw
        h³IcIfpsS IqsS Xs¶ BIWw. F¶v thWw                  a\Ênem¡nbXv ]pXnb Hcp]mSdnhpIfnte¡v \½sf
        A\pam\n¡m³.                                        \bn¨p.  ASp¯ shÃphnfn  Ipd¨p  IqSn ITn\am


           112  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[bncp¶p. \mÄ¡p\mÄ hÀ[n¨p hcp¶
                                                                  a\pjyhyPohn     kwLÀjpw       ^ï-pIfpsS
                                                                  A]cym]vXXbpw FÃmw Hcp Xhfsb kw-
                                                                  c£n¡Ww F¶ Bhiy§Ä¡v ap¶nÂ
                                                                  henb shÃphnfnIfmbncp¶p. ChnsS hep
                                                                  Xpw `wKnbpffXpw IqSpXemfpIfnÂ CjvS
                                                                  hpw Dï-m¡p¶ PohnIÄ Dfft¸mÄ F§s\
                                                                  Chcnte¡v P\{i² sImï-v hcpw F¶Xv
                                                                  kwibambncp¶ kab¯mWv
                                                                  aUKmkv¡mdnÂ \S¶ Hcp tImgvknÂ
                                                                  h¨v aUKmkvIÀ Zzo]nse aqdpIfpsS kw-
                                                                  c£W¯nÂ henb ]¦p hln¨ ]m{So-
                                                                  jy ssdäv F¶ Atacn¡bnse tÌmWn
                                                                  {_q¡v  kÀhIemimebnse  s{]m^kdpsS
                                                                  {]`mjWw  tIÄ¡p¶Xv.  kwkmc¯nepS
                                                                  \ofw kwc£nt¡ï- PohnIsf P\§fnte¡v
                                                                  P·\kpIfnte¡v        F§s\       ASp¸n¡mw
        F¶Xv Hcp KthjIs\, kwc£Isc kw_Ôn¨nSt¯mfw {][m\amWv F¶Xv AhÀ BhÀ¯n¨p ]dªp
        sImï-ncn¡p¶p. A¶mWv BZyambn F§s\ ]mXmf Xhfsb P\§fnte¡v F¯n¡pI F¶ Nn´ h¶Xp
        Xs¶.
               BZyw kqNn¸n¨Xv t]mse h\{]tZi¯pw h\¯n\I¯pw Xmakn¡p¶ BZnhmkn kaql¯nse ]
        eÀ¡pw AXpt]mse Xs¶ P´pimkv{X hn`mK¯nse Ipd¨p t]À¡pw ]mXmf Xhfsb Adnbpw F¦nepw
        hensbmcp iXam\w aebmfnIÄ¡pw C¯c¯nsemcp Pohnsb¡pdn¨v tI«v tIÄhn t]mepansÃ¶XmWv hm-
        kvXhw. At¸mgmWv F´v sImï-v hÀj¯nÂ Hcp Znhkw a®n\SnbnÂ/]mXmf¯nÂ \n¶v hcp¶ \½fpsS
        alm_ensb t]mse Xs¶bmWv P´p temIs¯ alm_enbmb ]mXmf¯hfbpw F¶ BibapZn¨Xv. ]
        Xnsb ]mXmf Xhfsb alm_en Xhf F¶v hnfn¡phm\pw A¯c¯nÂ Dff teJ\§fpw tkmjyÂ aoUnb
        Ims_bn\pIfpw aäpw Bcw`n¨Xv. hensbmcp amäamWv Ahsc¡pdn¨pff {]NmcW¯nÂ alm_en F¶ t]
        cv Dï-m¡nbXv. GsXmcp Pohntbbpw kwc£n¡Ww F¦nÂ AXnsâ NpaXebpffhÀ¡v FÃmw B Pohn kp]
        cnNnXambncn¡pI F¶Xv. AsXmcp XpS¡ambncp¶p.
        A§s\bncns¡ BWv tIcf¯n\v Hcp HutZymKnI Nn{Xie`apï-m¡p¶Xv. apJya{´nbpsS t\XrXz¯nep-
        ff sshÂUv sse^v AssUzkdn t_mÀUv A¯c¯nsemcp {]Jym]\w \S¯nbt¸mgmWv F´v sImï-v
        \½ps¡mcp HutKymKnI D`bPohn Dï-mbn¡qSm. AXneqsS sNdpPohnIfmb D`bPohnIfpw kwc£nX
        {]m[m\yaÀln¡p¶hcmWv  F¶  s]mXpt_m[w  krjvSn¡Ww  F¶  Bibw  DSseSp¡p¶Xv.  ]cnWma]
        cambn {]tXyIX DffXpw BtKmfXe¯nÂ hwi\mi `ojWn t\cnSp¶Xv sImï-pw (EDGE List, Evolution-
        arily District and Globally Endangered) temI¯nse F®mbnc¯ne[nIw hcp¶ D`bPohnIfnÂ aq¶-
        maXv \nÂ¡p¶ ]mXmf Xhf. Pohn¨ncn¡p¶ t^mÊnÂ F¶ \nebnepw aebmfnIfpsS {]nbs¸« alm_
        ensb t]mse P´ptemIs¯ alm_en F¶ \nebnepw ]ÝnaL«¯nÂ tIcf¯nemWv Chsb IqSpXÂ
        CS¯v Iï-n«pffXv F¶Xv sImï-pw,
        tIcf¯nsâ HutZymKnI ^ew. ]£n,
        arKw  F¶sXms¡  t]mse  Xs¶,
        tIcf¯nsâ Xhf BIphm³ F´p
        sImï-pw tbmKyXbpffXv ]mXmf Xh-
        fbv¡v Xs¶. A[nIw Xmakn¡msX
        Xs¶ Hcp t{]mt¸mkÂ
        X¿mdm¡n      h\wa{´nbv¡pw,    h\w
        hIp¸v No^v sshÂUv sse^v hmÀU
        \pw sshÂUv sse^v AssUzkdn
        t_mÀUv               sa¼ÀamÀ¡pw
        kaÀ¸n¡p¶Xpw. CXv hsc AwKoI
        cn¨n«nÃ. F¦nepw B hmÀ¯
        Hcp]mSv    P\{i²bmÀÖn¡pIbpw
        X·qew C¶v hensbmcp iXam\w
        BfpIfnte¡v       alm_en       Xhf
        F¯pIbpw sNbvXn«pï-v.


                                                                                          WEAVES      113]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[Winners of Calicut University Badminton Championship
                                                                  Winners of Calicut University Boxing Championship

























                                                                Winners of Calicut University Basketball Championship
        Winners of Calicut University Power Lifting Championship



                 Team Josephites: The Invincibles





         “There are two possible outcomes, either win or   by step to make the impossible possible. Winning the
        lose; but what matters is participating”         prestigious title of College Games 2022 is a best exam-
                                                         ple for this. Beating all the well-known colleges includ-
        The Physical Education Department of St Joseph’s   ing mixed colleges, we, the women empire proved that
        College (Autonomous) Irinjalakuda has a great leg-  we are unconquerable.
        acy in the field of sports. It began with one or two
        events and over the course of the time it reached   Every sports student at the college tries her best to be
        many. Year after year, scores of passionate stu-  part of the respective teams, working hard and getting
        dents  from  different  districts  walk  through  the   an opportunity to wear the jersey with the name of our
        campus gates for opportunities and to face chal-  college is a priceless moment. Every athlete takes risks
        lenges. Our dedicated coaches bring out the best   with their health during the matches they play to win a
        in us. Achieving success in sports without the sup-  medal  for  our  college.  Every  year  St.  Joseph’s  College
        port of others is inconceivable. It is a combined ac-  upgrades its Sports and Games and social recognition
        tion and of course the Josephites sports stars have   by winning laurels in the form of awards, trophies and
        admirable support from the side of faculty and the   championships.
        management. Josephites are moving forward, step



           114  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[As sports students, we have to say no to a lot of things
             in order to prioritise our sports life. Reducing our
             screentime, sleeping early and waking up early are
             not easy for the teenagers today. Sometimes we feel
             exhausted and decide to give up but we realise our
             duty to make our college proud and get up to give it
             a try. Mostly we miss our home, parents, siblings and
             our friends; being a sports student we have to leave
             our loved ones. All the sports students of the college
             spend hours in the ground to improve their skills and
             to make the college proud in competitions. The happi-
             est and proud moment is when all the students of the
             college, the faculty, management and other well-wish-
             ers put their applause on our achievements, that is the
             moment when we forget all our pains and struggles
 Winners of Calicut University Boxing Championship  that we faced to achieve it.
                                                                       First Runner Up of Calicut University
             Being a female athlete at many levels is hard, there is        Volley Ball Championship
             so much pressure on us to succeed and to compete at
             the highest levels. We can’t refuse training sessions or
             say no to competition during our menstruation days,
             of course there are times when we get frustrated and
             don’t feel like we can do anything right at that time; we
             have to accept the situation and move on. While it is
             hard and sometimes the worst, we have the ability to
             make the truth about being female athletes something
             awesome. It will always be hard, but in the end it is all
             worth it.

             As we are aware of the famous quote: “No pain, No
             gain; The Pain you experience today will be the success
             you enjoy tomorrow”.  Let your pain motivate yourself!
                                                                      First Runner Up of Calicut University
                                                                         Sepak Takraw Championship
 Winners of Calicut University Basketball Championship
             Shilpa Shaji
             II BA Economics














                                                                                Winners of Calicut University
                                                                                   Football Championship













                                                                           First Runner Up of Calicut University
                                                                                  Rugby Championship


                                                                                          WEAVES      115]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[AMRUTHA P S            VARSHA VENKITESH             AISWARYA PK           ALEENA ANTONY
               III B COM                 III B COM                III BA ENGLISH       I BA ECONOMICS
          CALICUT UNIVERSITY      SENIOR NATIONAL AND         CALICUT UNIVERSITY       JUNIOR NATIONAL
          BADMINTON PLAYER         CALICUT UNIVERSITY         BASKETBALL PLAYER       BASKETBALL PLAYER
                                    BADMINTON PLAYER














             ALEENA SEBY            ANGELA SUNNY                   ANLA  P A           ANN MARIYA JOHNY
           II MA ECONOMICS         II MA ECONOMICS                  II MCJ              III BA ECONOMICS
         CALICUT UNIVERSITY     SENIOR NATIONAL AND          CALICUT UNIVERSITY        CALICUT UNIVERSITY
         BASKETBALL  PLAYER      CALICUT BASKETBALL          BASKETBALL  PLAYER        BASKETBALL  PLAYER
                                  UNIVERSITY PLAYER













            APARNA SADASHIVAN           DIVYA SAM            NANDANA K M                 SHILPA P J
              I MA ECONOMICS       I M SC PSYCHOLOGY            I B COM                    I BBA
            CALICUT UNIVERSITY     CALICUT UNIVERSITY     CALICUT UNIVERSITY         JUNIOR NATIONAL
            BASKETBALL  PLAYER     BASKETBALL PLAYER      BASKETBALL  PLAYER        BASKETBALL PLAYER














               ANASWARA P M           NIKHITHA M BABY           NISSY LAICY            PARVATHY P
                I BA HISTORY            II BA HISTOR               II MCJ               BA HISTORY
             SENIOR NATIONAL         SENIOR NATIONAL         SENIOR NATIONAL        SENIOR NATIONAL
                AND CALICUT           AND UNIVERSITY         AND UNIVERSITY          BOXING PLAYER
                 UNIVERSITY           BOXING  PLAYER          BOXING  PLAYER
               BOXING PLAYER


           116  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[ABHINA P A              ABHIRAMI           ALEENA MATHEW             FEMINA RAJ.V
               III BA HISTORY         III BA HISTORY       III BA ECONOMICS        II MA MALAYALAM
             SENIOR NATIONAL      CALICUT UNIVERSITY      CALICUT UNIVERSITY     CALICUT UNIVERSITY
             FOOTBALL PLAYER        FOOTBALL PLAYER        FOOTBALL PLAYER         FOOTBALL PLAYER














                  GATHA                 JYOTHIRAJ               KAVYA K K             MANJU BABY
               III BA HISTORY          III BA ENGLISH       II MA MALAYALAM               I MCJ
            CALICUT UNIVERSITY       SENIOR NATIONAL       CALICUT UNIVERSITY     CALICUT UNIVERSITY
           AND SENIOR NATIONAL       FOOTBALL PLAYER      AND SENIOR NATIONAL  AND SENIOR NATIONAL
             FOOTBALL PLAYER                                FOOTBALL PLAYER        FOOTBALL PLAYER













           NIDHIYA SREEDHARAN           RESHMA C                 SIVISHA C             VINITHA VIJAYAN
                   I MCJ                   I MCJ                   I MCJ                     I MCJ
           CALICUT UNIVERSITY      CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY
          AND SENIOR NATIONAL  AND SENIOR NATIONAL  AND SENIOR NATIONAL             AND SENIOR NATIONAL
             FOOTBALL PLAYER         FOOTBALL PLAYER         FOOTBALL PLAYER          FOOTBALL PLAYER













                  HELNA                LAKSHMIPRIYA             AISWARYA PK                ANLA  P A
            I BSC PSYCHOLOGY         II BSC PSYCHOLOGY       III BA ENGLISH WON      II MCJ WON THE SEC-
           CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY      THE SECOND PLACE IN     OND PLACE IN THE ALL
            HANDBALL PLAYER           KABADDI PLAYER         THE ALL INDIA INTER   INDIA INTER UNIVERSITY
                                                            UNIVERSITY NETBALL             NETBALL
                                                               CHAMPIONSHIP            CHAMPIONSHIP




                                                                                          WEAVES      117]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[MERYTA SIMON                 AJEESHA A                 SONA P T
                           I MCJ                 II BA ENGLISH           III BA ECONOMICS
                    WON THE SECOND          SENIOR NATIONAL  AND         JUNIOR NATIONAL
                  PLACE IN THE ALL INDIA      CALICUT UNIVERSITY      POWERLIFTING PLAYER
                  INTER UNIVERSITY NET-      POWERLIFTING PLAYER
                   BALL CHAMPIONSHIP













              ATHULIA BHAI               ABHIRAMI                KAVYA K K II             AISWARYA V S
              III BA HISTORY           III BA HISTORY          MA MALAYALAM                  II MSW
           CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY
              RUGBY PLAYER         SEPAK TAKRAW PLAYER      SEPAK TAKRAW PLAYER        VOLLEYBALL PLAYER















               ALEENA BIJU           ANEETA THOMAS                 ANUSREE                  ARYA C V
                 II B COM             III BA HISTORY             I BA ENGLISH                 II MCJ
           CALICUT UNIVERSITY  KHELO INDIA NATIONAL          CALICUT UNIVERSITY       CALICUT UNIVERSITY
           VOLLEYBALL PLAYER          YOUTH GAMES                   PLAYER                   PLAYER
                                    VOLLEYBALL GOLD
                                   MEDAL AND CALICUT
                                   UNIVERSITY PLAYER














                      DEVATHEERTHA P C          ROSE MARY TITUS            SHILPA SHAJI
                       II BA ECONOMICS          II BA ECONOMICS          II BA ECONOMICS
                       YOUTH NATIONAL           YOUTH NATIONAL          SECOND IN YOUTH
                          VOLLEYBALL          SECOND AND CALICUT         NATIONALS AND
                         SECOND PLACE          UNIVERSITY PLAYER       CALICUT UNIVERSITY
                                                                              PLAYER

           118  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[Best Compliments from II DC Mathematics
















































                                                                                          WEAVES      119]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[120  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[Scan Here in Spotify


                   SJC Playlist




































                       Dandelions          Jupiter Mazha          Ranjha        Strawberries & Cigarettes
                                               Dhanwin K.B,      Jasleen Royal, B.
                         Ruth B.           Apoorva Sandhya       Praak, Romy,            Troye Sivan
                                                                 Anvita Dutt

















                      Night Changes          Darshana           Left and Right     Manavaalan Thug
                                                Hesham Abdul       Charlie Puth, Jung
                       One Direction       Wahab,  Darshana      Kook, BTS               Dabzee, SA
                                             Rajendran
















                       Wildest Dreams     Kaadhal En Kaviye    Punchiri Thanjum     Ranjithame
                                                                                    Thalapathy Vijay,
                        Taylor Swift      Sid Sriram, Sreejith Edavana  Shankar Mahadevan  M.M. Manasi, Thaman S.






                                                                                          WEAVES      121]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[Aiswarya K.R
                                                                                           II DC BBA























































































           122  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[WEAVES      123]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[Alfeena Sebastin
                                                                                          III DC Botany



































           124  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[Aparna Shaju
                                                                                 II DC MBFSC










































                                                                                               Devika T.S
                                                                                      III DC Mathrmatics









































                                                                                          WEAVES      125]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[Archana C Binu
                                                                                             II DC BSW






           126  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[Anakha Kanan
                                                                                      III DC English(SF)






















































































                                                                                          WEAVES      127]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[COURSES :

                                                       1.Tally Prime +  GST ............. Rs . 6000/-


                                                       2.Tally + Peachtree+
                                                          Quick Books ......................  Rs . 5000/-

                                                       3.GST ....................................... Rs . 5000/-

                                                       4.Tally Prime+ Advanced
                                                          Excel & Word ...................... Rs . 6000/-


                                                       5.Gulf VAT ..............................   Rs. 4000/-


              Our Salient Features:-                   6.  Diploma in Professional
               Regular& Holiday Batch.                   Accounting + Office

               Experience Certificate                    Administration+GULF VAT
               SAP Online Certificate                    +GST ..................Rs 10000/- (250 Hours)

                Highly Qualified Teachers             SAP COURSES :
                     100% PLACEMENT                    7. Diploma in Professional
                        ASSISTANCE                        Accounting with  SAP FICO
                                                           ...................... Rs .35000/- (500 Hours)


                      ADMISSION                        8. Diploma In Corporate
                       STARTED                            Accounts Management

                  Director :    Centre Manager :          With SAP - FICO , MM, B1
               A R Padmakumar      Shaju C J              Rs 50000/- ........................ (600 Hours)










           128  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[Faculty Members                             Staff



















 COURSES :

 1.Tally Prime +  GST ............. Rs . 6000/-


 2.Tally + Peachtree+
 Quick Books ......................  Rs . 5000/-

 3.GST ....................................... Rs . 5000/-

 4.Tally Prime+ Advanced
 Excel & Word ...................... Rs . 6000/-


 5.Gulf VAT ..............................   Rs. 4000/-


 Our Salient Features:-  6.  Diploma in Professional
  Regular& Holiday Batch.  Accounting + Office

  Experience Certificate  Administration+GULF VAT
  SAP Online Certificate  +GST ..................Rs 10000/- (250 Hours)

   Highly Qualified Teachers  SAP COURSES :
 100% PLACEMENT  7. Diploma in Professional
 ASSISTANCE  Accounting with  SAP FICO
 ...................... Rs .35000/- (500 Hours)


  ADMISSION  8. Diploma In Corporate
 STARTED  Accounts Management

 Director :  Centre Manager :  With SAP - FICO , MM, B1
 A R Padmakumar  Shaju C J  Rs 50000/- ........................ (600 Hours)










                                                                                          WEAVES      129]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[130  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[WEAVES      131]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[132  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[WEAVES      133]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[134  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[WEAVES      135]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[136  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[WEAVES      137]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[138  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[WEAVES      139]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[140  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="141"><![CDATA[WEAVES      141]]></page><page Index="142"><![CDATA[142  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="143"><![CDATA[WEAVES      143]]></page><page Index="144"><![CDATA[144  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="145"><![CDATA[WEAVES      145]]></page><page Index="146"><![CDATA[146  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="147"><![CDATA[WEAVES      147]]></page><page Index="148"><![CDATA[148  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="149"><![CDATA[WEAVES      149]]></page><page Index="150"><![CDATA[150  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="151"><![CDATA[WEAVES      151]]></page><page Index="152"><![CDATA[152  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="153"><![CDATA[WEAVES      153]]></page><page Index="154"><![CDATA[154  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="155"><![CDATA[WEAVES      155]]></page><page Index="156"><![CDATA[156  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="157"><![CDATA[WEAVES      157]]></page><page Index="158"><![CDATA[158  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="159"><![CDATA[WEAVES      159]]></page><page Index="160"><![CDATA[FINE ARTS

        PRIZES 2021 - 2022  MALAYALAM SPEECH                        LIGHT MUSIC

                                                                    1ST - DEVA RAGHUCHANDRAN
                            1St  - HENNA ROSE JOHNSON                           ( III DC PSYCHOLOGY)
                                        (II DC ENGLISH)
                                                                    2ND - DEVIKA M
                            2nd  - SR.SIMI VARGHESE                                (III DC PHYSICS)
                                          (I PG ENGLISH)
                                                                    3RD- SARAYU C
                            3rd - MEGHA M M                                      (II DC BOTANY)
               U                        ( III DC BOTANY)                        RANJANA P H
                                                                                (II DC ENGLISH)
                J           ENGLISH SPEECH                          MONOACT

                            1St  - ANNA REEJO PARAYIL
                J                       (II DC MATHEMATICS)         1st  - CHRISTEENA C B
                                                                               ( II DC BOTANY)
              W             2nd  - OLIVIA LIMSON                    2nd  - ESTHER N ROY
                                          ( I DC ECONOMICS)
                            3rd  - NANDITA SURESH                                (I DC BCOM. FINANCE
               A                         ( II DC CHEMISTRY)          3rd - ALANA SIBY


                L           RECITATION (MALAYALAM)                              (II DC BIOTECHNOLOGY,
                                                                             ANNETTE ROSE JOSEPH,
                            1ST - LAKSHMI SAJEEVAN                           (II DC BVOC MBFSC
               A                        (II DC CFD)


                            2ND - BHAVISHYA P B                     FOLK DANCE
                                           ( II DC BCOM.FINANCE)    1st - Ranjana P.H
                                                                              (II DC English)
                2           3RD - ANAGHA T.S                        2nd – Anagna K.G
                                        ( II DC HISTORY)
                                                                                ( II DC Biotechnology)
               K            RECITATION (ENGLISH)                    3rd – Anitta Babu
                                                                                (II DC Physics)

               2            1ST - RANJANA P H                       BHARATHANATYAM
                                                                    1st - Swetha Unnikrishnan
               2                        ( II DC ENGLISH)                       (II DC BBA)
                                                                    2nd - Anjana Prakash K
                            2ND - NANDITHA SURESH                               (Ill DC Botany)
                                          (II DC CHEMISTRY)         3rd - Gayathri Jayan
                                         ASWATHI                               ( I PG Biotechnology)
                                         (I DC MATHS)
                                                                    MOHINIYATTAM
                            3RD- ANNA MARIYA                        1st - Swetha Unnikrishnan
                                        (II DC ENGLISH(Self))                  (II DC BBA)
                                     SHAMIYA S                      2nd - Gayathri Jayan
                                     (II DC CHEMISTRY (SELF))                   (I PG Biotechnology)
                                                                    3rd - Dinta Davis (I DC Chemistry)

           160  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="161"><![CDATA[FINE ARTS

        PRIZES 2021 - 2022    PENCIL DRAWING                          3rd –Gayathri MS
                              1st - Ansha Singri                                  (II DC B.com[Aided])
                                        (III DC Zoology)
                              2nd - Bubly Babu                        SHORT STORY
                                          (II  PG Maths)              MALAYALAM
                                       Bhadra Balan                   1st –Sharol MA
                                       (I DC Botany)                             (II PG Physics)
                              3rd - Rithika Sukumar                   2nd –Aswathy Madhu
                                         (II PG Physics)                          (III DC B.com[Aided])
                                                                      3rd –Thennel Krishna P
               U              WATER COLOUR PAINTING                              (I DC History)
                              1st - Arya CR
                                         (II DC B. Com Self [B])
                J             2nd - Meghna S                          GROUP EVENTS

                                          (II DC Economics)
                J             3rd - Shahin Navas                      FUSION DANCE
                                         (II DC B.Com finance [self])
                                                                      1st –Teresa Noby & Team
              W               ESSAY WRITING ENGLISH                              (English[Aided])

                                                                      2nd –Gayathri & Team
               A              1st –Durga Siddharth                                (B.com [SF])
                                         (I DC Bcom[Aided])
                                                                      3rd –Anjali Krishna & Team (BSW)
                              2nd –Rosmin CR                                     Josena Jose & Team
                L                         (II DC Mathematics)                    (English[SF])

                              3rd –Nanda Varma
               A                         (III DC Physics)             GROUP SONG

                              VERSIFICATION MALAYALAM                 1st –Fathima TS & Team (Botany)
                                                                      2nd –Siya KJ&Team (B.com[self])
                              1st –Jisa Johny                         3rd –Angel Mariy George &
                2                        (II DC Commerce)                        Team (Mathematics)
                              2nd –Meenu Prasad
                                          (II DC Physics)             THIRUVATHIRA
               K              3rd –Unni Maya KV                       1st –Physics

                                          (II DC B.com Finance[self])
               2              VERSIFICATION ENGLISH                   2nd –English[Aided]
                                                                      3rd –B.com[self]
                              1st –Aparna Sudheer
               2                        (III DC English)              KITCHEN DANCE

                              2nd –Bavishya PB
                                         (II DC B.com[self])          1st –Chemistry
                              3rd –Durga Siddharth                    2nd –Mathematics
                                         (I DC B.com[Aided])          3rd –English[SF],B.com[Aided]


                              SHORT STORY ENGLISH
                              1st –Arsha Dinesh Babu
                                         (I DC Psychology)
                              2nd –Annapoorna Boban
                                          (I DC Botany)


                                                                                          WEAVES      161]]></page><page Index="162"><![CDATA[Scalp massage   Tame frizzy hair  overworked hair For damaged &  Before/After bath nourishment  Hair & beard care









              VIRGIN COLD PRESSED  ...............................  ...........................  ...........................  ...........................  ...........................

























       UPGRADE TO  UPGRADE TO  From Ordinary Coconut Oil  ...............................  ...........................  ...........................  ...........................


























                               SWEET/MILD  AROMA  LIGHT  NON   STICKY                             For more information,   visit  www.klfnirmal.com












           162  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="163"><![CDATA[Hm-À-½--I-fpsS



                                                         e-b-\w-


                                                         thÀ]mSv F¶pw thZ\mP\IamWv. \n\¨n
                                                         cn¡m¯ t\c¯v XncnsIsb¯psa¶v {]
                                                         Xo£n¡m³ t]mepw hIbnÃmsX acWsa¶
                                                         BLmXtaÂ¸n¨v {]nbs¸«hÀ bm{XbmIp-
                                                         t¼mÄ Hcp \Sp¡t¯msSbÃmsX BÀ¡mWv
                                                         Cu thÀ]mSns\ kao]n¡m\mIpI. shdpsX
                                                         t\m¡n \nÂ¡m³ am{Xw ]äp¶ Nne Imcy§
                                                         fpïv. am\¯p \n¶v ASÀ¶p hogp¶
                                                         ag¯pffnIsf XSªp \nÀ¯m³ km[n¡m¯Xp
                                                         t]mse acWsa¶ bmYmÀ°ys¯ thZ\
                                                         tbmsS t\m¡n ImWms\ km[n¡q. amÀ¨v
                amkw Cu Iemeb¯n\v A¯csamcp thZ\bpsS amkamWv. I®ocnsâbpw. \
                jvSt_m[¯nsâbpw At\IÀ¡v CjvSkulrZ¯nsâbpw \oäÂ ]Icp¶ amkw, Cu
                Iemebapä¯v \½nÂ Hcmfmbn Ifn¨pw Nncn¨pw Xmfw ]nSn¨pw Xmf¯ns\m¸w BSn-
                bpw Xsâ imcocnI IpdhpIsf adnIS¶v BImiw IWs¡ kz]v\w Iï aq¶mw hÀj
                sImtagvkv hnZymÀ°n\n eb tUhokv Cu Iemeb¯nÂ \n¶v F¶t¶bv¡pambn
                bm{Xbmbn; Ifnbc§nÂ \n¶v s]mSp¶s\ A{]Xy£amIp¶, Nne thj§Ä t]mse.
                       Ahkm\ hÀj hnZymÀ°n\nIÄ¡mbpff bm{Xbb¸n\mbn AWnsªmcp§n
                ss_¡nÂ A¸Ñt\msSm¸w Iemeb¯ntebv¡v bm{XbmIpt¼mÄ CXv Xsâ Ahkm\
                bm{XbmsW¶v AhÄ hnNmcn¨ncn¡nÃ. FXnsc h¶ hml\¯nsâ Ccbmbn Xsâ
                {]nbaIÄ bm{Xbmbt¸mÄ ssIIpS¶bpsS NqSpw kvt\l¯nsâ \\hptaIn hfÀ¯n
                hepXm¡nb amXm]nXm¡fpsS I®ocnsâ Bg§sf Af¡m\mInÃ. F¦nepw Bizkn¡mw
                AhÄ ssZh¯nsâ CSs\©nÂ Nmªpd§pIbmWv. Hcp]mSv \·bpsS tijn¸pIÄ _m¡n
                h¨n«mWv aq¶p]nSn a®nsâ \\hnte¡v, ssZh¯nsâ CSs\©ntebv¡v AhÄ bm{XbmbXv.
                ebsb¡pdn¨p ]dbpt¼mÄ ebbpsS A²ym]Icpw kl]mTnIfpw Gsd hmNmecm-
                Wv. Bscbpw amän \nÀ¯msX Ghscbpw Hcpt]mse kvt\ln¨v kulrZw Øm]n¨v
                Hcp sNdp]p©ncnbpambn kl]mTnIfntebv¡v Bgv¶nd§nbt¸mÄ imcocnI Ipd
                hpIsf adnIS¶v ]cnanXnIsf km[yXIfm¡n Xsâ kz]v\§Ä¡v NndIv \ÂIm³ ]
                cn{ian¨hÄ, ssZh¯nÂ B{ibn¨p PohnXw \bn¨hÄ, hfsc will power Dff s]¬Ip«n,
                \sÃmcp KmbnI C§s\ Hcp]mSv Imcy§Ä ebsb¡pdn¨v AhÀ¡v ]dbm\pïv.
                       Hcp]mSv {]Xo£bpsS \Ã ]mT§Ä au\ambn ]Tn¸n¨v, Ne\§fpsS Hmf§Ä
                krjvSn¨v \·bpsS kpKÔw Iemeb¯nÂ ]c¯n kulrZ¯nsâ XWÂacambn XoÀ¶
                {]nb ktlmZco, \ns¶ Ipdn¨pff acn¡m¯ kvarXnIÄ R§fpsS lrZb§fnepïv.
                ]dbm³ _m¡n h¨ hm¡pw, tIÄ¡m³ sImXn¨ \·Ifpw C\nbpw ]qhWnbm¯
                kz]v\§fpw _m¡nbpsï¦nepw Hcp]nSn \Ã HmÀ½IÄ k½m\n¨mWv \o bm{XbmbXv.
                Hcn¡Â Hcp s]¬Ip«n Xsâ ]nXmhnt\mSp tNmZn¨p; ]nXmth F´m \Ã a\pjyÀ s]s«¶v
                acn¡p¶Xv?. ]nXmhv ]dªp.. \o Hcp ]qt´m«¯nemsW¦nÂ GXp ]qhmbncn¡pw BZyw
                Cdp¡pI? kzÀ¤¯nse aeÀhmSnbnse Gähpw at\mlcamb tdmkm]qth \n\¡v {]Wmaw..





                                                                               Sr. Aneeta Stephan
                                                                               II DC B.Com Finance



                                                                                          WEAVES      163]]></page><page Index="164"><![CDATA[Special Thanks











                                                                                                Ms. Ursula N











                                                                                              Dr. Salmi Sebastian










                                                                                                Ms. Priya U. S





                     Loose threads taken from the rich tapestry of life
                     are woven together into WEAVES. Many hands were
                     put together to meld memories and fantasies
                     that coloured and shaped the leaves of this magazine.
                     While these pages unfold to fill you and me with
                     delight and nostalgia, we have nothing but A Million Thanks
                     to all those guiding forces and supportive hands.
                     We thank Divine Providence for all graces !
                     We would like to thank our Manager Rev. Sr. Elsy Kokkat,
                      Principal Rev. Sr. Dr. Asha Therese, Vice- principals,
                     Rev.Sr.Blessy & Rev.Sr. Dr. Elaiza, and Self - financing Coordinator
                     Rev. Sr. Dr. Rose Bastin for their boundless support and guidance.
                     Thanks to Ms. Geetha, Jeswin Sir, Ms. Veena, Ms. Rejo,
                     Ms. Salmi, Ms. Ursula and dear Priya chechi for
                     knitting, colouring and shaping WEAVES.


                     As we part ways to explore the unexplored,
                     …todays will give way to tomorrows and …
                     When tomorrows will seek yesterdays ...
                     We wish and hope that WEAVES
                     adds colour to our fond memories…

                      EDITOR
                      WEAVES




           164  WEAVES]]></page><page Index="165"><![CDATA[WEAVES      165]]></page><page Index="166"><![CDATA[I went to the woods because I wished to live deliberately, to front only the
                        essential facts of life, and see if I could not learn what it had to teach, and not,
                         when I came to die, discover that I had not lived. I did not wish to live what
                         was not life, living is so dear; nor did I wish to practice resignation, unless it
                        was quite necessary. I wanted to live deep and suck out all the marrow of life,
                         to live so sturdily and Spartan-like as to put to rout all that was not life, to
                        cut a broad swath and shave close, to drive life into a corner, and reduce it to
                        its lowest terms, and, if it proved to be mean, why then to get the whole and
                         genuine meanness of it, and publish its meanness to the world; or if it were
                                  sublime, to know it by experience, and be able to give
                                        a true account of it in my next excursion
                                            — Henry David Thoreau, Walden.









                                                    Weaves







































           166  WEAVES]]></page></pages></Search>